<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1251" ?>
<string_table>
	<string id="first_bunker_fake_sms1">
		<text>Science Camp:\nWhat is it you want?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="first_bunker_fake_sms2">
		<text>Science Camp:\nWait a moment, I am going to disable the security system.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="first_bunker_fake_sms3">
		<text>Science Camp:\nDone, you may go.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="volk_sasesc_bar4">
		<text>Lone Wolf\nNow we can talk.</text>	
	</string>
	<string id="volk_sasesc_bar4">
		<text>Toad:\nMesser, I heard that the military sent a group of soldiers towards Agroprom, most likely to get the documents you need to get me. Anyway, if you run into them, try to call someone for help on your PDA, that'll help distract some of the soldiers. That's all I can think of for now, and don't forget the box!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bun_swatoy_rush_sms">
		<text>Message: Messer:\nHey you, stop!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="radar_na_tochke_govlab_sms">
		<text>Message:\nYou're on your own from here - we're not going in there with you, our orders are to hold this area.</text>
	</string>
		<string id="kill_actor_svd_dolina">
		<text>Unknown sniper:\nWhere are you going, stalker?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="hy_punk_dont_shoor_my_rat">
		<text>Message:\nHey, he's shooting at our rats!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="blacened_pp">
		<text>Message:\nOh, hey! Come on over and chat with me.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="start_bar_one_timer_0">
		<text>Major Kravtsov: Come in, let's talk. You'll find me at our base. I'm waiting.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="novic_leaded_dead_sms_slizen">
		<text>Slug:\nUh, I don't get it, is he fucking dead?! Get over here!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="spawen_monolit_na_kordone_komandira_sms">
		<text>Message:\nHey, you! Go to the building next to the water tower. I need to talk to you.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sms_esc_doki_band">
		<text>Incoming message:\nBro, come out! Come over here.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jaba_killar_washe">
		<text>Toad:\nAttention, everyone! From now on, the stalker called Messer is declared a murderer! There is a bounty on his head - let him serve as another example of how not to treat a fellow stalker. He may still get a chance to atone for his sins, if, of course, he manages to get to me and talk things out.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jaba_killar_pre">
		<text>Toad:\nHey, what are you doing?! You'll be declared a murderer if you intentionally kill another stalker - you won't be considered a stalker anymore, and you'll be hunted, so be aware of that.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jaba_ohrene">
		<text>Toad:\nHey, are you out of your mind?! These are my guys guarding my bunker!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="komandir_zdohnah">
		<text>Toad:\nMesser, what the fuck?! Is he dead?! Why the hell did I send you down there?! You still have amnesia, what am I gonna tell the troops?! Get over here!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="infor_glob_rad_palba">
		<text>PDA:\nAttention! Critical radiation levels detected! Check your suit for holes or leave the contaminated area immediately!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="voy_dolineaa">
		<text>Toad:\nMesser, the soldiers have organized a raid on the bandits in the area where you are now, so don't run into them. A couple of hours ago an army jeep left the Cordon - there were 6 or 7 people inside it, and they were carrying some equipment with them. As soon as their mess subsides, see what was there, and you see if you can 'borrow' a car from the gentlemen in uniform. Anyway, if you find anything, I'll be in touch.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="oobrataan">
		<text>%c[255,160,160,160]Zyablikov:\n %c[255,245,118,54]Thanks for your help. I need to be alone.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="njvis_oka_sch">
		<text>Goiter:\nStalker, come here, I've got a job to do. I'm over here by the hillside.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="prof_heliequp_smsone">
		<text>Professor\nAlright, keep your eyes on the road to the bar. After the helicopter crosses paths with you, head toward the bunker.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="barman_group_sms">
		<text>%c[255,160,160,160] Barkeep:\n%c[255,160,160,160]What happened to the group? Damn it, Messer.\n</text>
	</string>
	<string id="messer_fonar_sms2">
		<text>Dwarf:\nI want to ask you about something...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_lonewolf_gar_smsm">
		<text>Lone Wolf:\nStalker, you've probably heard of the stalker bar by now, right? A place in the heart of the Zone, where stalkers gather after returning from distant raids. I can tell you that they're interested in you, but they're not waiting for you empty-handed. There's a house in the Dark Valley area, and the Barkeep is very interested in the documents that may be there..</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_lonewolf_gar_smsm2">
		<text>Lone Wolf:\nThis loot will be your pass into the elite club, and you'll automatically move into the category of experienced stalkers. However, you can't get into the Valley for no reason - there is some kind of installation on its territory that generates waves of psionic radiation that drives people mad.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_lonewolf_gar_smsm3">
		<text>Lone Wolf:\nYou need a special protective device. The troopers went on a raid there recently, and it looks like they're all dead. I have information that a couple of soldiers made it out to the Garbage. I'm sure one of them has a protective device. They were seen at a crossing where a small creek runs off of it.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_volk_sasesc">
		<text>Lone Wolf:\nStalker, watch out, there's a pseudo-dog!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_volk_sasesc_bar">
		<text>Lone Wolf:\nWait, don't go! Messer!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_volk_sasesc_bar2">
		<text>Lone Wolf:\nWell, here we are. The room is all yours. Make yourself comfortable. I think you should be able to get about seven or eight hours of sleep. The doors are only locked from the inside, and once the door is open, the compartment is considered unoccupied. You can't lock it from the outside, so everyone carries their own stuff. Also, you have to be ready to evacuate at a moment's notice if anything goes wrong. You get some sleep, and then we'll go to the bar, where we can drink, eat, and talk.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_volk_sasesc_bar3">
		<text>Lone Wolf:\nYou awake? Alright, time to move to the bar...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_volk_sasesc_stop">
		<text>Lone Wolf:\nHey, Messer, wait!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_zagon_bandosa">
		<text>Incoming message -\nSprout: Man, come with us! We got that bandit bastard that smoked seven of our guys in that house up on the hill, help us smack that bastard! Come here, I'll tell you more.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_bad_timer_del_novic_sms">
		<text>\nWhere's my gun, Messer?! What, you're keeping it for yourself? Well, I'll remember that, Messer!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_dofhodi_kvestpat">
		<text>Toad:\nMesser, come in. So here's the situation: I need to get something. It's called the Toad's Eye. It's located in the Garbage to the north. I sent a group there before, but they lost contact almost as soon as they got there. One of my defectors said that in the place where they saw the artifact there was no anomalous activity, but they were afraid to go there. So go to the Garbage and get me that artifact. I'll upload the coordinates of the Toad's Eye location to your PDA.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_jaba_zavod_doki_escsa">
		<text>Toad:\nYeah, one more thing. That thing you shot stole one of my courier's documents while he was sleeping in the factory. He said it had some kind of lair on the roof. Maybe the creature took them there. Find them and bring them to me, as they have some value. Don't come back without them.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_horok_ne_have_go_nazad">
		<text>Toad:\nI don't get it, is he dead or something? What the hell were you looking at? I sent you to him. Go back to my bunker.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_sms_esc_olr_kvest_3_zametki_bio">
		<text>Toad:\nOh, I forgot to tell you something. In your PDA you have the ability to display the contact information of stalkers that are within a radius of about 250 meters from you. You can contact some of them from a distance. To do this, select the desired stalker in the contacts section. There you can also find out a brief description of this stalker. Try to reach Digger via PDA when you are near him. I think you'll get the gist of it.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_pda_zarad_info_zaba">
		<text>Toad:\nYeah, one more thing - your PDA has a charge, and it loses that charge over time. Keep an eye on it so that you can keep your PDA working, and recharge it whenever you can. Your PDA is your lifeline in the Zone.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_olr_blowout_first_zaba">
		<text>Toad:\nHow are you doing. Still alive?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_olr_blowout_first_zaba_blok">
		<text>Toad:\nMesser, there's something going on at the checkpoint after the emission. I can't get any signals from there, it's like there's no one there. Listen, why don't you go over there quietly and see what's going on? Once you figured out what happened, get the hell out of there and report back to me what you see.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_pes_go_talk1">
		<text>Watchdog:\nHey, man, come here, we'll talk. Just help us deal with the pack first.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_pes_go_talk2">
		<text>Watchdog:\nHow's that rookie doing? Is he feeling well?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_pes_go_talk3">
		<text>Crow's Eye:\nHe's doing great! And he's no rookie either, if you'd seen the way he deftly took down the ringleader..</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_pes_go_talk5">
		<text>Watchdog:\nYes, he's no newbie. Come, we need to talk.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_bad_timer_gardolpsevdo">
		<text>Duty:\nWatch out! There's a pseudo-dog! Somebody kill it! Hurry up! Stalker, kill that damned mutant!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_bar_dolg_lider_zom1">
		<text>Duty Leader:\nFighters, take your positions! The dead are coming. Messer, this is your chance to make your mark.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_bar_dolg_lider_zom2">
		<text>Duty Leader:\nGet ready, men! Another wave is coming!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_bar_dolg_lider_zom3">
		<text>Duty Leader:\nAttention! We are detecting strange interference in the air, everyone be careful.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_bar_dolg_lider_stuka">
		<text>Duty Leader\nOkay, we've got the rat. He's pushing our ammo to the left. Go to our merchant for your reward.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_zagon_bandosa2">
		<text>Incoming message:\nAh... critters...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sms_mil_vishka_night_go">
		<text>Incoming message:\nIf you stay in the tower all night, something is bound to happen.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_noobik_progulka_one">
		<text>Incoming message:\nDamn it. I knew there was something wrong here. Okay, let's go to another place.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_noobik_progulka_tri">
		<text>Incoming message -\nSergei: The group is dead, everyone here is dead... bloodsuckers! Damn it, what to do now? Thanks for coming with me, stalker. I owe you one. If you need me, look for me where I was or at the bar. I need a drink.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_noobik_progulka_two">
		<text>Incoming message:\nFucking door.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_zhaba_random_zakaz_0">
		<text>I've got a special order here. Bring anything weird you find. You never know what kind of surprise the Zone will spring on you next time. It's ten times the price for an unknown artifact. And hurry, you're not the only one trying to capitalize on this.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_zhaba_random_zakaz_1">
		<text>Hey, are you outside the Cordon now? I was told a strange artifact was seen in that area. Bring anything strange you find. You never know what kind of surprise the Zone will give you next time. There's a tenfold fee for this unknown artifact. And hurry, you're not the only one looking for it.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_zhaba_random_zakaz_2">
		<text>There's information about a special artifact in the area where you are. Bring anything weird you find. You never know what surprise the Zone will give you next time.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_deadcity_paras_talk_to_dleader_sms2">
		<text>Message:\nHmm, looks like a source of the contagion...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_deadcity_paras_talk_to_dleader_sms3">
		<text>Message:\nHmm, looks like a source of the contagion...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_deadcity_paras_talk_to_dleader_sms">
		<text>Message:\nMesser, this is the leader of the Duty faction. I'm waiting for you at my place, we need to talk.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_krisa_gavgav3">
		<text>Major:\nHello, Rat, trying to do your business behind my back?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_krisa_gavgav4">
		<text>Rat:\nHello, Major. I was acting solely on your instructions.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_krisa_gavgav">
		<text>Rat:\nLeave us two alone.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_krisa_gavgav2">
		<text>Rat:\nDo I have to repeat myself?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="volk_sasesc_bar4">
		<text>Toad:\nMesser, I heard that the military sent a group towards Agroprom, most likely sent to get the documents you need to get me. Anyway, if you run into them, try to call someone for help on your PDA, at least it'll distract some of them. That's it. And don't forget the box!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bun_swatoy_rush_sms">
		<text>Message: Messer:\nHey you, stop!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="radar_na_tochke_govlab_sms">
		<text>Message:\nYou're on your own from here - we're not going in there with you, our orders are to hold this area.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kill_actor_svd_dolina">
		<text>Unknown sniper:\nWhere are you going, stalker?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="hy_punk_dont_shoor_my_rat">
		<text>Message:\nHey, he's shooting at our rats!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="blacened_pp">
		<text>Message:\nOh, hey! Come on over and talk to me.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="start_bar_one_timer_0">
		<text>Major Kravtsov:\nCome in, let's talk. You'll find me at our base. I'm waiting.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="novic_leaded_dead_sms_slizen">
		<text>Slug:\nUh, I don't get it, is he fucking dead?! Get over here!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="spawen_monolit_na_kordone_komandira_sms">
		<text>Message:\nHey, you! Go to the building next to the water tower. I need to talk to you.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sms_esc_doki_band">
		<text>Incoming Message:\nBro, come out! Come down.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jaba_killar_washe">
		<text>Toad:\nAttention, everyone! From now on, the stalker called Messer is declared a murderer! There is a bounty on his head - let him serve as another example of how not to treat a fellow stalker. He may still get a chance to atone for his sins, if, of course, he gets to me and talk things out with me.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jaba_killar_pre">
		<text>Toad:\nHey, what are you doing?! You'll be declared a murderer if you kill one more neutral stalker. Through your own fault, you'll be out of the Stalkers' way, and you'll be hunted, so be aware of that.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jaba_ohrene">
		<text>Toad:\nHey, are you out of your mind?! These are my guys! They're guarding my bunker!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="komandir_zdohnah">
		<text>Toad:\nMesser, what the fuck?! Is he dead?! Why the hell did I send you down there?! You still have amnesia, what am I gonna tell the troops?! Get over here!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="infor_glob_rad_palba">
		<text>PDA:\nAttention! Critical radiation contamination detected! Check your suit for leaks or leave the contaminated area immediately!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="voy_dolineaa">
		<text>Toad:\nMesser, the soldiers have organized a raid on the bandits in the area where you are now, so don't run into them. A couple of hours ago an army jeep left the Cordon - there were 6 or 7 soldiers - and they were carrying some equipment with them. As soon as this mess is over, see what was there, and you can 'borrow' a car from the gentlemen in uniform. Anyway, if you find anything, I'll be in touch.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_maxsms_cool1">
		<text>Incoming message - Max:\nIt's working! Let's run to the hall and see what's going on!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_maxsms_cool2">
		<text>Incoming message - Max:\nThe light is on, my friend, the light is on!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_maxsms_cool3">
		<text>Incoming message - Max:\nThis is it! This is what I was talking about!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_maxsms_cool4">
		<text>Incoming message - Max:\nYes, I'm coming to you.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_rush_rostok_tmer_mochii">
		<text>Message:\nShit, there's someone out there, everybody be on the lookout!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_rush_rostok_tmer_mochii2">
		<text>Message: Group\nEveryone group up! Remember, our goal now is to get to the tunnel leading to Rostok.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_progulka_prisli_plos_lead">
		<text>Message: Leader\nOkay, it's quiet. Come stalker, we'll discuss what to do next...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_progulka_prisli_plos_lead2">
		<text>Message: Leader\nKeep quiet... Everyone check your guns...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_progulka_prisli_plos_lead3">
		<text>Message: Leader\nThere's something there...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_progulka_prisli_plos_lead4">
		<text>Message: Black Slug\nHalt! Let's take the bastards down! Whoa... who are these guys?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_progulka_prisli_plos_lead5">
		<text>Message: Black Slug\nOkay, put the guns away, guys. This is just an ID check. You try to run, you're gonna get shot, I'm telling you.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_progulka_prisli_plos_lead6">
		<text>Message: Black Slug\nWhat the hell?! Nail, go check it out. We're holding these ones, don't piss--</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_progulka_prisli_plos_lead7">
		<text>Message: Black Slug\nThere's nothing here! Let's go get these guys and get the fuck outta here!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_progulka_prisli_plos_lead8">
		<text>Message: Black Slug\nYou! Get your backpack off!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_progulka_prisli_plos_lead9">
		<text>Message: Black Slug\nFuck! Get the fuck away!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_progulka_prisli_plos_lead10">
		<text>Message: Leader\nMesser! Get out of here, let's go!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_progulka_prisli_plos_lead11">
		<text>Message: Leader\nMesser! Follow me, let's get out of here, hurry up! What the hell is this place!? That thing dragged you down here before I could get here!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_progulka_prisli_plos_lead12">
		<text>Message: Leader\nIt's quiet. Shit. Go to the bar and talk to the Barkeep about what happened. I'm not going with you, I have some things I need to take care of... Go!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_mg_sms_hey_punkass_hrom">
		<text>Chrome:\nI think I got a signal. Wait a bit, our guys will give them a warm welcome. If you can, do us a favor and help our guys. I don't think they'll know who attacked them in the dark.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_mg_sms_hey_punkass_hrom2">
		<text>Freedomer:\nQuiet, boys. Let's try to get in quietly...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_mg_sms_hey_punkass">
		<text>Message: Monolith\nStalker, get out of here... this is none of your business.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_sms_val_garbage_bandits">
		<text>Message:\nHey, stalker! Bro, come here, I have something to do!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_olr_lab_2_door_unlocked_fake_sms1">
		<text>Message:\nThis password expired on 20.02.2012. Please enter a new password.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_olr_lab_2_door_unlocked_fake_sms2">
		<text>Messer:\nFuck... Fucking Slug...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_olr_lab_2_door_unlocked_fake_sms3">
		<text>Message:\nUh, hey you, bro, you come over here, around the corner.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_shakal_esc_sms1">
		<text>Message: Jackal\nMesser, turn on your PDA and find me through the Contacts tab. I'll tell you what's going on...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_shakal_esc_sms2">
		<text>Message:\nConnection lost.</text>
	</string>
</string_table>
