<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1251" ?>
<string_table>

	<string id="af_dummy_dummy_q1_desc">
		<text>This object is a strange artifact that's known as Dummy. It sticks to the wall of my backpack, and it also gives off a faint greenish glow.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="af_banka_s_holodcom">
		<text>Jelly</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_af_banka_s_holodcom">
		<text>This jar contains a concentrated Witches' Jelly anomaly. If you break the jar, the anomaly will pour out and form an hazardous anomalous area.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_zone_artifact_esc_vishka">
		<text>This anomalous artifact is of uknown origin. It floats slightly in the air, and it's also fairly heavy.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="af-compas">
		<text>Spiral</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_zone_artifact_af-compas">
		<text>An artifact with a bizarre shape, resembling a spiral.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_zone_af_art_kub">
		<text>This artifact has interesting and unpredictable properties. For example, it increases your resistance to blowouts. Rumor has it that if you fall asleep with this artifact after being zombified, you'll turn back to normal and the artifact itself will disappear.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="af-af_art_kub">
		<text>Invisible Cube</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_zone_art_lenss">
		<text>This artifacle is rare and valuable. It'll get you a lot of money if you sell it, and has no known except properties except for one: it increases the resistance of its user to high temperatures.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="af-art_lenss">
		<text>Lens</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_zone_art_ruchk">
		<text>The Handle is an anomalous object of unknown origin. It resembles a thick pen, dark in color with a grey-colored pattern on its surface. It radiates warmth that you can feel even through the gloves of your protective suit. It you put a Handle on your belt, it'll increase the weight you can carry by 3 kilograms.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="af-art_ruchk">
		<text>Handle</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_zone_art_spiral">
		<text>The Spiral an anomalous object of unknown origin, resembling its namesake. It you put a Spiral on your belt, it'll make you feel drowsiness.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="af-art_spiral">
		<text>Spiral</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_zone_art_steklo">
		<text>This artifact has no known anomalous properties. It resembles an object made out of glass, being transparent and aesthetically pleasing to look at. It'll get you a bit of money if you sell it.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="af-art_steklo">
		<text>Glass-like artifact</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_zone_art_sterj">
		<text>This artifact, which has only one known example that exists, resembles a straight metal rod that is 43 centimeters long. You can see the numbers "2465" clearly printed on one of its sides. The main anomalous property of this artifact is that it's capable of quenching any type of energy without changing its shape, and it also maintains a consisent temperature - regardless of what kind of heat or energy it's exposed to. It isn't radioactive, and it has no known negative effects. Selling this to a scientist would get you a fair sum of money as it is both extremely rare, benign, and has anomalous properties that defy the laws of physics.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="af-art_sterj">
		<text>Rod 2465</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_zone_art_chernaya_busina">
		<text>This artifact, resembling numerous black beads, has the anomalous trait of picking up the negative psionic properties of its host, such as anger or anxiety.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="af-art_chernaya_busina">
		<text>Black Bead</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_zone_art_lichinka">
		<text>This artifact, which appears to be a shrunken larva of an unknown type of insect inside a glass oval, has the anomalous property of saturating its host.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="af-art_lichinka">
		<text>Larva</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_zone_art_3_step_anom_svetim">
		<text>This artifact has a level-three rating for anomalous energy. Its properties unknown, except for one - it increases resistance of its host to radiation. It is known that level-three artifacts can react abnormally with other artifacts of the same type.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="af-art_3_step_anom_svetim">
		<text>This artifact has a level-three rating for anomalous energy.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_zone_art460">
		<text>This artifact, designated #460, is an object with a negative degree of anomalous energy. Its properties are unknown. It's well known that artifacts that have negative degrees of anomalous energy can react anomalously with other artifacts of the same type.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="af-art460">
		<text>Artifact #460</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_zone_artifact_black_kristal">
		<text>An artifact of unknown origin. Very little is known about this artifact. It has the anomalous trait of increasing the physical strength of its host, allowing its host to run for longer periods of time.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="af-black_kristal">
		<text>Black Crystal</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_zone_artifact_af_kolco">
		<text>An artifact of unknown origin. It has the anomalous trait of increasing the physical strength of its host, allowing its host to run for longer periods of time, although this specific artifact will degrade if you use it for long periods of time.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="af-af_kolco">
		<text>Ring</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_zone_af_studen">
		<text>This artifact is a highly hazardous, viscous substance that has numerous colonies of bacteria that's highly dangerous. You should only carry this around if you have an R1 capsule to store it safely.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="af-af_studen">
		<text>Stud</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_af_gold_fish_black">
		<text>This artifact is the result of merging two together with a specialized device. It has both the positive and negative traits of its parental artifacts.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="af-af_gold_fish_black">
		<text>Black Gravi</text>
	</string>
	<string id="af_studen_m1_desc">
		<text>This artifact is the result of modifying the genes of the Jelly artifact. It protects its host against parasitic spores, and also greatly augments the immune system of its host - making it nearly impossible for any virus or bacteria to make its host ill.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ui_st_unknown_art_name">
		<text>Unknown artifact</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ui_st_unknown_art_desc">
		<text>An artifact with unknown properties.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="af-ameba-mica">
		<text>Mercury Ball</text>
	</string>
	<string id="af-ameba-slime">
		<text>Radioactive bolt</text>
	</string>
	<string id="af-ameba-slug">
		<text>Radioactive fragment</text>
	</string>
	<string id="af-blood">
		<text>Toad's Eye</text>
	</string>
	<string id="af-cristall">
		<text>Double pacifier</text>
	</string>
	<string id="af-cristall-flower">
		<text>Glass bagel</text>
	</string>
	<string id="af-drops">
		<text>Droplet</text>
	</string>
	<string id="af-dummy-battery">
		<text>Disintegrator</text>
	</string>
	<string id="af-dummy-dummy">
		<text>Pacifier</text>
	</string>
	<string id="af-dummy-glassbeads">
		<text>Dead Head</text>
	</string>
	<string id="af-dummy-pellicle">
		<text>Plasma</text>
	</string>
	<string id="af-dummy-spring">
		<text>Washcloth</text>
	</string>
	<string id="af-electra-flash">
		<text>Burning Wat</text>
	</string>
	<string id="af-electra-moonlight">
		<text>Electric ball</text>
	</string>
	<string id="af-electra-sparkler">
		<text>Node</text>
	</string>
	<string id="af-fireball">
		<text>Transparent ball</text>
	</string>
	<string id="af-fuzz-kolobok">
		<text>Sharp needles</text>
	</string>
	<string id="af-gold-fish">
		<text>Strong gravitational artifact</text>
	</string>
	<string id="af-gravi">
		<text>Gravitational artifact</text>
	</string>
	<string id="af-medusa">
		<text>Bagel</text>
	</string>
	<string id="af-mincer-meat">
		<text>Rusty Hair</text>
	</string>
	<string id="af-night-star">
		<text>Magnet</text>
	</string>
	<string id="af-rusty-kristall">
		<text>Black Thorn</text>
	</string>
	<string id="af-rusty-sea-urchin">
		<text>Needles</text>
	</string>
	<string id="af-rusty-thorn">
		<text>Thorn</text>
	</string>
	<string id="af-soul">
		<text>Black blobs</text>
	</string>
	<string id="af-vyvert">
		<text>Weak gravitational artifact</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_zone_artifact_af-ameba-mica">
		<text>This artifact is composed of anomalous liquid metal. It's formed after an emission, and if you use it - it'll stay in contact with your body and then evaporate after a short while.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_zone_artifact_af-ameba-slime">
		<text>This is a cheap and widespread artifact. It manifests in the form of metal debris, and it's completely devoid of any useful properties. You can sell it to traders for a pittance, since researchers want artifacts like these for measuring levels of radiation.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_zone_artifact_af-ameba-slug">
		<text>This is a cheap and widespread artifact. It manifests in the form of metal debris, and it's completely devoid of any useful properties. You can sell it to traders for a pittance, since researchers want artifacts like these for measuring levels of radiation.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_zone_artifact_af-blood">
		<text>This artifact is unique and is the end result of a Whirligig and a Black Spike interacting with each other. The result of interaction between the Black Spike and the Meat Grinder. This artifact is also rare and rarely appears.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_zone_artifact_af-cristall">
		<text>This artifact appears normally appears in clusters of anomalies. It protects its host against fainting, restores strength, and also gives protection against psionic radiation.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_zone_artifact_af-cristall-flower">
		<text>This artifact is sometimes formed by the Springboard anomaly. It can found in specific parts of the Zone that have Springboards.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_zone_artifact_af-drops">
		<text>This artifact is formed by the "Burner" anomaly at high temperatures. Externally, it looks like a blackened, droplet-shaped formation with a glossy surface that's covered with cracks.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_zone_artifact_af-dummy-battery">
		<text>A super-artifact that is both magnetic and electrical in nature. One of its distinct features is its directional disintegration field. When activated, it emits a powerful field that instantly transforms any objects into "jelly". The origin of this object is shrouded in scientific mystery. It's clear that it's made in part by dielectric elements, but science does not know the physical conditions in which it's formed.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_zone_artifact_af-dummy-dummy">
		<text>This artifact is normally formed by weak electrical anomalies. It has no practical uses, so it won't get you much money if you sell it.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_zone_artifact_af-dummy-glassbeads">
		<text>A level-two super-artifact. It normally appears in clusters of anomalies, and it has the ability to scare away mutants - but it can also attract Controllers. If you use it to scare away mutants, it loses its anomalous energy and will vaporize once its energy is exhausted. This artifact is rare, so it'll get you a lot of money if you sell it.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_zone_artifact_af-dummy-pellicle">
		<text>This artifact is the result of two artfacts transmutating together. It resembles viscous substance that's sticky, but very strong, and tends to spread into crevices. Rumor has it that when this artifact is worn on your belt, it spreads to damaged areas of its host's suit and then solidifies there, patching any holes and damage.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_zone_artifact_af-dummy-spring">
		<text>A super-artifact that has an unstable gravitational field. If you throw it and it hits the floor or an obstacle, it'll go to the nearest living thing and hit it, and it'll repeat this process until it loses momentum or hits an inanimate object. Once it falls, you can pick it up again.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_zone_artifact_af-electra-flash">
		<text>This artifact, which is created by the Burnt Fuzz anomaly, is highly dangerous and leaves severe burns when it comes into contact with unprotected skin. It accumulates in lowlands, pits and hollows. It'll rise into air if its picked by wind, or if its caught in a shockwave of an explosion.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_zone_artifact_af-electra-moonlight">
		<text>This artfact seems to be spawned by the Electro anomaly. This wonderful, round artifact is created when the anomaly is subjected to high temperatures. This artifact is expensive, so it'll get you a lot of money if you sell it.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_zone_artifact_af-electra-sparkler">
		<text>The origin of this artifact, as well as the the origin of its name is shrouded in mystery - although its been theorized that its spawned by the Electro anomaly. It's valued among the researchers in the Zone for its qualities.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_zone_artifact_af-fireball">
		<text>This artifact is created by anomalies that emit intense levels of heat. It has the form of a transparent, shimmering sphere.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_zone_artifact_af-fuzz-kolobok">
		<text>When you hold this mystery of the Zone in your hands, you feel how your skin becomes tougher and less sensitive. You can still shoot through it with a bullet, but it's much more difficult to cut through.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_zone_artifact_af-gold-fish">
		<text>This artifact is created by the Vortex anomaly. It's elemental in nature, and contains a directed gravitional field anomaly. Equipping this artifact will allow you to carry an additional 6 kilograms of weight.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_zone_artifact_af-gravi">
		<text>This artifact, elemental in nature, contains a directed gravitional field anomaly. It has a variant with more pronounced anomalous properties: the strong gravitational artifact. Equipping this artifact will allow you to carry an additional 4 kilograms of weight.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_zone_artifact_af-medusa">
		<text>This artifact, elemental in nature, gets its namesake from the fact that it's shaped like a torus. At least two varieties of this artifact are known - the Torus, and the Glass Bagel.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_zone_artifact_af-mincer-meat">
		<text>This artifact, organic in nature, is a bunch of hard lichen fibers fused together. It has no useful properties, but it'll fetch you a few roubles.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_zone_artifact_af-night-star">
		<text>'Magnets' are various metal fragments that have been exposed to gravitational anomalies for long periods of time. Their namesake comes from the fact that these pieces of metal have acquired high-intensity magnetic fields. This sample is from a gear shaft. It has strong unilateral gravitational anomalous field, and because of this, Magnets are used to create gravity-based weapons and anti-gravity devices. It normally appears near the anomaly that creates it. It's not dangerous, so it can be picked up and does not necessarily need to be stored in a container. The artifact moves in every possible way: it dances and jumps up to half a meter, unsteadily hovers above the ground and shakes; it can hang on a wall or ceiling, which confirms its gravitational origin. If your detector picks up this artifact, it'll make a make a sound indicating its presence. Equipping this artifact will allow you to carry an additional 5 kilograms of weight.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_zone_artifact_af-rusty-kristall">
		<text>This artifact is created by the Burnt Fuzz anomaly. It removes and filters out radiation from any living organism that comes into contact with it - although using this artifact will cause you to bleed through the ears and any skin that's exposed to it. That is, through the ears along with some amount of blood. This artifact is very widespread and effective, which is the cause for the its stable price the artifact market.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_zone_artifact_af-rusty-sea-urchin">
		<text>This artifact resembles a large bunch of needles that are 10 centimeters long. It normally appears near its parent anomaly, stuck in the ground and rippling slightly. If you stick it into something, such as a wall or a tree, it won't fall off. Despite how sharp this artifact is, it's relatively harmless and doesn't need to be stored in a specialized container. If your detector picks up this artifact, it'll make a make a sound indicating its presence. This artifact will also give its host some protection against psionic radiation, and it'll also cause blind dogs to lose track of you.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_zone_artifact_af-rusty-thorn">
		<text>This artifact is the result of an interaction between the Burnt Fuzz anomaly and the body of a careless stalker. The Needles artifact stabs the body of its host, no matter what. But it also helps clean the body of radionucliodes. Quite widespread and cheap.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_zone_artifact_af-soul">
		<text>This is an incredibly rare artifact. If it does appear, it can be located near the Whirligig anomaly. Very few stalkers have managed to find this artifact, and few have even seen it. It has a nice shape and it'll get you a great deal of money if you sell it.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_zone_artifact_af-vyvert">
		<text>This artifact is located near Vortex anomaly. When it touches the body, it disseminates any absorbed radiation, and it gives you some protection from scratches or wounds made by weapons. This artifact isn't hard to find, so traders don't pay much for it.</text>
	</string>
</string_table>
