<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1251" ?>
<string_table>





 <string id="zjhfgzheliequp_0"> 
 <text>Hello, Professor. I have a question for you. What do you know about the Phantasm?</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="zjhfgzheliequp_1"> 
 <text>Phantasm? Strange, why do you need this information? We have some information, of course.</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="zjhfgzheliequp_2"> 
 <text>I must find it and destroy it.</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="zjhfgzheliequp_3"> 
 <text>Hmm, interesting. You want to destroy the Phantasm? Many others have tried this.</text> 
 </string>
 <string id="zjhfgzheliequp_4"> 
 <text>So can you tell me what it is and what it's like? I take it it's not your average mutant that a couple of point-blank shots will calm down?</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="zjhfgzheliequp_5"> 
 <text>That's correct. Let's just say the Phantasm is a spherical entity that lives in the deep marshes. It possesses extra sensory perception, and it can also create phantom objects and formations of an energy-informational or ectoplasmic nature.</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="zjhfgzheliequp_6"> 
 <text>Where did you get this information?</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="zjhfgzheliequp_7"> 
 <text>We had a small base out there in the swamps. There's no one there now. All the employees have literally disappeared into thin air. One of the missions of this research group was to monitor the Phantasm and study its habits.</text> 
 </string>
 <string id="zjhfgzheliequp_8"> 
 <text>How can I destroy it?</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="zjhfgzheliequp_9"> 
 <text>It's a long shot. As I mentioned, it's underwater most of the time and can't be easily drawn out. However, we have a special device that can lure it to the surface.</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="zjhfgzheliequp_10"> 
 <text>Great, what do you want for this device?</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="zjhfgzheliequp_11"> 
 <text>Well, since you're here and interested in helping us, we have a task for you.</text> 
 </string>
 <string id="zjhfgzheliequp_12"> 
 <text>What are you talking about?</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="zjhfgzheliequp_13"> 
 <text>You've been to zombie town before, you must know the neighborhood. I'm talking about the low-lying swamp outside of town. The group that's stationed in the city has seen a Phantasm-like creature, but it's not a Phantasm. It's a very strange creature, and extremely rare. We can't study it, it's too dangerous. You will have to destroy this mutant. First, we'll give you our experimental psi-blocker. It will help you to keep your sanity intact, as stalkers that have seen this creature noted that the psionic activity near is off the scale. Also, we'll give a device that should lure out the monster.</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="zjhfgzheliequp_14"> 
 <text>So in order to get the equipment to hunt Phantasm, I have to destroy some kind of Phantasm-like mutant first?</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="zjhfgzheliequp_15"> 
 <text>Yeah, that's right. Destroy the creature in the abyss in zombie town, you'll get a second Phantasm-kit. You'll also do a little test on our device, since it hasn't been field-tested.</text> 
 </string>
 <string id="zjhfgzheliequp_16"> 
 <text>Good. Can you tell me what weapons are effective against it?</text> 
 </string>
 <string id="zjhfgzheliequp_17"> 
 <text>Bullets don't seem to affect it according to our information and reports from Freedom stalkers. However, grenade launchers seem to be effective against it. At least the thing went down after that shot.</text> 
 </string>




      <string id="zzheliequp_0"> 
 <text>Take your equipment, Professor.</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="zzheliequp_1"> 
 <text>Well, good. I hope you didn't get spotted in the village?</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="zzheliequp_2"> 
 <text>No. Why the secrecy? They're just ordinary bandits, except they're more heavily armed.</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="zzheliequp_3"> 
 <text>I'll tell you, it's not in your interest to know what's what. You've done your job, now we can talk.</text> 
 </string>




      <string id="oheliequp_0"> 
 <text>Hooah, we made it!</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="oheliequp_1"> 
 <text>Well, you've gotten a warm welcome from the zone.</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="oheliequp_2"> 
 <text>Zip it, man. If it wasn't for you, I think we would be dead. How the hell did these assholes get RPGs? That's crazy, man! Alright, well, here's the equipment, that's what you're gonna give to the Professor. He's probably waiting for it. They've been on army rations for a week. Okay, thanks again.</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="oheliequp_3"> 
 <text>Yeah, well, good luck to you, too.</text> 
 </string>




      <string id="heliequp_0"> 
 <text>Anything else?</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="heliequp_1"> 
 <text>You know we're one of the few government science groups in the entire zone to study what's going on here officially? No? Well, now you do. We're running low on supplies, and a few hours ago we requested the equipment we need from the Big Land. The only way to deliver it is by air. There's a helipad on our bunker, right above us.</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="heliequp_2"> 
 <text>Go on, Professor, what's to be done?</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="heliequp_3"> 
 <text>The helicopter is approaching the lake area, it usually flies from the side of the former town where the stalkers' bar is now located. You need to head towards the abandoned village here on Yantar and follow the helicopter. The thing is that the local looters, simply put bandits can raid our convoy with expensive equipment, as the helicopter has to go at low altitude because of the extremely strong anomalous activity coming from under the lake. It turns out that in case of an attack, our convoy has no opportunity for maneuver and will not be able to fight back. Your task is to go towards the village and control the passage of the cargo. I don't think it's necessary to shine in the village... hide on the roof of one of the houses. After that, the helicopter will land at our landing pad, where the pilot will hand you the equipment, which you will deliver to our bunker. Okay, I'm gonna loan you a rifle just in case. Anything can happen. After you get the equipment, don't forget to give it back to me.</text> 
 </string>




      <string id="jiannar_0"> 
 <text>Professor, I've been to the lab under the Dark Valley.</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="jiannar_1"> 
 <text>What!? What did you see there? Did you find anything there?</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="jiannar_2"> 
 <text>A few dead people. Apparently your employees, and some equipment. Here, take a look.</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="jiannar_3"> 
 <text>Ah. This is my fault. Well, give me what you got. And here, take this from me personally.</text> 
 </string>




      <string id="jannar_0"> 
 <text>Greetings, Professor.</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="jannar_1"> 
 <text>Messer, you can't imagine how much the scientific community owes you. Thanks to you, Messer, we can now venture deep into the Zone without fear of being hit by psi radiation. You can't imagine how long we've dreamed of this. Now our lab will definitely get an increase in funding. Thank you from the bottom of my heart.</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="jannar_2"> 
 <text>You're welcome. But I didn't come here to thank you. I was hoping the reward would be a little more material.</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="jannar_3"> 
 <text>Oh, trust me, I understand. Here you go. You deserve it.</text> 
 </string>
 <string id="jannar_4"> 
 <text>...</text> 
 </string>
 <string id="jannar_5"> 
 <text>What the? Shit, it looks like someone's attacking our mobile lab again. Damn it! The bunker's defense system is down! It must be the zombified that were controlled by the installation. Now they're coming this way.</text> 
 </string>
 <string id="jannar_6"> 
 <text>Is there anything I can do to help?</text> 
 </string>
 <string id="jannar_7"> 
 <text>Help repel the attack. Contact the safety officer in charge of lab personnel. Ask how you can help. Either way, science will thank you handsomely. One more time.</text> 
 </string>








      <string id="jpnnar_0"> 
 <text>Professor, are you alright?</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="jpnnar_1"> 
 <text>Oh, I think so. Where the hell did they come from? It's alright, though, it's not the first time. how are you?</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="jpnnar_2"> 
 <text>I think I'm fine. They were probably brought in by a controller, probably from the city.</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="jpnnar_3"> 
 <text>Well, at least the pack's been wiped out. Take this gift from us, I think you'll find it very useful. Oh, shit. I'm getting so old. I can't even think straight. Yes, I should probably share some information with you in addition to that... Here's a marker for your PDA, there's a transition to some old tunnels here in the Lake Yantar area... I don't know what's in there, but I think that information would be useful.</text> 
 </string>


<!--Dialogues with the Chief Scientist-->
    <string id="yan_saharov_monsters_0">
	    <text>Professor, can you tell me anything about the mutants of the Zone?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_saharov_monsters_1">
	    <text>Which species are you specifically interested in? I warn you, I can't tell you about all of them.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_saharov_monsters_11">
	    <text>I'd love to hear about the controllers.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_saharov_monsters_12">
	    <text>I'm interested in zombies.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_saharov_monsters_13">
	    <text>Burers. I hate the Burers.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_saharov_monsters_14">
	    <text>Tell me about the pseudo-giants.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_saharov_monsters_15">
	    <text>Pseudo-dogs, and common mutts.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_saharov_monsters_111">
	    <text>There are many theories about the origin of these mutants. The most common is that they're the victims of a failed experiment on the human brain. They're very dangerous. They subdue their influence by eye contact. That's why encountering them in the open is almost certain death.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_saharov_monsters_121">
	    <text>Here on Yantar, they're especially numerous. They're just shells left by humans after prolonged exposure to psi radiation. In the early stages of decomposition, they can still wield weapons, so they are the most dangerous. At a later stage, they're just walking corpses. Most difficult to deal with in a large group of zombies.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_saharov_monsters_131">
	    <text>Dwarves, whose origin is unknown, but most likely something similar to experiments with controllers. Possess kinetic abilities, that is, they can interact with objects at a distance. Very dangerous creatures, usually living in catacombs.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_saharov_monsters_141">
	    <text>Perhaps one of the most terrifying creatures in the Zone. Its size frightens even seasoned stalkers, often there are specimens whose skin can not be penetrated even by a bullet from an automatic rifle. Stupid walking carcasses, which are driven only by instincts.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_saharov_monsters_151">
	    <text>During the Second Explosion, many animals, including dogs, were hit by a huge amount of energy, and as a result we have mutants. Pseudo-dogs are usually the leaders of a pack of blind dogs. An encounter with a well-organized group usually ends in death.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_saharov_monsters_2">
	    <text>None of these interest me.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_saharov_monsters_3">
	    <text>Thank you for the information!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_saharov_monsters_4">
	    <text>There's something else I'd like to know.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_saharov_monsters_5">
	    <text>...</text>
	</string>
    <string id="bring_arts_thank">
	    <text>Here's your fee, anything else?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bring_arts_666">
	    <text>No.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bring_arts_0">
	    <text>I brought something.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bring_arts_1">
	    <text>What have you got there?</text>
	</string>
    <string id="bring_arts_101">
	    <text>A magnet.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bring_arts_102">
	    <text>A strong gravitational artifact.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bring_arts_103">
	    <text>Double empty.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bring_arts_104">
	    <text>Black blobs.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bring_arts_105">
	    <text>Electric ball.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bring_arts_106">
	    <text>Mercury ball.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bring_arts_107">
	    <text>Sponge.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bring_arts_108">
	    <text>Empty.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bring_arts_109">
	    <text>Dead head.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bring_arts_110">
	    <text>Needles.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bring_arts_111">
	    <text>Strong needles.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bring_arts_no">
	    <text>Some other time.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="what_do_in_zone_0">
	    <text>What are you guys doing here?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="what_do_in_zone_1">
	    <text>We're investigating the phenomena of the Zone from a scientific point of view. I'm realizing more and more that that's impossible. But you can help us in this difficult endeavor by bringing us artifacts.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="what_do_in_zone_2">
	    <text>All of them?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="what_do_in_zone_3">
	    <text>No, we don't need common artifacts. We only want the rarest ones, so we won't take the bounty. Bring us only the rarest specimens. If we need an artifact like the one you got, we'll buy it back in any condition for a flat fee of 500. </text>
	</string>
	<string id="what_do_in_zone_4">
	    <text>Alright, I'll come around.</text>
	</string>
<!---->

   <string id="o2_bar_0">
     <text>I dropped off the container.</text>
  </string>
   <string id="o2_bar_1">
     <text>Good. Did they meet you?</text>
  </string>
   <string id="o2_bar_2">
     <text>Yeah, there was a stalker. By the way, what kind of village is this?</text>
  </string>
   <string id="o2_bar_3">
     <text>It's where the workers of the compound used to live. Along with their children. I heard they all disappeared at one point. It's a murky story... and in Bar, where people lived in the houses, there was a similar situation...</text>
  </string>
   <string id="o2_bar_4">
    <text>I know that. Is there anything you can tell me about the Journalist?</text>
  </string>
   <string id="o2_bar_5">
    <text>Yeah. He disappeared a few months ago, looking for information about the Zone. I haven't heard much about him myself, but I know he had some business in Bar... I know he was on Yantar. hanging around a ruined house for a while. And he's been seen in Shining Path more than once. Even probably the most times... So, uh, search somewhere in these parts. That's all I can tell you about him.</text>
  </string>
   <string id="o2_bar_6">
    <text>Okay, alright.</text>
   </string>
  <string id="o2_bar_7">
    <text>Thanks again, Messer.</text>
  </string> 

   <string id="o_bar_0">
     <text>What's the job? Professor gave me a tip.</text>
  </string>
   <string id="o_bar_1">
     <text>You know how to drive? You probably can, it's not your first day here. Anyway, I need to take a car with a container to the village.</text>
  </string>
   <string id="o_bar_2">
     <text>What car?</text>
  </string>
   <string id="o_bar_3">
     <text>It's here, at the base. An old RAF. We use it to transport all sorts of crap... for recycling and stuff. Here's the key. You take the container, leave the car here too. They'll take it to the right place.</text>
  </string>
   <string id="o_bar_4">
    <text>Will there be someone waiting for me at the site?</text>
  </string>
   <string id="o_bar_5">
     <text>Yes, a man will meet you. We work closely with the regular stalkers, not just you alone.</text>
  </string>
   <string id="o_bar_6">
    <text>Good.</text>
   </string>
  <string id="o_bar_7">
    <text>Don't go too fast, Messer.</text>
  </string> 



   <string id="sahs_bar_0">
     <text>We did it, Professor. The measurements are in.</text>
  </string>
   <string id="sahs_bar_1">
     <text>Yeah, I got the results.</text>
  </string>
   <string id="sahs_bar_2">
     <text>What's next?</text>
  </string>
   <string id="sahs_bar_3">
     <text>The picture is becoming clearer. There is indeed a laboratory beneath the central complex, and something in it is creating a psi-barrier. From my research, I've determined that it's possible to get to the psi unit and disable it. But the thing is, all the entrances are blocked by a psi-field. However, based on the equipment you brought, I've constructed a psi-blocker that will help you gain access to one of the lab's entrances.</text>
  </string>
   <string id="sahs_bar_4">
    <text>You're suggesting we disable that device?</text>
  </string>
   <string id="sahs_bar_5">
    <text>That's right. Take the psi-blocker. The entrance is in a large loading hangar, collapsed by the pressure of the bridge. However, there are no exact coordinates for the control room and you'll have to find it yourself.</text>
  </string>
   <string id="sahs_bar_6">
    <text>I'll do my best.</text>
   </string>
  <string id="sahs_bar_7">
    <text>Good. I'm counting on you, Messer!</text>
  </string> 


   <string id="sah_bar_0">
     <text>Rat said you could help me get to the center.</text>
  </string>
   <string id="sah_bar_1">
     <text>Yeah, the Barkeep contacted us, we talked to him about the current state of affairs. Theoretically it's possible to get to the center, but as you know, the way is blocked by some kind of psi installations...</text>
  </string>
   <string id="sah_bar_2">
     <text>What do you want me to do?</text>
  </string>
   <string id="sah_bar_3">
     <text>We're at one of the Zone's scientific bases, our goal is to study this place. There's a localized psi installation of unknown origin. Its structure is very similar to the one in the north. If we could study this installation, we could construct a psi-blocker that would help us get to the center. Now, there's been a lot of psi research done in many parts of the Zone. And the thing is, the people who worked on it are gone. But there should be some of their scientific work left behind. You need to get the prototypes developed by our employees, as well as two samples of gravity weapons. The first prototype is in the laboratory under the Dark Valley in the closed laboratory control room. The code to the door is 4678. The second prototype is in one of the apartments in the town of Shining Path in the north. More precisely, you can find out from the leader of the Freedom faction where it is. As for the gravity weapon - we can't say for sure, but there are reports that there is a certain sanctuary of dwarves in the laboratory under the Dark Valley, and they have what we need... And then there's the most important thing. We need documentation on how the psi helmet works. It's a zombie brain activity emulator. I know for a fact that there are several copies of this documentation, and they were stolen by stalkers from the research institute on Agroprom and Dark Valley. However, I don't know exactly where they are. Try asking traders, or people who trade in information. They might be able to help with that.</text>
  </string>
   <string id="sah_bar_4">
    <text>Alright, I'll get the prototypes.</text>
  </string>
   <string id="sah_bar_5">
    <text>This is excellent, Messer! But be careful, there are a lot of radiation sources on the lake. Yeah, talk to the leader of Clear Sky, he'll probably have a job for you.</text>
  </string>
   <string id="sah_bar_6">
    <text>I'll make sure to talk to him.</text>
   </string>
  <string id="sah_bar_7">
    <text>Then we'll decide what to do next.</text>
  </string>  


   <string id="sahh_bar_0">
     <text>Hello, Professor. I got what you asked for.</text>
  </string>
   <string id="sahh_bar_1">
     <text>Hello, Messer. Give them here, now we'll see what we can do about it.</text>
  </string>
   <string id="sahh_bar_2">
     <text>Well, what do you think, Professor?</text>
  </string>
   <string id="sahh_bar_3">
     <text>Quite interesting specimens. Unfortunately, however, the data here needs to be deciphered. In addition, psi-field measurements must be taken.</text>
  </string>
   <string id="sahh_bar_4">
    <text>Psi-field measurements? I don't know how to take any psi-field measurements. What even is that?</text>
  </string>
   <string id="sahh_bar_5">
    <text>All you have to do is ensure the safety of our employee who will be taking the measurements. There's a parking lot across the street from our base. Walk to the entrance of the parking lot and you'll spot him. He'll be coming from the direction of the stranded barge.</text>
  </string>
   <string id="sahh_bar_6">
    <text>I'm on my way.</text>
   </string>
  <string id="sahh_bar_7">
    <text>Be careful, there's mutant activity in that area. Oh, before I forget. Please accept this item as a thank you. I think you're gonna need it. It's an exoskeleton battery. With it, you can use this type of suit at full power. However, this item is very rare, and I advise you to keep it safe. It is unlikely that you will be able to find another working copy of this kind... It can be recharged in our bunker. Now go on, I think the assistant will be at the bunker soon.</text>
  </string>  


	<string id="zam_talk_0">
		<text>You're the one who's supposed to be taking psi-field measurements?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zam_talk_1">
		<text>Yes, that's right. The plan is to move towards the tower in the village area. Then go to the left side of the parking lot. Then follow me, and cover me. We'll go towards the pillbox and the dome-shaped structure. Once we're done, we'll go to the base.</text>
 
	</string>
	<string id="zam_talk_2">
		<text>Got it.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zam_talk_3">
		<text>By the way, there's help for the camp arrived in an APC. Apparently, the professor managed to negotiate with the local stalkers. Well, let's go!</text>
	</string>


	<string id="sah_talk_0">
		<text>Professor, do you have any water to drink?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sah_talk_1">
		<text>Yes, of course. There's a kettle of water right behind you. Drink to your content.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sah_talk_2">
		<text>How much you want me to pay?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sah_talk_3">
		<text>For stalker, the drinks are on us. Help yourself.</text>
	</string>


	<string id="oles_talk_0">
		<text>Hi, who are you?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="oles_talk_1">
		<text>We're a group called Clear Sky, we are ecologist stalkers in essence. We study the Zone, looking for a way to cure the world of this plague. We're neutral toward all factions.</text>
 
	</string>
	<string id="oles_talk_2">
		<text>Right. I see you're working with scientists?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="oles_talk_3">
		<text>Yes. Unfortunately, there aren't many of us. Few people share our views.</text>
	</string>



	<string id="ohr_talk_0">
		<text>Are you going to the base? To the scientists? Come on, come on in. Just keep your weapon holstered!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ohr_talk_1">
		<text>I see you've hired yourself out to guard the scientists' base.</text>
 
	</string>
	<string id="ohr_talk_2">
		<text>Yeah. It's an easy, quiet job.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ohr_talk_3">
		<text>I didn't think this place could be quiet.</text>
	</string>


	<string id="za1">
		<text>Messer! You did it! Damn, I am not sure what to say. The installation is down, I suppose. It only makes sense to head north next.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="za2">
		<text>Hey, there. Yeah, that wasn't easy. You're going north? You don't mind teaming up?</text>
 
	</string>
	<string id="za3">
		<text>No, I'm sorry. We're probably not going the same way. But maybe I'll see you around. Thanks again for your contribution and good deed, Messer!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="za4">
		<text>Good luck to you.</text>
	</string>



	<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_talk_start_121111">
		<text>Just for you, the price is a very reasonable 2 grand. What do you think? Yes, I'll tell you right away - after the treatment, your body will be highly susceptible to spores, so I recommend staying away from sources of infection for a while, until you regain the necessary immunity.</text>
	</string>


	<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_talk_start_211144">
		<text>Relax, you're lucky it's in my best interest for you to disable the damn machine. Here's the helmet, but a reward is out of the question, because you've screwed up big time, young man. The entrance to the underground complex is in the large loading bay, that's the way down. Just don't go into the center of the complex, the radiation's off the charts. That's it, go.</text>
	</string>


</string_table>
