<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1251" ?>
<string_table>
	<string id="mil_max_dialog_8001">
		<text>Hey, stalker! What are you doing here?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mil_max_dialog_8002">
		<text>I'm here on business. Can you tell me where your main man is?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mil_max_dialog_8003">
		<text>Go to the main hall.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mil_zoneguard_common2_0">
     <text>Hello. It looks like you're settling in nicely.</text>
  </string>
   <string id="mil_zoneguard_common2_1">
     <text>You seem to be doing good too. Yeah, we picked a quieter place, so to speak - but there's a lot of dangerous shit in town.</text>
  </string>
   <string id="mil_zoneguard_common2_2">
     <text>How do you guys survive here? It's dangerous here.</text>
  </string>
   <string id="mil_zoneguard_common2_3">
     <text>Yeah, mostly. This spot's relatively safe, that's why we hang out here. In fact, if the occasion arises, we'll relocate. It wouldn't be the first time we've done so.</text>
  </string>
   <string id="mil_zoneguard_common2_4">
    <text>Take care.</text>
  </string>
	<string id="g_bhar_0">
     <text>Anything else?</text>
  </string>
   <string id="g_bhar_1">
     <text>Well, you've made it clear that you're genuinely determined to find what you're looking for.</text>
  </string>
   <string id="g_bhar_2">
     <text>You're right. So what do you want me to do this time?</text>
  </string>
   <string id="g_bhar_3">
     <text>We need raw materials. Not food, no. Not even artifacts. Raw materials.</text>
  </string>
   <string id="g_bhar_4">
    <text>Uhh.. what are you talking about? Can you be more specific?</text>
  </string>
   <string id="g_bhar_5">
    <text>Flesh.</text>
  </string>
   <string id="g_bhar_6">
    <text>You mean the flesh of mutants? You want me to kill some mutants and collect tissue samples from them?</text>
   </string>
  <string id="g_bhar_7">
    <text>No, you misunderstand me, stalker. We need the dead flesh of small animals. Bring some rat and crow carcasses, I think that'll be enough for us.</text>
  </string> 
	<string id="gdhs_0">
		<text>Here, take these carcasses.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gdhs_1">
	<text>Let's see... hmm, yes, you did good.</text> 
	</string>
	<string id="gdhs_2">
		<text>I hope you won't need anything else?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gdhs_3">
		<text>Well, you've done your job. Get out of here while you're still alive. Who knows if you'll be able to be reborn next time...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="what_for_went_to_zone_0">
		<text>I hear you're looking for something in the Zone. Can you tell me more about it?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="what_for_went_to_zone_1">
	    <text>About six months ago, there was a major incident. As you know, there are many settlements around the Chernobyl Exclusion Zone. One day, the children of all the surrounding settlements went deep into the Zone, and they didn't come back. I've tried to find out what happened to them, but to no avail...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="what_for_went_to_zone_2">
	    <text>I had a vision at the school in Pripyat. I saw a man and a child. One of them became a mutant, then I woke up, and, would you believe it, there was a dwarf next to me. I killed him.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="what_for_went_to_zone_3">
	    <text>Hmm, that clears up a few things.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="what_for_went_to_zone_4">
	    <text>I hope so.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="what_try_do_0">
	    <text>What are you going to do next?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="what_try_do_1">
	    <text>Well, I can't go to the Big Land after I told people about what happened to the kids, they won't leave me be.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="what_try_do_2">
	    <text>What about here in the Zone?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="what_try_do_3">
	    <text>I'll stay here. I'm used to life here, although you never truly get used to it. I guess I'm just adapting.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="what_try_do_4">
	    <text>I see.</text>
		</string>
	<string id="j_bar_0">
		<text>Hello, Gunslinger.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="j_bar_1">
		<text>Journalist?!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="j_bar_2">
		<text>Yes, I'm Journalist. I'm ready to answer your questions.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="j_bar_3">
		<text>What happened to me on my first trip to the center of the Zone?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="j_bar_4">
		<text>You and a group of stalkers went to the center of the Zone through Pripyat, right after the first big blowout. As you followed a group of military men, there was a second explosion. I don't know what happened next, all I know is that you somehow survived and were sent back to the barrier on a "death truck".</text>
	</string>
	<string id="j_bar_5">
		<text>What do you know about the Black Monolith?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="j_bar_6">
		<text>The Black Monolith is also known as the "Wish Granter". You know, some things are actually quite different in reality than they appear at first glance. The Monolith is just an illusion, a weapon in the hands of those who are behind what's happening here. The center of the Zone is not at the power plant, but further from it, and all the Zone's mysteries can be solved there. I think if you manage to get to the Monolith, we can figure out how to find a way to the center of the Zone.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="j_bar_7">
		<text>I'm going to the Sarcophagus... I think I know what I want.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gds_0">
		<text>The stalkers are dead.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gds_1">
		<text>Did you learn anything from their conversation?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gds_2">
		<text>They were going to attack your base.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gds_3">
		<text>Morons! They didn't stand a chance anyway. And you, in turn, have shown your worth, twice-born. We're watching you with great interest. You're living up to our expectations of you, stalker.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mil_secret">
		<text>Unknown Stalker: If you sit in a water tower all night, something is bound to happen...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mg_svob_hello">
		<text>Freedom: Stalker, you are on our territory, so don't try anything funny. If you want to earn some money, please proceed to our base.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_0">
		<text>Greetings...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_1">
		<text>Oh, it's the new guy. We just got back from a raid here. This our base, more or less, although we move around sometimes, so to speak. You didn't happen to come from Yantar, did you? Chrome said some guy is doing business with the Professor, doing all sorts of orders for him and being very efficient at it. We know about you. But, uh, make sure to back up your reputation, okay? Once you do, you can talk to our boss. So listen up: we got a squad coming back from a raid from Yantar, and something really bizarre happened - we lost their signal in the school district. I'm afraid something went wrong. Why don't you go check it out?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_2">
		<text>Alright, I'll check it out.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_3">
		<text>Some other time.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="as_0">
		<text>The squad was taken over by a controller. I was able to kill it, and your guys are on their way back, safe and sound.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="as_1">
		<text>Holy shit.. thank you, it must have followed them all the way from Yantar. They mentioned that their transmitter kept malfunctioning.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="as_2">
		<text>Yeah, that's probably what happened.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds2_0">
		<text>Do you have any more work?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds2_1">
		<text>We're thinking of expanding, and there's some weird shit going on in the building across the street. I've heard about glass shards flying out through windows and guns being ripped out of the hands of stalkers. Something isn't right. We don't have a lot of people here right now, and nobody wants to go in there. You're a brave guy, you've proven yourself. Do you want to check it out?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds2_2">
		<text>I'll do it. I'll see what's going on.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds2_3">
		<text>Some other time.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="as2_0">
		<text>There were several poltergeists in the building. That explains all the stuff you mentioned previously. They won't bother you again.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="as2_1">
		<text>Thanks again for your help, stalker. You know, there's not a lot of people like you in the Zone. Very few people would bother to help with something like this.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="as2_2">
		<text>You're welcome, good luck.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds2_kvest">
		<text>Check the building</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mil_bodyguard_dialog_0">
		<text>I can thank you for that. After that mess at the roadblock, I had to run north to get away. The radiation here is high, but that will keep me safe from them - they won't pursue because most of the grunts don't know how to deal with that. I don't need them hunting me down. Even with our business ties, they had a grudge against me.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mil_bodyguard_dialog_1">
		<text>The Sinners. They're some crazy dudes. One of them came here the other day, went to the counter, stood there silently for ten minutes, and then left without a word. It was like a fucking horror movie. And then last night, I was just about to close up. This bunker's got good doors, and a couple of these stoners came in. They're standing over there in the corner staring at me. I tell them to get the fuck out, and they don't give a shit. Fuck them.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mil_max_dialog_2001">
		<text>Go on.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mil_screw_dialog_1000">
		<text>What do you want here?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mil_screw_dialog_1001">
		<text>I got a message from your leader.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mil_screw_dialog_1002">
		<text>A message? Interesting..</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mil_screw_dialog_1003">
		<text>Who are you?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mil_screw_dialog_1004">
		<text>Does it matter?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mil_screw_dialog_1005">
		<text>Not really, I guess.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mil_screw_dialog_1006">
		<text>That's right, stalker. Oh, by the way. You have to give me an artifact. The artifact I specifically need is a Dead Head.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mil_screw_dialog_1100">
		<text>No.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mil_screw_dialog_1101">
		<text>Then get out.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mil_screw_dialog_1102">
		<text>Alright. (chuckles)</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mil_screw_dialog_1200">
		<text>Here you go.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mil_screw_dialog_1201">
		<text>Then let's make a deal.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mil_screw_dialog_1202">
		<text>Good luck.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mil_screw_dialog_2000">
		<text>...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mil_screw_dialog_4">
		<text>Did you bring the artifact?</text>
	</string>
</string_table>
