


	<string id="traders">
		<text>Trader</text>
	</string>


	<string id="jurnalist_bio">
		<text>This experienced stalker goes by the name "Journalist". He is unsociable and reclusive. The only thing that's known about him is that he's looking for something in the Zone.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="esc_noobik_bio">
		<text>This stalker is an experienced veteran that been in the Zone for a long time. Rumored to be on the radar.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="greh_reg_bio">
		<text>This individual is former stalker that's been rumored to be a walking corpse now, controlled by some unknown influence.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="aes_Monolit_master_bio">
		<text>This individual is an veteran Monolith soldier. This individual is also highly dangerous, so it's best to stay away from him. No detailed information available.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="aes_Monolit_rpg_bio">
		<text>This individual is a militant that's loyal to the Monolith faction. No details available.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="aes_Monolit_sniper_bio">
		<text>This individual is a sniper that's loyal to the Monolith faction. No detailed information available.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="aes_Monolit_sniper_gauss_bio">
		<text>This individual is a stalker that's loyal to the Monolith faction. No detailed information available.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="aes_Monolit_specnaz_bio">
		<text>This individual is a well-equipped militant that's loyal to the Monolith faction. No details available.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="aes_Soldier_commander_bio">
		<text>This individual is a commander of an military assault force. No details available.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="aes_Soldier_military_bio">
		<text>This individual is a military stalker who is well armed, well trained, and very dangerous. No details available.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="aes_Soldier_sniper_bio">
		<text>No detailed information available.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="aes_Soldier_specnaz_aes_bio">
		<text>This individual is an special forces soldier that's well trained and well equipped. No details available.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="aes_Soldier_specnaz_aes_name">
		<text>Unknown spec ops soldier</text>
	</string>
	<string id="aes_Soldier_specnaz_bio">
		<text>This individual is an special forces soldier that's well trained and well equipped. No details available.</text>
	</string>



	<string id="agr_krot_bio">
		<text>A young stalker from the nearly extinct clan known as the "Disciples of Master D," he is a self-proclaimed Tolkien enthusiast. Inspired by the romantic fantasies he devoured in his youth, he ventured into the Zone despite skepticism from seasoned loners, many of whom believed he wouldn’t survive long. Yet, against all odds, this lover of novels has roamed the Zone for years, relying on his remarkable strength and extraordinary endurance to carve out his place in its harsh, unforgiving landscape.</text>
	</string>


	<string id="bar_rosomaha_bio">
		<text>Wolverine of the Blade Clan is a seasoned stalker who has traversed every corner of the Zone. During his long and storied career, he lost the fingers on his right hand to an encounter with an amoeba anomaly near Kopachi.</text>
	</string>


	<string id="agr_krot_name">
		<text>Mole</text>
	</string>
	<string id="agr_nii_commander_name">
		<text>Captain Maximenko</text>
	</string>
	<string id="agr_ratcatcher_name">
		<text>Pied Piper</text>
	</string>
	<string id="agr_ratcatcher_bio">
		<text>Little is known about this enigmatic figure, and rumors abound. Some claim he’s a former bandit; others insist he’s a counterintelligence officer with the call sign Krysolov. There’s even speculation that he reached the heart of the Zone and wished for the power to command rats, earning him his nickname. One thing is certain - encounters with him are rare, and even seasoned veterans seldom cross his path. Recently, he seems to have vanished entirely, fading from memory as people begin to forget he ever existed.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_arena_stalker">
		<text>This individual is one of the participants in the deadly battles in the Arena. No detailed information available.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_arny_bio">
		<text>This individual is an leader of a group of rookies from the Cordon.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_arny_name">
		<text>Arnie</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_guard_bio">
		<text>Garik serves as the guard of the Stalker Bar - or, if you prefer, the Barkeep's personal bodyguard. His past, like his present, remains shrouded in mystery.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_guard_name">
		<text>Garik</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_guard2_bio">
		<text>Garik's twin brother. He works as an bouncer at the bar. He is as quiet as his brother.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_guard2_name">
		<text>Zhorik</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_barmen_bio">
		<text>Neither a saint nor a scoundrel, he knows his worth, and for that, he’s respected among stalkers. Rumor has it he’s hiding in the Zone to escape a dark past. After an encounter with an anomaly left him with a limp, he decided to change his path. He set up a bar near the Duty group, which quietly became the main gathering spot for Zone veterans. The Barkeep now has extensive connections, both within the Zone and in the outside world.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_barmen_name">
		<text>Barkeep</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_beast_name">
		<text>Beast</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_drunk_bio">
		<text>A Duty member and regular at the Stalker Bar, rumored to have close dealings with Duty's merchant.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_drunk_name">
		<text>Brome</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_hunter_bio">
		<text>A good-natured, cheerful guy, his only quirk is that he refuses to use anything but a hunting shotgun - and he’s a crack shot with it. Unfortunately, he ran into trouble near the Rostok factory and lost his shotgun, a cherished family heirloom. Now he spends his days hanging around the bar, hoping someone will help him get it back.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_hunter_name">
		<text>Hunter</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_informer_bio">
		<text>A mysterious, all-knowing stalker who deals in information at the Stalker Bar.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_informer_name">
		<text>Snitch</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_ivancov_bio">
		<text>An experienced stalker and dedicated member of the Duty faction, he is an ideological fighter who wholeheartedly believes in Duty’s cause. Considered the top candidate for the group’s next leader, he stands out as one of the few who voluntarily ventures into the deep Zone - areas with intense psionic activity - while managing to maintain a clear and sound mind.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_ivancov_name">
		<text>Captain Ivantsov</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_kicenko_name">
		<text>Sergeant Kitsenko</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_lelik_bio">
		<text>The Arena owner's bodyguard. Not much is known about his past, but all of it is bad. He hates his brothers.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_lelik_name">
		<text>Lyolik</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_lisiy_name">
		<text>Baldy</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_petrenko_bio">
		<text>A seasoned military stalker who has explored every corner of the Zone, he found his place within the paramilitary group Duty, quickly earning respect and authority through his extensive experience. His primary role is to procure weapons, ammunition, and medical supplies for the group. Given Duty’s numerous ties to the armed forces beyond the Perimeter, it’s easy to guess who their main sponsor might be. Though he rarely sells his wares to ordinary stalkers, he is known for his kind and gentle demeanor. A passionate collector, his fascination with weaponry goes far beyond mere necessity.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_petrenko_name">
		<text>Petrenko</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_plichko_bio">
		<text>Chief of Duty's territory security.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_plichko_name">
		<text>Plichko</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_ryaboy_bio">
		<text>An unidentified man who has suffered significant mental damage after exposure to a 'brain scorcher'.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_ryaboy_name">
		<text>Ryaboy</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_voronin_bio">
		<text>Voronin, a seasoned Zone veteran, is the leader of the paramilitary group Duty, whose primary mission is the destruction of the Zone. He first entered the Zone as part of the infamous initial armed forces expedition, which ended in a disastrous failure. For several years now, he has commanded Duty with an iron hand, enforcing strict discipline and demanding absolute compliance from his subordinates. Due to numerous assassination attempts by mercenaries, Voronin rarely leaves his office these days. Securing an appointment with him requires strong connections within the Zone.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_voronin_name">
		<text>Voronin</text>
	</string>
	<string id="cit_bandit_drunk_bio">
		<text>Alkash</text>
	</string>
	<string id="cit_bandit_general_bio">
		<text>This individual is a unknown stalker of questionable reputation. No detailed information available.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="cit_bandit_veteran_bio">
		<text>This individual is a unknown stalker of questionable reputation. No detailed information available.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="cit_bandits_leader_bio">
		<text>This individual is one of the leaders of the bandits. Well armed and very dangerous. No detailed information available.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="cit_bandits_leader_name">
		<text>Greyhound</text>
	</string>
	<string id="cit_doctor_bio">
		<text>This person is simply known as 'The Doctor'. Very little is known about this individual.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="cit_doctor_name">
		<text>The Doctor</text>
	</string>
	<string id="cit_killer_exo_bio">
		<text>This unknown individual is a mercenary. Well armed and very dangerous. No detailed information available.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="cit_killer_general_bio">
		<text>This unknown individual is a mercenary. Possibly well armed and dangerous. No detailed information available.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="cit_killers_leader_bio">
		<text>This individual is a stalker that's part of the Clear Sky faction. He's known for collecting information about the Zone, as well as deciphering encrypted PDA's.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="cit_killers_leader_name">
		<text>Dushman</text>
	</string>
	<string id="cit_vp_bio">
		<text>This individual is a highly experienced stalker. No detailed information available.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="cit_vp_name">
		<text>Vasily Petrovich</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dar_corpse_bio">
		<text>No detailed information.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dar_explorer_bio">
		<text>This individual is a highly experienced stalker. He keeps his ear to the ground, keeping up with new developments in the Zone.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dar_explorer_name">
		<text>Zheka Duplet</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dar_kalugin_name">
		<text>Kalugin P.I.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_sergant_regular_bio">
		<text>This individual is a sergeant that's enlisted in the army. No detailed information available.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_soldier_regular_bio">
		<text>This individual is a private that's enlisted in the army. No detailed information available.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_bandit_novice_bio">
		<text>This individual is a unknown stalker of questionable reputation. No detailed information available.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_soldier_blockpost_commander_name">
		<text>Lieutenant Chuguikin</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_lieutenant_bio">
		<text>This individual is a lieutenant that's been enlisted in the army for a long time. No detailed information available.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_captain_bio">
		<text>This individual is a captain that's been enlisted in the army for a long time. No detailed information available.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_fanat_bio">
		<text>This individual is stalker who has managed to not lose his mind, retaining his sanity even after witnessing the worst aspects of the Zone.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_fanat_name">
		<text>Fanatic</text>
	</string>



	<string id="esc_fox_bio">
		<text>An experienced stalker who entered the Zone several years ago, Fox is known for his resourcefulness and cunning. During a deep raid with his partner, they encountered the military conducting a punitive operation near the old warehouses. In the ensuing firefight, Fox's partner was killed, leaving him with a deep, personal grudge against the military. His reputation among stalkers and traders is mixed - many dislike him for his sly nature. Rumors circulate that he doesn’t shy away from robbing other stalkers, though no witnesses have ever come forward to confirm it.</text>
	</string>




	<string id="esc_fox_name">
		<text>Fox</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_killer_specnaz_bio">
		<text>This individual is a unknown contractor, possibly heavily armed. No detailed information available.</text>
	</string>




	<string id="esc_petruha_bio">
		<text>A rookie stalker who arrived in the Zone just two months ago, he has quickly adapted to its harsh environment. So far, he hasn’t ventured beyond Agroprom, believing there’s plenty to be gained on the outskirts of the Zone. Specializing in artifact retrieval for orders and mutant hunting, he has proven himself skilled at both. A humanist by nature, he prefers to steer clear of both the military and bandits, avoiding unnecessary conflict whenever possible.</text>
	</string>




	<string id="esc_petruha_name">
		<text>Petruha</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_provodnik_bio">
		<text>A legendary stalker, known for his unparalleled knowledge of the Zone, he’s said to be able to guide you to any location within it. His services don’t come cheap, but it’s not just about the money - he refuses to work with anyone he doesn’t like, no matter the price. A true veteran, he knows the Zone inside and out.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_provodnik_name">
		<text>Guide</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_sergant_regular_bio">
		<text>This individual is a sergeant that's enlisted in the army. No detailed information available.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_shustryi_bio">
		<text>A stalker who has earned the nickname Quick due for his knack for being both inconspicuous and indispensable. Traders often rely on him for delicate tasks—tailing someone, keeping watch, or discreetly eavesdropping.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_shustryi_name">
		<text>Quick</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_soldier_commander_bio">
		<text>This individual is a major that's enlisted in the army. He commands the checkpoint at the bridge and he's also known for taking a toll from stalkers, letting anyone pass through if they pay.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_soldier_commander_name">
		<text>Major Kuznetsov</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_soldier_regular_bio">
		<text>This individual is a conscripted solider that's enlisted in the army, having the rank of private. No detailed information available.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_specnaz_bio">
		<text>This individual is a special forces operator that's enlisted in the army. Highly trained and well equipped. No detailed information available. (start here for your first session on 1/28/25 and don't forget to remove this reminder when you start)</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_specnaz_killer_bio">
		<text>Unknown Mercenary. Well armed and very dangerous. No details available.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_stalker_novice_bio">
		<text>Rookie. New to the Zone. No details.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_tolik_bio">
		<text>Just a stalker.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_tolik_name">
		<text>Tolik</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_wolf_bio">
		<text>Commander of the patrol of the Cordon zone.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_wolf_name">
		<text>Commander</text>
	</string>
	<string id="escape_trader_bio">
		<text>He's been in the trade since he was a kid. In kindergarten sold colored pencils. At school he sold chewing gum. At the institute, he sold light narcotics. When the Zone came along, he realized there was a good way to make money. He is famous for being able to establish good trade relations with the most diverse customers.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="escape_trader_name">
		<text>Toad</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_bandit_leader_bio">
		<text>Enjoys a certain authority among the bandits in the Zone. Borov's accomplice.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_bandit_leader_name">
		<text>Vasya Kaban</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_dolg_blokpost_bio">
		<text>Stalker of the Duty faction. No detailed information available.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_dolg_blokpost_leader_bio">
		<text>Officer of the Duty faction. No detailed information available.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_dolg_blokpost_leader_name">
		<text>Prapor</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_dram_novice_bio">
		<text>Rookie. Taking his first steps in the Zone.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_dram_novice_name">
		<text>Yurik</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_hellcar_bio">
		<text>Experienced stalker. Fishing for artifacts on the Garbage.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_hellcar_name">
		<text>Sprout</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_newbie_bio">
		<text>A rookie. New to the Zone. No detailed information available.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_seryi_bio">
		<text>Stalker with a dirty face and no less dirty biography.</text>
	</string> 
	<string id="gar_seryi_name">
		<text>Witcher</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_stalker_regular_bio">
		<text>Experienced stalker. No detailed information available.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mil_Dolg_specnaz_bio">
		<text>A militant of the Duty faction. Usually well equipped. No detailed information available.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mil_Dolg_specnaz_cherep_bio">
		<text>Commander of a special forces unit of Duty group. Usually well equipped.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mil_Dolg_specnaz_cherep_name">
		<text>Skull</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mil_Dolg_specnaz_silence_bio">
		<text>A fighter of the Duty faction. Usually well equipped. No detailed information available.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mil_Killer_informator_bio">
		<text>Known throughout the Zone as an Informant and informant.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mil_Killer_informator_name">
		<text>Ara</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mil_killer_master_bio">
		<text>Unknown Mercenary. Well armed and very dangerous. No detailed information available.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mil_killer_sniper_bio">
		<text>Unknown Mercenary. Apparently new to the Zone. No details available.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mil_Killer_specnaz_bio">
		<text>Unknown Mercenary. Probably heavily armed. No details available.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mil_Monolit_master_bio">
		<text>Guardian of the Monolith faction. Best to stay away from him. No details available.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mil_Monolit_regular_bio">
		<text>Monolith stalker. No details available.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mil_Stalker_master_bio">
		<text>One of the Zone's veterans. This stalker knows the Zone like the back of his hand. Usually well equipped and very dangerous. No details available.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mil_Stalker_veteran_bio">
		<text>A veteran stalker. Probably well equipped. No detailed information available.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mil_Svoboda_blockpost_leader_bio">
		<text>Free stalker. A man who has rallied people around him, ready to die for a common cause.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mil_Svoboda_blockpost_leader_name">
		<text>Kep</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mil_Svoboda_bodyguard_bio">
		<text>Guard for Lukash, leader of the Freedom group.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mil_Svoboda_cook_bio">
		<text>Freedom's cook. A drunkard and a debauchee, but an excellent cook.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mil_Svoboda_cook_name">
		<text>Cook</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mil_Svoboda_engineer_bio">
		<text>A well-known mechanic in the Zone. He can build a tank out of a tractor.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mil_Svoboda_engineer_name">
		<text>Screw</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mil_Svoboda_leader_bio">
		<text>Leader of the Freedom faction.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mil_Svoboda_leader_name">
		<text>Freedom leader</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mil_Svoboda_master_bio">
		<text>Master of the Freedom faction. No detailed information available.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mil_Svoboda_master_Max_bio">
		<text>Guardian of the Freedom faction. Fanatically devoted to the faction. Well equipped and very dangerous. No details available.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mil_Svoboda_master_Max_name">
		<text>Chief of Security</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mil_Svoboda_master_Ugrumiy_bio">
		<text>Guardian of the Freedom faction. Well equipped and very dangerous. No details available.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mil_Svoboda_master_Ugrumiy_name">
		<text>Sullen</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mil_Svoboda_Kolyan_name">
		<text>Kolyan</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mil_Svoboda_Tolyan_name">
		<text>Tolyan</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mil_Svoboda_regular_bio">
		<text>Stalker of the Freedom faction. No detailed information available.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mil_Svoboda_sniper_bio">
		<text>Freedom sniper. No detailed information available.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mil_Svoboda_specnaz_bio">
		<text>Freedom fighter. Usually well equipped. No detailed information available.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mil_Svoboda_stukach_bio">
		<text>Freedom Stalker. No detailed information available.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mil_Svoboda_stukach_name">
		<text>Pavlik</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mil_Svoboda_trader_bio">
		<text>Known for being greedy and unyielding, but they say you can get anything from him.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mil_Svoboda_trader_name">
		<text>Freedom Merchant</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mil_Svoboda_zombi_stalker_bio">
		<text>Stalker of the Freedom faction. No detailed information available.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mil_Svoboda_zombi_stalker_name">
		<text>Crazy Freedom Stalker.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mil_Svoboda_zoneguard_bio">
		<text>A Freedom Stalker. Usually well equipped. No detailed information available.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="pri_followers_bomber_name">
		<text>Sasha White</text>
	</string>
	<string id="pri_followers_common_bio">
		<text>Veteran stalker. Possibly well equipped. No detailed information available.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="pri_monolith_common_bio">
		<text>Stalker of the Monolith faction. No detailed information available.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="pri_monolith_exo_bio">
		<text>Elite stalker of the Monolith faction. No detailed information available.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="pri_monolith_leader_bio">
		<text>Leader of the Monolith faction. No detailed information available.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="pri_monolith_leader_name">
		<text>Monolith leader</text>
	</string>
	<string id="pri_monolith_regular_bio">
		<text>Private stalker of the Monolith faction. No detailed information available.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="pri_monolith_specnaz_bio">
		<text>Monolith special forces stalker. No detailed information available.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="pri_zombied_soldier_bio">
		<text>Private soldier. No detailed information available.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="pri_zombied_soldier_name">
		<text>Zombie</text>
	</string>
	<string id="pri_zombied_stalker_bio">
		<text>One of the unlucky stalkers.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="pri_zombied_stalker_name">
		<text>Zombie</text>
	</string>
	<string id="pri_lom_name">
		<text>Crowbar</text>
	</string>
	<string id="pri_brevno_name">
		<text>Log</text>
	</string>
	<string id="rad_dolg_master_bio">
		<text>Master of the Duty faction. Very well equipped. No detailed information available.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="rad_ecolog_bio">
		<text>Scientist. No detailed information available.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="rad_ecolog_guard_bio">
		<text>Scientist guards. No details available.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="rad_ecolog_guard_name">
		<text>Assistant</text>
	</string>
	<string id="rad_ecolog_name">
		<text>Assistant</text>
	</string>
	<string id="rad_monolith_general_bio">
		<text>Stalker of the Monolith faction. No detailed information available.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="rad_monolith_specnaz_bio">
		<text>Monolith militant. Well equipped. No detailed information available.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="rad_specnaz_bio">
		<text>Army Special Forces. Well equipped. Details unavailable.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="rad_stalker_master_bio">
		<text>One of the Zone's veterans. This stalker knows the Zone like the back of his hand. Usually well equipped and very dangerous. Details unavailable.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="rad_stalker_veteran_bio">
		<text>A veteran stalker. Probably well equipped. No details available.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="rad_svoboda_master_bio">
		<text>Master of the Freedom faction. No details available.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="rad_zombied_general_bio">
		<text>One of the unlucky stalkers.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="rad_jaw_zam_name">
		<text>Lyokha Jawbone's replacement.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="stalker_rad_jaw_name">
		<text>Lyokha Jawbone</text>
	</string>
	<string id="stalker_rad_jaw_bio">
		<text>Veteran stalker. Possibly well-equipped. Questionable personality. No detailed information available.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ros_ecolog_guard_bio">
		<text>Employee of a mobile science lab. No details available.</text>
	</string>



	<string id="ros_freeman_bio">
		<text>Unlucky lone stalker. Always getting into trouble, rarely getting out of it in one piece. He once lost his eye when he went to the Swamps to retrieve an artifact. Since then, he has been fitted with a prosthetic eyeball instead of an eyeball. Due to a perpetual lack of money, he accepts suicide missions from the Merchants, such as exploring abandoned communications.</text>
	</string>




	<string id="ros_freeman_name">
		<text>Phil</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ros_happy_bio">
		<text>Looter and Murderer. A bounty has been announced for his head on numerous occasions. Was once on good terms with Duty, helped them recapture their current territory. Now dwells in the wilderness and robs lone stalkers with his gang.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ros_happy_name">
		<text>Lucky</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ros_kruglov_bio">
		<text>Doctor of Biological Sciences. Outside the Zone, he studied pathogenic mutations in animals. He went to the Zone to study mutations in blind dogs.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ros_kruglov_name">
		<text>Prof. Kruglov</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ros_tiran_bio">
		<text>One of the "heroes" of the Mercenaries. A veteran shot by all calibers. A rare psycho and sadist.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ros_tiran_name">
		<text>Tyrant</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ros_volkodav_bio">
		<text>One of Freedom's field commanders. Commander of a squad of fighters who call themselves dogs. An anarchist who despises all laws except those of force.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ros_volkodav_name">
		<text>Wolfhound</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sar_monolith_bio">
		<text>Stalker of the Monolith faction. No detailed information available.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sar_monolith_cristall_bio">
		<text>Stalker of the Monolith's special unit Crystal, responsible for the safety of the Monolith itself.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sar2_arena_manager_name">
		<text>Unknown stalker</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sar2_arena_savage_name">
		<text>Beast</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sar2_bandit_leader_name">
		<text>Vasya the Boar</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sar2_bio">
		<text>Psychomaterial image.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sar2_borov_name">
		<text>Hog</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sar2_crazy_svoboda_name">
		<text>Crazy</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sar2_dolg_blokpost_leader_name">
		<text>Prapor</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sar2_dolg_guard_commander_name">
		<text>Chief of Security</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sar2_dolg_skull_name">
		<text>Skull</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sar2_dolg_zastava_commander_name">
		<text>Outpost commander</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sar2_dram_novice_name">
		<text>Yurik</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sar2_explorer_name">
		<text>Zheka Duplet</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sar2_fanat_name">
		<text>Fan</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sar2_fox_name">
		<text>Fox</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sar2_gordon_name">
		<text>Gordon</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sar2_haron_name">
		<text>Haron</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sar2_hellcar_name">
		<text>Imp</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sar2_informator_name">
		<text>Ara</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sar2_ivancov_name">
		<text>Captain Ivantsov</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sar2_krot_name">
		<text>Stalker Mole</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sar2_kruglov_name">
		<text>Prof. Kruglov</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sar2_kuznetsov_name">
		<text>Major Kuznetsov</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sar2_lucky_name">
		<text>Lucky</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sar2_petrenko_name">
		<text>Petrenko</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sar2_petruha_name">
		<text>Zhorik</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sar2_professor_name">
		<text>Prof. Sakharov</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sar2_ryaboy_name">
		<text>Ryaboy</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sar2_seryi_name">
		<text>Gray</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sar2_svoboda_blockpost_leader_name">
		<text>Cap</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sar2_svoboda_bodyguard_name">
		<text>Capez</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sar2_svoboda_cook_name">
		<text>Cook</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sar2_svoboda_engeneer_name">
		<text>Screw</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sar2_svoboda_leader_name">
		<text>Lukash</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sar2_svoboda_max_name">
		<text>Freedom Stalker</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sar2_svoboda_stukach_name">
		<text>Pavlik</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sar2_svoboda_trader_name">
		<text>Scrooge</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sar2_svoboda_ugrumyi_name">
		<text>Sullen</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sar2_tiran_name">
		<text>Tyrant</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sar2_tolik_name">
		<text>Tolik</text>
	</string>


	<string id="fobos_bio">
		<text>This formerly cheerful and cheerful stalker once had the misfortune to fall into a trap set by the religious group Sin. In captivity, he miraculously survived all the unthinkable horrible abuse, which was subjected to, but his will was finally and irrevocably broken. The brainwashing had a strange effect on his behavior: now he was a cold-blooded and brutal killer, incapable of expressing emotions. His fanatical devotion to the group's cause has made him one of the most dangerous people in the Zone.</text>
	</string>


	<string id="val_agreh_leader_bio">
		<text>An enigmatic figure who heads the underground religious group Sin, which has settled in the territory of former military warehouses. Not much is known about his past, but if we believe the stories of stalkers who miraculously survived after talking to him, this is a highly educated man who knows about the Zone almost more than the ecologists from Lake Yantar. This is a sadistic preacher, who is feared even by his "brothers". There is an opinion that he is a mutant created by the Zone itself. The only thing left in him is his body structure. For the head of the leader of Sin appointed a huge reward, but so far none of the stalkers have not been able to get to him - he is protected by his flock.</text>
	</string>


	<string id="zablikov_bio">
		<text>A longtime stalker. Before the evacuation, he lived with his family in a classified military town in the Zone. He was hired by a research institute to protect a scientific expedition of ecologists from a mobile research lab. Well oriented in the Zone, which has saved his life more than once. Very often visits the bar </text>
	</string>




	<string id="sim_bandit_general_bio">
		<text>Unknown stalker. Questionable reputation. No detailed information available.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sim_bandit_master_bio">
		<text>Unknown stalker. Questionable reputation. No detailed information available.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sim_bandit_master_fraer_bio">
		<text>Came to the Zone looking for adventure. Looks like a comic book hero from the '60s. He is called different names: Batman, Macho, Black Cloak, Banderos and, although the fact that he has been in the Zone for two years and is still alive speaks volumes, he is still not taken seriously, which hurts him a lot.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sim_bandit_master_kocherga_bio">
		<text>Ferocious, angry, rude, selfish, cruel, unfeeling, cold. No one knows when or how he got into the Zone. He is feared and disliked. In the Zone simply lives, he has no future and no past. After one of his many forays into the Zone, he lost his memory and forgot a lot of things. He can't remember where he comes from, he can't remember his real name, he often has memory lapses. For example, he can forget a new acquaintance an hour after meeting him and, having perceived him as an enemy, kill him.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sim_bandit_novice_bio">
		<text>Unknown stalker. Questionable reputation. No detailed information available.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sim_bandit_veteran_bio">
		<text>Unknown stalker. Questionable reputation. No details available.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sim_dolg_master_bio">
		<text>Guardian of the Duty faction. Unless you are their friend, you should avoid them. Details unavailable.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sim_dolg_regular_bio">
		<text>Duty Stalker. No details available.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sim_dolg_sniper_bio">
		<text>A Duty faction fighter. Usually well equipped. No detailed information available.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sim_dolg_veteran_barin_bio">
		<text>Boor, sycophant, hypocrite, coward. Barin's life credo could be called the phrase "after us there will be a flood". He tries to capitalize on everything. He's very ambitious and resentful. He came to the Zone, as banal as it may sound, for money. And for the second year in the Zone is engaged in the extraction of material values by any means.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sim_dolg_veteran_bio">
		<text>A militant of the Duty group. Usually well equipped. No detailed information is available.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sim_dolg_veteran_prapor_bio">
		<text>He's an official recruiter for the SBU. Often sits in a bar. Everyone knows about it, and also about the fact that if it gets too tight, you should go to him. However, after this step the way back to honest stalkers will be closed.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sim_ecolog_zob_bio">
		<text>In everyday life phlegmatic, does not express his emotions, calm. However, with strong impressions, he is irascible, aggressive. Intellectual. Materialist, terribly regrets that he got into the Zone. After graduating from medical school he was sent to the Zone, where the camp of scientists needed an assistant neurosurgeon. He dissects the brains of mutants and studies their psychokinetic abilities. Waiting for a pension and the opportunity to live in the capital city away from this dead place.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sim_fresh_Zombied_bio">
		<text>One of the unlucky stalkers.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sim_killer_general_bio">
		<text>An unknown mercenary. Possibly heavily armed. No detailed information available.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sim_killer_master_bio">
		<text>Unknown Mercenary. Possibly heavily armed. No detailed information available.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sim_killer_sniper_bio">
		<text>Unknown Mercenary. Possibly heavily armed. No detailed information available.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sim_killer_veteran_bio">
		<text>Unknown Mercenary. Possibly heavily armed. No detailed information available.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sim_monolith_master_bio">
		<text>Stalker of the Monolith faction. No details available.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sim_monolith_regular_bio">
		<text>Stalker of the Monolith faction. No detailed information available.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sim_monolith_sniper_bio">
		<text>Stalker of the Monolith faction. No detailed information available.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sim_monolith_specnaz_bio">
		<text>Stalker of the Monolith faction. No detailed information available.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sim_soldier_commander_bio">
		<text>No detailed information available.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sim_Soldier_master_bio">
		<text>A military stalker. Well armed and very dangerous. No detailed information available.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sim_soldier_regular_bio">
		<text>Private soldier. No detailed information available.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sim_soldier_sniper_bio">
		<text>No details available.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sim_soldier_specnaz_bio">
		<text>Army Special Forces. Well equipped. No detailed information available.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sim_stalker_general_bio">
		<text>Experienced stalker. No details available.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sim_stalker_general_upir_bio">
		<text>Incredibly lucky stalker. Many times his group was on the brink of death, and always he was the only one who managed to save himself. Stalkers have a bad reputation as an unlucky talisman. Since some time he's been walking alone.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sim_stalker_master_bio">
		<text>One of the Zone's veterans. This stalker knows the Zone like the back of his hand. Usually well equipped and very dangerous. No detailed information is available.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sim_stalker_master_chuchelo_bio">
		<text>A smuggler with a long history.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sim_stalker_master_diador_bio">
		<text>Ex-Afghan. During one of the mujahideen ambushes, he came to believe in God. After Afghanistan he immigrated to Poland, where he entered the seminary. After graduating from the seminary he preaches for some time in the Lviv Catholic Church. After the explosion at Chernobyl NPP he signed up as a volunteer to help the victims. For the last few years he has been preaching in the Zone.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sim_stalker_master_master_bio">
		<text>In the past he was a mechanic at the KholodMash plant. After his wife left him, he decided to commit suicide, and since he was a religious man, he chose the Zone as the original method of suicide. But he survived, wore himself out for a couple of years and gained a certain authority among stalkers, thanks to his professional skills. At the moment the Master is the most competent locksmith in the Zone, repair of equipment and machinery, arrangement of defense systems of group bunkers, etc. etc. etc. - his diocese. He can get into any door, is influential, simple, but rude in communication.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sim_stalker_master_polkan_bio">
		<text>Former military stalker, lieutenant colonel of the internal troops. After one of the operations in the depths of the Zone, he was left alone from the entire squad, but found evidence that they were simply set up and sent for slaughter. After that he decided not to go back, faked his own death and went to the stalkers, to deal with the problem of the Zone illegally. Silent, cynical, determined.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sim_stalker_novice_bio">
		<text>A rookie. New to the Zone. No detailed information available.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sim_stalker_novice_neumeha_bio">
		<text>Unsophisticated 20 years old. He has nothing and no one left on the Big Land, so he decided to come here. He has nowhere to leave the Zone. In the Zone simply makes ends meet. He owes a lot of stalkers some money. He goes to the Zone very often, but never alone, more often he joins groups of stalkers. But few people agree to take him, because he is just an extra burden. Loot collects very rarely. Lives on handouts from other stalkers and therefore all in debt.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sim_stalker_sniper_bio">
		<text>Stalker's a veteran. Probably well equipped. No detailed information is available.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sim_stalker_veteran_bio">
		<text>Stalker veteran. Probably well equipped. Detailed information is missing.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sim_stalker_veteran_gusarov_bio">
		<text>Oleg Demon Gusarov. Former Black Beret, served in the Belotserkovsky brigade of Spetsnaz. Senior enlisted, senior sergeant, specialty sniper and bomber. By state of mind - a lone wolf. In the Zone he never takes his partners with him, preferring to act alone. More than once he was offered to join clans, but he always refused flatly for this reason.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sim_stalker_veteran_umnik_bio">
		<text>A student from the Physics Department, he left the fifth year of the institute to go to the Zone to earn money. He liked to show off his scientific knowledge and argue on abstract philosophical topics. For this show-off he is disliked by stalkers. But in general, the guy is not bad. Still believes in high ideals.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sim_stalker_veteran_vorobey_bio">
		<text>Sparrow's 27 years old. Cunning, far-sighted, but sometimes he makes grave mistakes. Sometimes sneaky. Overall, leaves an ambivalent impression of himself. thin and pale. He came to the Zone out of curiosity and made a promise to himself - two months in the Zone and then home. But he stayed here. On his first foray into the Zone, he managed to walk without devices through a field full of anomalies without knowing about them. When he was informed about it, he could not recover for a long time. Since then he celebrates that day (October 9) as his second birthday.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sim_Svoboda_master_bio">
		<text>Master of the Freedom faction. No detailed information is available.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sim_Svoboda_regular_bio">
		<text>Stalker of the Freedom faction. No detailed information available.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sim_Svoboda_sniper_bio">
		<text>Stalker of the Freedom faction. No detailed information available.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sim_Svoboda_specnaz_bio">
		<text>Freedom Fighter. Usually well equipped. No detailed information available.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sim_Svoboda_specnaz_leshii_bio">
		<text>Leshiy, as he was nicknamed by his brother, came to the zone as a young idealist. But a few years of living on the edge of death made him a cynical realist. He considers the zone his home, and those who have not passed the test of the zone - unworthy to live on Earth.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sim_svoboda_specnaz_prut_bio">
		<text>He writes essays and stories about the Zone under the pseudonym Arkady. In the past, a journalist, meticulous, tough, but fair. Enjoys a certain respect among stalkers.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sim_zombied_master_bio">
		<text>One of the unlucky stalkers.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sim_zombied_novice_bio">
		<text>One of the unlucky stalkers.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sim_zombied_veteran_bio">
		<text>One of the unlucky stalkers.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="val_bandit_bodyguard_bio">
		<text>Bandit security guard. Questionable reputation. No detailed information available.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="val_bandit_general_bio">
		<text>A common bandit. Questionable reputation. No details available.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="val_bandit_novice_bio">
		<text>Rookie bandit. Questionable reputation. No details available.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="val_bandit_veteran_bio">
		<text>Experienced bandit. Questionable reputation. No details available.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="val_borov_bio">
		<text>Bandit leader.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="val_borov_name">
		<text>Borov</text>
	</string>
	<string id="val_dolg_common_bio">
		<text>Stalker of the Duty faction. No detailed information available.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="val_monolith_common_bio">
		<text>Stalker of the Monolith faction. No detailed information available.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="val_prisoner_bio">
		<text>Stalker faction Duty. Detailed information is not available.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="val_prisoner_name">
		<text>Sergei Shaggy</text>
	</string>
	<string id="val_pulia_bio">
		<text>Stalker of the group Duty. No detailed information available.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="val_pulia_name">
		<text>Bullet</text>
	</string>
	<string id="val_soldier_regular_bio">
		<text>Private soldier. No detailed information available.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="val_soldier_specnaz_bio">
		<text>Army Special Forces. Well equipped. No detailed information available.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="val_stalker_general_bio">
		<text>Experienced stalker. No details available.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="val_stalker_novice_bio">
		<text>Rookie. New to the Zone. No detailed information available.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="war_ucheniy_osoznanie_bio">
		<text>Representative of Project Awareness.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="war_ucheniy_osoznanie_name">
		<text>Representation. Awareness</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_ghost_name">
		<text>Ghost</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_saharov_bio">
		<text>The head of an expedition of ecologists from a mobile scientific laboratory. A world-famous scientist, once interested in natural anomalies in this part of the world, conducts research on the shore of Lake Yantar in his bunker. He is the author of a thesis on "Properties of gamma particles in fields with multidirectional gravitational acceleration". He has been known to send stalkers to their deaths to test artifact-based drugs or technologies.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_saharov_name">
		<text>Sakharov</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_semenov_bio">
		<text>A researcher in the mobile laboratory. No detailed information available.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_semenov_name">
		<text>Scientist</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_vasilyev_name">
		<text>Scientist</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zombie_name">
		<text>Zombified stalker</text>
	</string>
	<string id="actor_name">
		<text>Messer</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sim_bandit_master_fraer_name">
		<text>Fryer</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sim_bandit_master_kocherga_name">
		<text>Sapyga</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sim_dolg_veteran_barin_name">
		<text>Veteran of duty</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sim_dolg_veteran_prapor_name">
		<text>Prapor</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sim_ecolog_zob_name">
		<text>Zob</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sim_stalker_general_upir_name">
		<text>Ghoul</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sim_stalker_master_chuchelo_name">
		<text>Scarecrow</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sim_stalker_master_diador_name">
		<text>Father Diodorus</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sim_stalker_master_master_name">
		<text>Master</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sim_stalker_master_polkan_name">
		<text>Polkan</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sim_stalker_novice_neumeha_name">
		<text>Inept</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sim_stalker_veteran_gusarov_name">
		<text>Oleg Demon Gusarov</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sim_stalker_veteran_umnik_name">
		<text>Clever</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sim_stalker_veteran_vorobey_name">
		<text>Sparrow</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sim_Svoboda_specnaz_leshii_name">
		<text>Summoner</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sim_svoboda_specnaz_prut_name">
		<text>Prut</text>
	</string>
