<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1251" ?>
<string_table>

	<string id="dm_action_info_0">
		<text>I'm sorry, I don't have time to chat right now. (start here for your first session on 6/6/25 and don't forget to remove this reminder when you start)</text>
	</string>

	<string id="dm_action_info_1">
		<text>I'd rather wait for the lunch break of those handsome men in uniforms. It's no use hanging around here, I have to go to the Big Land, and they won't let me in! I'm not the only one trying to get out, but we still can't slip through.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_action_info_10">
		<text>There's something not far away that the cops in shoulder straps need. No one's ever come this way before me. Everything was cleaned up before me, cables and those were cut. And now they've found it. I couldn't even get close to the building, they saw me and shot me. I'm glad it didn't blow a hole.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_action_info_100">
		<text>I didn't hear a thing. It's the same old thing.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_action_info_11">
		<text>We're putting together a team of those who don't piss under the ground in the Zone. There's an old factory, and underneath it are all kinds of communications. They say there's a lot of stuff, there's always something to be had. Interesting, again.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_action_info_12">
		<text>Not new, old! They say this used to be the main Gunslinger base... I wonder if we can find any traces of that time, if we look hard enough.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_action_info_13">
		<text>I almost got myself in trouble an hour ago. I was here six months ago - peace and quiet, and now skinheads in their sweatpants under every bush! Wow.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_action_info_14">
		<text>You're lucky, stalker, that the bandits didn't take you in! They have a base right next door. I'd hit it if I had my way. But for now, we're just keeping watch. This is their auxiliary point - the main one is located closer to the center of the Zone.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_action_info_15">
		<text>They say there was a serious laboratory here, classified. Uh-huh. On the one hand, I wish I could find the entrance - I bet there's a lot of loot in there! On the other hand, it's kind of creepy...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_action_info_16">
		<text>Do you know that before the disaster there was a research complex in the current Dark Valley, and underground? I don't know its purpose, but I don't think it's anything good. There's all sorts of stories about it, but mostly bad. Scary, even.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_action_info_17">
		<text>Why? What do you want to hear? I'll tell you something! Dutyovtsy, of course, the police, but they know how to restore order, yes, yes! But I don't like them at all. They are the masters of everything, don't take this, don't take that out of the Zone... Not only that, they've already figured out what they can say on the Big Land and what they can't say! They say they want to destroy the Zone little by little. Well, I'm not surprised at warriors, even if they're ex-military. dreamers. Worse, they say they've got support from the very top.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_action_info_18">
		<text>This territory is now controlled by Duty, and the law here is Duty's rules. We control the borders of the Zone and cool the hotheads! Blown up people come here in trains, lovers of romance... and then die in packs on the first day.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_action_info_19">
		<text>Have you ever been to our transshipment base? It's not just ours. There's a lot of people here. The main thing is that it's a good place, free of all kinds of crap, and all the news about the Zone comes here. Almost always you can hear something useful or just talk to people about life. It's a pity that Baldy left the day before yesterday with the group - so I didn't see him this time.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_action_info_2">
		<text>Let's go to the camp, you'll hear all the rumors there. All the first-timers, rookies like you, usually come to us. Get some experience or get some rest. We've got soldiers on our side, so don't be afraid of them, but don't be too vigilant - they can shoot you, it's as easy as two fingers for them... There's a place not far from the merchant, the local reseller, where you can organize a rest.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_action_info_20">
		<text>This place is safe now, stalker, and we try to keep it that way. There's always a lot of people here! Some have settled down and don't go further than the neighborhood, and some are preparing for the next raid. It's a pity Iroquois didn't come back - he liked to teach first-timers like you the way of the truth.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_action_info_21">
		<text>Did you hear Duty announced a recruitment drive? I thought about it for a minute, and then I decided, what the hell do I need it for?! Back on the belt every other day? Discipline, that sort of thing. I've served my two tours, that's enough!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_action_info_22">
		<text>In case you haven't heard, I'm telling you! We've announced an additional recruitment. If you have more or less experience, come, you won't regret it.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_action_info_23">
		<text>I don't know anything. Go where you're going.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_action_info_24">
		<text>Fuck off, I can't talk to you!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_action_info_25">
		<text>I'm sorry, I don't want to have this conversation for nothing.</text>
	</string>



	<string id="dm_action_info_26">
		<text>They say if you get some kind of disease in the zone, you can go crazy... Some of them even settle accounts with themselves.</text>
	</string>




	<string id="dm_action_info_27">
		<text>Shit, you ever heard of diseases? Rabies? It's so bad, it's scary. If you get it, you're probably dead.</text>
	</string>



	<string id="dm_action_info_28">
		<text>At Lake Yantar, when the blowout starts, the equipment there goes into overdrive... If you get in trouble, hide in a shelter somewhere.</text>
	</string>



	<string id="dm_action_info_29">
		<text>You ever been to the swamp? They say there was some kind of massacre there. Though it's dangerous to go there. Rumor has it that the rain there is acidic, and some fumes...</text>
	</string>



	<string id="dm_action_info_3">
		<text>Shit, I'd like to go to the factory... there are rumored to be some interesting documents hidden there...</text>
	</string>



	<string id="dm_action_info_30">
		<text>I hear there's some scientists doing some research in the valley. They even recruited one of ours to guard them. It's been a while.</text>
	</string>




	<string id="dm_action_info_31">
		<text>Go away before it's night! It's still daytime, but when the sun goes down...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_action_info_32">
		<text>Stalker, get out! We're going to take down the cordon. We're only keeping it during the day, but we're leaving at night. It's too bad here at night.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_action_info_33">
		<text>You see, at night, you gotta take cover here, and preferably behind good doors. We're practically under siege at night.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_action_info_34">
		<text>Well, buddy, I see you haven't heard? At night, you gotta go to bed somewhere far away from here. A grenade launcher doesn't always work at night!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_action_info_35">
		<text>You know what? Let the Dugovtsy and the freedom fighters and the looters decide whose piece this is, and I don't give a shit. Fuck it.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_action_info_36">
		<text>We're working here now, stalker. There's enough scum out there, and now these darkies are interfering with our lives...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_action_info_37">
		<text>I have to warn you, it's not safe here during the daytime. I understand there's some kind of confrontation between local gangs.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_action_info_38">
		<text>Look, you tell me. This is all our territory, right? It's easier for us to keep the shit coming out of the center of the Zone, right? Let the eggheads go digging around, but let Duty and the looters get the hell outta here!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_action_info_39">
		<text>Don't you know? There's a new path to get past the Drog patrols to the perimeter with the loot. From Yantar here, then through the vegetable gardens to Agroprom, and that's it!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_action_info_4">
		<text>Nothing! I don't know shit! I'm just scrounging for my daily bread. I'm afraid to go to the Zone itself, to hell with it! And at home there's no work, my wife is nagging me... I have to live somehow, don't I? Here on the Garbage, if you walk around for a day, you can collect various artifacts. It's enough to eat and drink.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_action_info_40">
		<text>What are you doing here? Are you going to Yantar, or do you want to sneak artifacts past the bar?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_action_info_41">
		<text>I won't hide the fact that here your fellow stalkers from time to time offer us very interesting anomalous formations - artifacts, as you call them. These places, because of their. shall we say, the uncertainty of their control, they're something of a busy smuggling trail.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_action_info_42">
		<text>Oh, come on, man. We've paved the path so you don't have to meet Duty officials if you want to go to the Big Land! No, I mean, they've been around for a while. But as long as they don't know anything, at least we can avoid them.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_action_info_43">
		<text>I've just come from Yantar. I thought I'd push something to science, as usual, but they've locked themselves in their bunkers there, they don't even come out during the day, except for the next chopper. So, if you're going there, turn your horns up - you'll miss out...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_action_info_44">
		<text>There's some research going on in the Yantar zone, but there's been a lot of dead guys lately. So we're guarding the approaches.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_action_info_45">
		<text>I don't know what to tell you. I wanted to go back to our complex, which is Yantar, I think you know. And here we are! They say that if it was dangerous before, now it's impossible to pass through. Maybe they exaggerate?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_action_info_46">
		<text>I've been to Yantar, and the science there is completely dormant! Scared, hiding. They only live on what they get from the choppers. On the other hand, there's a lot of dead people out there. You live among them for a week, you won't be so scared. It's a nice place. It's not pretty.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_action_info_47">
		<text>Fuck the dogs, hanging out with the dead! There's more and more of them in this fucking complex. They're getting bigger and bigger.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_action_info_48">
		<text>We're trying to stop the dead from moving away from the lab complex. Honestly, I wouldn't mind if you got involved. We're a little short on manpower.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_action_info_49">
		<text>You know, we're doing our own intelligence gathering. I've been researching the main paths of quasi-lives. dead people, in your terminology. Would you care to share your observations?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_action_info_5">
		<text>It's just the way it is. Some of them are feeding on the Garbage, picking up little things, and some of them are drilling deeper into the Zone. There, of course, the pieces are much fattier, but not everyone goes there. Rookies without experience have nothing to do there, and if there is no decent equipment, it's a dead end. No chance!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_action_info_50">
		<text>Have you shot any of those dead people coming out of the lab building? Look at them! They're not afraid of anything, they don't feel pain, they have no brains at all.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_action_info_51">
		<text>I'm going to get a job at the lab! Alright, man, relax, it's just a joke of humor. Once you're in there, you're dead. Best case scenario, you're dead.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_action_info_52">
		<text>I'm warning you! Don't go in the lab. No, if you really want to go, go. I won't stop you. But you don't come back alive.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_action_info_53">
		<text>You see. I'd like to warn you. You shouldn't go to the lab. In fact, nobody should! It involves drastic changes in your psyche and metabolism - and, I'm afraid, completely irreversible.</text>
	</string>



	<string id="dm_action_info_54">
		<text>Whoa! I'm going to enlighten you. enlighten you. and save you, you lost sheep! Alright, dude. Don't ski to the center of the lake. It's fucked up there, really fucked up. People disappear, and then sometimes they come to you at night. But that ain't no vampire stories, that's dead people stories. That's the way it is.</text>
	</string>



	<string id="dm_action_info_55">
		<text>Have you seen our smart guys, that United Nations color? They've been getting scared lately. They take two steps away from the base and they've got a whole regiment with APCs and choppers to guard them.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_action_info_56">
		<text>What's it to you? Don't pester them with bad questions, then they won't pester you either.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_action_info_57">
		<text>You see, we usually don't leave our bunkers without proper security. Environmental conditions don't allow it. I'm a kind of exception - I don't really like big expeditions, all this fuss, military... But I'm afraid I can't tell you anything useful yet.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_action_info_58">
		<text>I'm in love with our funny science! I'm crazy about her, man! She doesn't usually come out of her bunker. But if she does, like she did the other day, it's like, "Oh, my God! There's a lot of troops, choppers, armored vehicles! It would be great if they brought a battleship here, or an armored train, at least...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_action_info_59">
		<text>I've been here for three days now, watching. The lab's here, right? No one's been in it since the beginning, Duty only cleaned the dead from the top, and now they've stopped even now, right? But science has started going in there. So they found a way to defend themselves, I don't know what against. So I thought I'd find out. I bet there's a lot of loot in that place.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_action_info_6">
		<text>Beasts have been coming out of the Dark Valley in packs lately. I don't know what's driving them out of there, but they're scurrying around like a fire. And in the eastern sector, the mutants are like bedbugs, we only have time to shoot them. That's the news.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_action_info_60">
		<text>What are you looking for? You're going to the lab, too? Did you hear that story about miraculous instruments and scattered artifacts? Fuck... When are you assholes gonna get a new lease on life?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_action_info_61">
		<text>I work here, young man. Just working, doing my duty to science and humanity. And if you want to know about the abandoned laboratory, in the knowledge of the secrets of which I am suspected by every stalker I meet, I'll answer... I don't know and I don't want to know! I'm not interested in this subject and never have been, do you understand?!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_action_info_62">
		<text>Maybe the scientists have invented a device, don't you know? I wonder what's hidden in that lab. Even if there's no good stuff, it's still interesting!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_action_info_63">
		<text>I'm thinking of going to Freedom? Why not? They seem to be smart people, and even if they're a little careless, it's even better! I don't need to be disciplined, I know what to do, I've been here for months...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_action_info_64">
		<text>I saw an old man in the hills. With a huge dog. What's he doing there?</text>
	</string>


	<string id="dm_action_info_65">
		<text>I'm meeting a fellow Dugovian. We're talking. He's a smart guy, but he's as narrow-minded as your tank. You see, we have a different philosophy. The zone can only be tamed, assimilated, not destroyed. That requires open access to all information. Someone will come up with something useful sooner or later. And they - close, forbid, do not disclose... They're assholes, for God's sake, assholes! On the other hand, it's understandable! When the whole state machine is behind you, you don't have to think too much.</text>
	</string>


	<string id="dm_action_info_66">
		<text>There's a hamlet here, it used to be quiet, but now some crap has broken out. It's better to make a detour, so I'm taking a detour... Look, I warned you.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_action_info_67">
		<text>You, stalker, I want to warn you right away. In the village long ago nested bloodsuckers, and maybe even worse, so be careful.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_action_info_68">
		<text>What's new? There are no artifacts here for a long time, and those houses over there used to be inhabited by bloodsuckers, and we shot them off as best we could. Now I'm here, and I can't get to the place. Intuition or something, but I can't go there, that's all. I can't. It's dead out there.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_action_info_69">
		<text>I'm getting the hell out of here. I've done four weeks at the barrier, and that's it. I'm done. Woodpecker's coming in 24/7, and it's getting more and more aggressive every day.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_action_info_7">
		<text>A lot of people are becoming garbage men now. Before, they didn't look in the piles at all - radiation so strong it'd boil your balls in half an hour. But now, when the loot is tight, they wrap themselves in protection, take chemistries, and nothing, they look for it. There's a lot of stuff there, though it's mostly small stuff.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_action_info_70">
		<text>If you're coming with us, I respect you. If not, get out of sight! We need real men, not assholes. We got enough of our own.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_action_info_71">
		<text>You're on the roadblock, man? It's good, at least one more normal person will show up. We organized this thing and kept it going pretty good. but then the beasts came in! It's hard now, so we need every gun we can get!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_action_info_72">
		<text>Keep your eyes open, kid. There's radiation and fanatics. Now let's go about our business.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_action_info_73">
		<text>You should have waited, stalker. You wouldn't run after everybody! Tell me something. Do you know what's in there? That's right, you don't. You don't know if there's something to eat or not. You don't know what the traps are, either. So why are you guys rushing around like a herd of elk?!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_action_info_74">
		<text>The way to the center is clear, understand?! Now we're going straight to the center. Now everyone's going to come in in droves. The main thing is to be among the first, to squeeze out the most juice...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_action_info_75">
		<text>Go ahead, you'll see for yourself! You don't want to see for yourself what's going on down there? Well, then, you're just... There must be so much there! You've heard of Wishful Thinking, haven't you?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_action_info_76">
		<text>They're like children, for God's sake! Wish granter, Klondike of artifacts.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_action_info_77">
		<text>I want to see what's over the horizon, man. Maybe we can find an explanation for all this bullshit they call the Zone in one fell swoop.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_action_info_78">
		<text>Have you seen the high-rises? That's Pripyat. Right behind it is the power plant. I wish I could go there. But we don't know what's out there in those buildings right now.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_action_info_79">
		<text>I'm explaining! There's Pripyat. Beyond Pripyat is Chernobyl. We don't know what's going on there and who's living there. This is where we belong. We'll find something to clean up, as always!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_action_info_8">
		<text>I don't know! I'm on my way to the bar to meet some people. You've never been there before? Oh, come on! That's it! As you stand, you're going straight north. Before you can take two steps, there'll be a bar right there. It's a good place to go, and for newbies like you, it's a doctor's appointment. Experienced guys hang out there, they'll tell you what to do. The only thing is that our guys from Duty will meet you on the way... Well, whether they like you or not, it's up to them.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_action_info_80">
		<text>Pripyat! Shit, pinch me! Finally! It's just a short walk to the power plant. I don't know who you'll meet here now, what kind of animal is sharpening its teeth at you!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_action_info_81">
		<text>Hey, buddy, listen. Is that voice in your head too, or am I the only one who's crazy? It just keeps on talking and talking.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_action_info_82">
		<text>Shit, another one. Alright! For the tenth time, I'm explaining the kind of telepathic influence people are subjected to here. Unheard from the outside voices constantly call them to the center of the Zone and promise to fulfill any wish of the one who manages to touch... as it... yes - some kind of Monolith!</text>
	</string>

	<string id="dm_action_info_83">
		<text>Can you hear the voice? It's cool, it's like a record player in your head! Too bad it's the same track. Come to me and you'll be happy. He's been saying the same thing for two hours...</text>
	</string>

	<string id="dm_action_info_84">
		<text>Can't you guess? You're trying to get to the power plant yourself! So are we, what other news?! If only we could get those possessed assholes out of the way...</text>
	</string>


	<string id="dm_action_info_85">
		<text>The power plant area is right next door. what else does that tell you?</text>
	</string>


	<string id="dm_action_info_86">
		<text>There it is, ChNPP, just a stone's throw away... It's all we have left, but these bitches are stubborn, they won't let us in! It's alright, we'll cover them.</text>
	</string>


	<string id="dm_action_info_9">
		<text>Listen, friend! You don't know about the Agroprom yourself? I wanted to go there, and people laughed at me. No, they say it's gone to shit, it's been stripped clean back then, only anomalies left. Do you know if they're telling the truth or just for laughs? I'm new here, I believe it if the locals say it's true. Maybe they're joking. They're just having a laugh, those pests!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_action_info_94">
		<text>Wait! Hurry up, but don't be in a hurry! There's Monolithians around here. They know the city from top to bottom, they've set up ambushes. Be careful!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_action_info_95">
		<text>I'm warning you! So far, most of the city is controlled by the Monolith faction. A lot of ambushes, they know the place like the back of their hand. Keep your eyes open and check your weapons.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_action_info_96">
		<text>What I'd love to do is carpet bomb this town. Bastards. Unless they're in sandboxes and flowerpots. People have already died because of these assholes!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_action_info_97">
		<text>Look, I don't know what the hell this Monolith is. Maybe it's not eternal, so there won't be enough for everyone? What are we supposed to do, stand on four points? If we get there, you'll be behind me, I promise...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_action_info_98">
		<text>Duty must break through to the center, if not first, then among the first! Just imagine, stalker, that some psycho - and you're all almost so-and-so, schizo, paranoid and oligophrenic - gets to the shit that really can fulfill any wish. Ah? Then what?!</text>
	</string>

	<string id="dm_action_info_99">
		<text>I don't feel like talking.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="dm_action_info_101">
		<text>Oh, nothing much. I'm just trying to survive and make a living.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_action_info_102">
		<text>I'm gaining experience, saving up my finances. When I get the money, I'll buy a better gun and armor, and then I'll rush to the center of the Zone...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_action_info_103">
		<text>The Zone fascinated me! I came here by accident, like on an illegal excursion... and, you know, I was hooked. The people here are real, both enemies and friends. And this danger, the feeling of near death - it makes you feel alive and enjoy every minute of this life.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_action_info_104">
		<text>I'm resting after the last raid. I went almost all the way to the Barrier - we organized a defense against all sorts of evil that comes from the center. Good guys gathered together. Sanya Shaggy, Lyokha Koresh, Maldi - all guys are kind-hearted. And I got some good loot too. I sold it to the dealer and decided to take a little break here. It's easier here than in the big Zone.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_action_info_105">
		<text>You ask me that?! It's because of assholes like you that we have to stay here. What do you find in this Zone? No, they come in droves, they die and still come! And you ask me what I'm doing here?! I should be asking you what you're doing here. Okay, I don't have time to talk. Get outta here!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_action_info_106">
		<text>Military secrets!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_action_info_107">
		<text>It's nothing, really. It's nothing.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_action_info_108">
		<text>I'm just admiring the beauty of this place. It's not like the outside world. I think, you know, you may not agree with me, but people just can not or do not want to find a common language with nature and their actions hurt her, and she as much as she can, gives them a signal, which they stubbornly ignore. Uh-huh.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_action_info_109">
		<text>It's none of your business!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_action_info_110">
		<text>Never mind...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_action_info_111">
		<text>What business is it of yours?!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_action_info_112">
		<text>Ever since I was a kid, I've loved going to undiscovered places. When I heard about this place, I came here immediately. This is the most unusual place I've ever seen!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_action_info_113">
		<text>I'm doing my duty to mankind! And that's not just a lofty word, that's the way it is. Saving them from what? The Zone and its spawn. We must destroy this breeding ground of evil and contagion before it destroys us!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_action_info_114">
		<text>I've recently joined Duty, I can't get enough of it. The guys here are real! And discipline at the height - always know what to do and who commands.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_action_info_115">
		<text>I have a lot of friends here in Duty. So I joined. It took me a few months to make up my mind. And now I remember my worries and think - what a fool I was! It's great here and much safer than wandering around the Zone by myself.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_action_info_116">
		<text>Well, in the Zone is not much to do, really. To search for loot, to fight, to explore the secrets of the Zone, and then to ensure that everyone has equal access to these secrets. That's what I have to do all the time.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_action_info_117">
		<text>Dude, I'm protecting the Zone from government forces. We can't let them take it over! Otherwise, it's gonna get so bad, we're all gonna die!</text>
	</string>




	<string id="dm_cool_info_0">
		<text>You don't want to go to the Garbage, there's a lot of wildlife out there. It's like some kind of crossroads in the zone. You could meet anything.</text>
	</string>






	<string id="dm_cool_info_1">
		<text>There are rumors that various special services are recruiting stalkers for their service. Most likely every second one works for someone from the world intelligence agencies.</text>
	</string>



	<string id="dm_cool_info_10">
		<text>They say that artifacts contain the power of anomalies, and some of them can generate anomalies themselves, but after that they are no longer good for anything, and the anomalies are weak and short-lived.</text>
	</string>



	<string id="dm_cool_info_100">
		<text>I haven't heard anything like that, sorry.</text>
	</string>



	<string id="dm_cool_info_11">
		<text>Saw a guy hanging around the bar, though. He was gray, like he was moldy. That's weird.</text>
	</string>



	<string id="dm_cool_info_12">
		<text>A mosquito mold is an anomaly, like a meat grinder, that happens between similar objects. Trees, for example. If you walk between them, you'll be stretched out. Half to each tree...</text>
	</string>




	<string id="dm_cool_info_13">
		<text>There are places in the Zone, there may be a new type of anomalies, which in a matter of seconds change any creature that falls into them. And there are almost no lethal mutations there. Sometimes, if a person gets there, he can even retain the remnants of reason, not for long, though. That's how rumors of mutants never seen before appear. And they usually don't live long, until the first armed stalker.</text>
	</string>



	<string id="dm_cool_info_14">
		<text>You heard of the Killers? They don't so much hunt artifacts as they do stalkers. And then they fulfill their orders.</text>
	</string>



	<string id="dm_cool_info_15">
		<text>If you're also talking about what you've been pissing me off about for the last two days, I'm telling you to go to hell! If I knew and it wasn't forbidden, I'd tell you! But I don't know, I don't know shit! What did those scientists find out? Where did our bosses go? What's it got to do with me? He's on vacation, and he doesn't have to report to us!</text>
	</string>




	<string id="dm_cool_info_16">
		<text>There's such a thing as induced fields. It's when the anomalies aren't exactly where the instruments show them. They say it's some kind of special cure. That's why in the depths of the Zone stalkers rely on their senses and vision more than on devices.</text>
	</string>




	<string id="dm_cool_info_17">
		<text>They say that some mutants can not only subdue, but also cause hallucinations. So you start shooting at everyone in sight. Or you're walking down a smooth road and you fall off a cliff.</text>
	</string>





	<string id="dm_cool_info_18">
		<text>Legend. A small group whose stalkers have learned to communicate with monsters. They rarely appear outside the Zone, their base is in the heart of the Zone, and they have untold treasures, as they have monsters helping them search for artifacts. It is said that Duty knows about this and is hunting them, but their official policy is to say that these are fairy tales.</text>
	</string>






	<string id="dm_cool_info_19">
		<text>They say that military stalkers have a monster detector and can see any critter within 200 meters. That's why they walk around the Zone so safely.</text>
	</string>






	<string id="dm_cool_info_2">
		<text>I don't know if you've heard or not. There's a group of military stalkers called Intercept. It's an elite special unit that operates deep enough in the Zone. They have several locations, a set of hideouts, and occasionally get supplies and equipment delivered by helicopter. The group is led by Major Gromov, nicknamed Grom. Their goals and objectives are unknown, marked by great freedom of action, flexibility of policy. Sometimes they cooperate with stalkers, but more often they fight. The goals and objectives of the "Intercept" group are unknown.</text>
	</string>





	<string id="dm_cool_info_20">
		<text>In the Zone noticed a large expedition, according to the official version of environmentalists from the UN. In practice, the U.S. military and scientific group. The goals may be different. It is characteristic that they did not take with them a single guide. Either they have their own channels for obtaining information about the Zone, or their assignment is so secret that even the temporary presence of outsiders in a secondary role is inadmissible.</text>
	</string>




	<string id="dm_cool_info_21">
		<text>They say there is a group of stalkers who are sometimes called shamans, sometimes druids. They never carry electronic equipment, as if they want to be closer to nature. They say that electronics, or rather on its radiation, the Zone reacts more strongly and pushes anomalies and mutants onto you. As if the Zone - a living organism and that it should not be interfered with devices, they say that man is well equipped by nature and can safely be in the Zone without any unnecessary equipment. True, they carry automatic rifles with them, assholes. Would not have teeth and claws to tear up the enemies if they are so tough. Although, as far as I know, they do not die in the Zone as much as expected. So maybe they're right. But I personally have not met any of these druids. They seem to go to the Zone more from the Belarus side.</text>
	</string>





	<string id="dm_cool_info_22">
		<text>It's a strange day today. Global bad luck is magically replaced by incredible good luck. It's a strange place I've come across. Weird.
...It all started yesterday, when out of the bushes and foggy evening gloom the silhouette of a large wooden house with a sagging roof in several places appeared in front of me. It looked like it used to be a village school and then some kind of hospital. It looked like a dead dragon. And where there's a dragon, there's gold," a misplaced thought popped into my head. Cheering myself up thus, I went in through the sprawling, rotten door. The dining room. Another unfamiliar odor pierced among the usual pile of rottenness and desolation. I redouble my caution, carefully inspecting every corner. 
And I fall. I fall very unpleasantly, on my sore leg. A couple minutes later, I come to my senses. As it happens, I've fallen into the basement. But. How could I not have noticed a hole two meters by one and a half meters in the floor? Fantastic bad luck. It's time to get out, though my leg hurts like hell, and I hit my head pretty hard. I managed to get to the ladder to the top. I crawl up and I can't believe it! At the top of the stairs, there's a KPPU! A universal first aid kit! Only military and special forces are equipped with such complexes. Finding such a thing in the Zone is like finding a thirsty source in the desert. I'm falling in. A few injections and it's almost fine: fatigue and bad mood have disappeared, and I can use my leg almost freely. In general, we can live. Let's move on.
Second floor. I step carefully: the steps and the wooden floor can hardly hold me. Out of the corner of my eye I notice a glint at the end of the corridor. I approach slowly. A door. What could be shining here? I don't see anything. I try to open the door: it yields, but with difficulty. I push harder. It moves a little more, like it's being held by a powerful spring. I slung my automatic behind my back and put my whole body on it. The door felt like lead, I only moved it a couple of centimeters! What the hell is this? I put my feet on the jamb and pressed as hard as I could. It's yielding, bitch! It's like someone let go of the door and I hit the floor. I lay there, cursing the door, resting. I just tried to get up, and it slammed! I flew two meters to the opposite wall of the corridor. That's it, I've had enough! I put a line into the door: splinters flew, slanting and dusty rays of sunlight broke through the holes. I even admired it, even though my rage was off the scale. I kicked open the door, and fell into the room, a former classroom now filled with broken beds. I look around. There's a body lying in the aisle between the beds. A military stalker. Ex. A long time ago, already well rotted. I was a bit stunned to see such a thing. The soldier was fully equipped (I had already calculated the value of all this stuff). There were a couple of questions. Not even a couple, but three. How did he end up here alone? Why had he left the first aid kit downstairs? And finally, the main one. Who killed you, you sick bastard?

Weird day today. Global bad luck magically turns into incredible good luck. Very strange. But you gotta take it while it's good. And run while it's still quiet. I bend over the corpse. His eyes are open, it's like he's looking at me. No, he's looking at me! Quietly turns his head in my direction. I hit him with the butt of my gun. The machine gun flies through the body as if it doesn't exist and crashes to the floor with all its might. I lose my balance and fall on my side. What's going on? The wreckage of the beds stirred and began to shift. I'm going to get hit! What the hell...

... It burst like a liquid balloon. Filled the whole room with his juice. So funny in its will to live - it scratches at the rusty bars that pierced it, wheezes something. Well, the day wasn't wasted - it was amusing to watch this miserable lump of flesh come here for its own filthy greed. Well, what he came with, he died with. It's a kind of justice, too.
</text>
	</string>







	<string id="dm_cool_info_23">
		<text>The Zone attracts people like a giant magnet. Or like a pile of shit - flies, or whatever you like.</text>
	</string>






	<string id="dm_cool_info_24">
		<text>Some say the Zone is alive and even intelligent. Someone - that the Zone is the spawn of the sins of Mankind and hell on Earth. Somebody starts talking nonsense about alien experiments. I don't know.</text>
	</string>




	<string id="dm_cool_info_25">
		<text>In my opinion, the Zone is neither alive, much less intelligent. It's a place with its own laws, that's all. An alternate biosphere. And it's just like in nature: If you break the law, you die. Just like that, without emotion. And all these miracles, higher minds, universal conspiracies - well, people need to believe in something. And it is not for me to dissuade them, especially since they are my best clients.</text>
	</string>





	<string id="dm_cool_info_26">
		<text>Some come here out of curiosity, some for exoticism, but most come for money. And I'm one of them. Usually, the first and second ones leave here, and very quickly. The third - according to circumstances.</text>
	</string>






	<string id="dm_cool_info_27">
		<text>I can't understand why many and many people consider the Zone a scary place? I totally disagree. It's like a return to nature. First man corrupted nature, took its wealth, violated its laws. And now nature is taking its course. Rips up man's creations, accumulates new wealth and changes the laws. There is no place on Earth more interesting! And more beautiful.</text>
	</string>




	<string id="dm_cool_info_28">
		<text>Nowadays, everyone is his own craftsman. So they do what they want.
What was it like in the old days? Experts were respected, people came for advice. And there were more of us
more of us. And now what? It's just me and Semyon the gunsmith and a bunch of small cops, 
who, to be honest, don't have a clue. They're putting optics on a gun. What an idea.
I remember when there used to be more unique weapons. Not the kind that could twist seven barrels into one, but guns with a deeper meaning.
I'm sure you've heard the stories about the self-defeating shotgun. Well, I've held this shooting complex myself.
 First of all, it's not a shotgun. It's an FN2000-based rifle system. But the only things left from the base are the trigger mechanism (and that has been remodeled), the barrel, and the grenade launcher. The case, electronics, optics - everything was redesigned. The essence of these modifications... Roughly speaking, the Optical Targeting System was taken, the one that our soldiers can't bring to their senses lately. And refined it. How Micah managed to cram it into such a compact case, and with good protection against interference - I can't imagine. He was such a master. And the main thing. On the basis of this compact OSC (control element), he built in an automatic firing system. That's so simple and ingenious! You set the firing mode, point it at the target, it automatically opens fire. He called it a self-timer. When we tested it, I was amazed. Target engagement is almost one hundred percent, no malfunctioning of the sight when pulling the trigger, not to mention saving ammunition! Just aim carefully and don't forget to reload in time. Yes, and in the disconnected state, the complex works with ordinary optics, no inconvenience.
Micah gave it to Black. Black wasn't the last master either, even though he was a stalker. Half a year ago, he died in the Zone. Eternal memory. So the Zone got his self-breaker. That's where we should look. And to make a second one. Think about it. Militaries put such EWS on helicopters, and even then, without a hundred percent guarantee of triggering. No, it won't work. If we could find the prototype itself, and dig in properly... 
Uh-huh.</text>
	</string>



	<string id="dm_cool_info_29">
		<text>There was a fool here - he was relaxing on his heel until his controller took him to the Zone.
Remember dukhman... Shorah there or a strange movement - you do not care. Calmly drop the horn on the firing sector, hit the bushes and trees. Switch to continuous.  This ain't no training school! They'll eat you up before you can fart!  
So you shoot the Horn and fall behind cover on your back. If the controller can see you, he has to focus on the victim. While you're sunbathing on your back, you flip the mate and put the Kalash on short bursts. You pop a round, count to three, and jerk... get the hell outta here! 
Suck it up?! You suckers. If you're like me, you'll live to see the end of your life. before you're discharged.</text>
	</string>





	<string id="dm_cool_info_3">
		<text>Have you heard anything about the Saint? They say he comes out of his hideout at night, somewhere on Radar, and wanders around Bar... you know?</text>
	</string>




	<string id="dm_cool_info_30">
		<text>You ever seen a kid's footprints here in the zone? Fresh ones! Sometimes you can get a little freaked out by what goes on here.</text>
	</string>




	<string id="dm_cool_info_31">
		<text>Scientists are sniffing around. I don't know what secret they've dug up, but the military's got their tails in a twist. They're already poking around Agroprom and Dark Valley, searching and searching...</text>
	</string>



	<string id="dm_cool_info_32">
		<text>There's more and more shit coming out of the city every day, and Duty and Freedom are going on another raid. How long can we hold this barrier alone?</text>
	</string>




	<string id="dm_cool_info_33">
		<text>The mutants are trying harder and harder to get past the barrier. It's been tough lately! If some of them would stop being so stupid, we'd take them down easy!</text>
	</string>




	<string id="dm_cool_info_34">
		<text>Anecdote. Stalker decided not to drink vodka anymore. Walked around the Zone, walked, tired, sat down on a stump to rest.
Okay - just get the bottle, I will not open it, just look at it.
Alright, alright, I'll open the bottle, but I won't pour it into the glass.
No, I'll pour it, I'll pour it into the glass, but I won't drink it, I definitely won't.
I'll just put the vodka in my mouth, but I won't swallow it, I'll just hold it in my mouth. That's all.
No, you can't do that, you have to take a sip. Just one sip.
I took a sip. Pour more, take a sip. Another...
I didn't want to drink, but I did! Quit drinking here, damn Controllers!!!! Stalker was upset...
</text>
	</string>





	<string id="dm_cool_info_35">
		<text>An anecdote remembered. Comes experienced Stalker to the young:
-Hi, let's go to the Zone, the monsters hunt monsters, from anomalies to turn away from anomalies, artifact search!
-Yeah, I don't know how to do it yet...
-What is there to know - pour and drink!!! - shared his experience Stalker...
</text>
	</string>




	<string id="dm_cool_info_36">
		<text>If you want to earn money - at the entrance to the bar, or at the scientists' bunker on Yantar there are bulletin boards, there are all sorts of ads about work. You can make a lot of money if you put your mind to it...</text>
	</string>




	<string id="dm_cool_info_37">
		<text>There was a fool here, relaxing on his heel until his controller took him to the Zone.
Remember, Dukhmans... You don't care if there's a shock or a strange movement. Calmly drop the horn on the firing sector, hit the bushes and trees. Switch to continuous.  This ain't no training school! They'll eat you up before you can fart!  
So you shoot the Horn and fall behind cover on your back. If the controller can see you, he has to focus on the victim. While you're sunbathing on your back, you flip the mate and put the Kalash on short bursts. You pop a round, count to three, and jerk... get the hell outta here! 
Suck it up?! You suckers. If you're like me, you'll live to see your demob.
</text>
	</string>




	<string id="dm_cool_info_38">
		<text>What's the news? We're sitting here, the beasts come at us, we shoot them off, and then they come again, only even stronger. There's been a few military choppers around. and it looks like they even flew over the Woodpecker.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_cool_info_39">
		<text>What's new here? same old, same old. Mutants, anomalies. Although, the military's been flying around in choppers. So at least once on the beast - no, nothing...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_cool_info_4">
		<text>New. What do they say? You can't believe it all, you won't have enough faith. Here, they say, some experienced stalker came from the inner regions, brought something unprecedented, made a lot of money... I can think of a hundred stories like that myself!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_cool_info_40">
		<text>I've seen military choppers! Imagine, they passed over us, and behind Woodpecker - one! Well, I think they'll get hit now! No shit, they went on, circled there, and went back the same way. That's a normal move, huh?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_cool_info_41">
		<text>Eh, the center of the zone is very close... There must be a lot of riches lying around out there.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_cool_info_42">
		<text>Now, as it became possible to pass relatively quietly to the center of the Zone, the stalkers flew there like flies to honey! Yeah. Greed is not the best human quality after all.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_cool_info_43">
		<text>What a life we're living! By the time all those from the bar and the perimeter get here, we'll have the cream of the crop. We'll pick up the good stuff and let the others do the small stuff.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_cool_info_44">
		<text>They say it really exists, the Black Monolith. Somebody's already gotten to it and made a big wish for it.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_cool_info_45">
		<text>Listen, buddy! I know things happen in the Zone. I've seen it. But these stories about instant monolithians are bullshit and nothing more!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_cool_info_46">
		<text>Don't you know that? Two of our guys, the ones who were the first to get to the center, made it to the monolith and made a wish. They dreamed of islands in the warm sea all their lives, so now they're sunbathing somewhere in the tropics, no other way!</text>
	</string>


	<string id="dm_cool_info_47">
		<text>I go to the peddler, and he says: until you pay off your debt, I'll keep your AK.
Fucking asshole! How can I work off my debt without a gun? Am I going into the zone with a bare ass? But I took a couple of TT's, some smokes, food for a week and went. Last raid, a guy showed me where an abandoned research institute was, but he scared me so much that I shouldn't go there. But if it's a research institute, there must be a lot of stuff there, right? So I went.
... to the site. The woods come right up to the fence, very convenient. I cross over, and beyond the fence, the yard is strangely clean. I cautiously approach the door, turn the knob...
... Damn stairs! What idiot designed this research institute? Nothing but stairs, corridors, passages. A couple more flights of stairs and I'll die. Good thing I thought to bring a kapron cord, I've already unwound 300 meters. What the hell is that door? Ugh, I'm on the roof! Well, what's that lying there? (Here the guy stopped talking, swallowed convulsively. I asked again: "Well, what was lying there?")
- An AK with a double horn. I remember I was terribly happy, even jumping for joy that I wouldn't have to pay back my debt. 
- And was it only an AK?
- No, not only.
...I saw a package lying nearby. Something big wrapped in roofing felt. I started to unwrap it, stupid me, and as soon as I unwrapped it, it turned me inside out! I wondered why there was such a sweet-smelling smell here. It was a corpse! Not even a corpse, but a real dismemberment. The body was almost cut into pieces, the skull was cut open... I got off the roof quickly, yanked back up the ladders, thanks to the cord, I ran to the door to the yard... And there's no door! That is, I can see it, but I feel the wall with my hand! Then I remembered, thank God, that at first the door seemed to be in another place, I started to fumble around, OPAH! There it is, the door! I find the handle, I open it... And there is not a courtyard, but a sea of some toothy tentacles swaying, the closest ones are also reaching out to me. It's disgusting! If I hadn't drained the starch on the roof, I'd have died here for sure. And then, like an epiphany! I looked closely at these tentacles - something's wrong. There's no shadow! The sun is hot, but there's no shadow! I realized it was a trick, an optical illusion. I gathered my courage, I thought I was going to die, so I rushed outside. But I didn't see the threshold because of my tentacles, I got caught. And the yard was covered with asphalt. Anyway, the result is on my face. I was still running through the woods, I almost fell into a mosquito's head, but I got out...
That's the story. Maybe the guy's lying. He was drunk as a pig, and he wanted to get to know the road. I checked it out, though. He did owe the dealer, and after that story, he got loose.
</text>
	</string>




	<string id="dm_cool_info_48">
		<text>One of Sin's squads was found in a previously inaccessible area. How did they manage to get through unscathed and then survive here for weeks? It just doesn't make any sense! Looks like we underestimated these guys.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_cool_info_49">
		<text>Hey, we found our Miklouha! Alive, and the guys he was with survived, too. We got past Woodpecker, and then we were here for a month, couldn't get out.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_cool_info_5">
		<text>There's something fishy brewing here. Rumors are going around that the Duty commander, a big shot, not just on some business from the Zone, but with the freedom fighters to negotiate. Well, they would have made peace in the open, but they've made a mess of things! This case smells bad, that's how it is. On the other hand, old men say they started fighting for a bad reason. I don't think they'll drag us all into some new meat grinder, those office freaks from the Big Land...!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_cool_info_50">
		<text>Did you hear that? The military's on a roll, they'll be here in a minute! They found out that Woodpecker's dead, they want to grab all the stuff at once!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_cool_info_51">
		<text>They just got word! The army is planning a large-scale landing on the power plant. My advice! If you want to grab some of the loot, hurry up!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_cool_info_52">
		<text>It's a total mess! Just when the corridor opened, the power plant started to be cleaned of all kinds of shit, and now the military are here! You have no shame, no conscience!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_cool_info_53">
		<text>What I don't understand is this. How could the freedom fighters hold out here for a month? Did they wear invisible hats? It's a hell of a place.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_cool_info_54">
		<text>Do you understand what's going on here? No, I respect Miklouha even more now. What's up with that? Four weeks and more to endure, and not to lose any of the guys!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_cool_info_55">
		<text>Some of us have lost our minds. They were always tough guys, but now they're drooling. It's scary!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_cool_info_56">
		<text>As we get closer to the power plant, the unknown telepathic influence intensifies. Some are starting to go crazy, others are having disturbances and visions. Maybe now would be a good time to back up a bit.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_cool_info_57">
		<text>Look, people are really freaking out here. Someone sees a pebble and suddenly starts yelling that it's his fucking artifact, that he was the first one to see it, and the rest of us can go south. Another Jar on a cloud shows up with his partners, who disappeared a few years ago... No, there's something sick going on here!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_cool_info_6">
		<text>The military's doing something. Searching, digging. Before, only choppers flew to Yantar - to protect scientists, supplies and equipment. But now there's an invasion! They've started organizing raids, riding on APCs. We've already seen them on Agroprom, in the Dark Valley, again. I don't know.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_cool_info_7">
		<text>Somebody tried to get through Woodpecker again. Well, that's the end of it, of course, and that's the end of the man. You ain't heard of Woodpecker? Oh, come on, man! It's the biggest hell in the whole neighborhood! The only trouble is, the horror stories about it are mostly true.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_cool_info_8">
		<text>Besides bandits, the military has started to come here too. Before, once in a hundred years you'd see a helicopter, but now they're almost all over the Zone. Did they lose something or something?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_cool_info_9">
		<text>I want to warn you, stalker. The military has gone crazy around here lately! They used to guard the scientists quietly and peacefully, but now it's as if someone has tipped their tails! They're running around. Your brother's been shelled more than once, and we've had two wounded this week.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_help_thanks_1">
		<text>Thank you very much.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_intro_0">
		<text>Don't bully the soldiers, you'll get a bullet in no time. And any of our guys who are around here might get hurt.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_intro_1">
		<text>I see you don't know your way around here yet, so I'm warning you in a neighborly way! Don't mess with the military. If you see them, get the hell out of here, because they've got no brains. They'll shoot you first, and then they'll look at your papers.</text>
	</string>



	<string id="dm_intro_10">
		<text>Dutyers run this place. Keep it in mind, so you don't get in trouble.</text>
	</string>




	<string id="dm_intro_100">
		<text>Good day, stalker. What do you want?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_intro_101">
		<text>Good day.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_intro_102">
		<text>Good day!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_intro_103">
		<text>Hey, man.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_intro_104">
		<text>Hi.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_intro_105">
		<text>Oh, hello!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_intro_106">
		<text>Hello.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_intro_107">
		<text>Greetings!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_intro_108">
		<text>Hello, stalker.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_intro_109">
		<text>Greetings, stalker.</text>
	</string>


	<string id="dm_intro_11">
		<text>You are in an area where order is maintained by members of the Duty group. Any request of the patrol must be obeyed without question.</text>
	</string>


	<string id="dm_intro_110">
		<text>Hey, you, stalker!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_intro_111">
		<text>Hello.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_intro_112">
		<text>Wow! What a bunch of people!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_intro_113">
		<text>And who do we have here?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_intro_114">
		<text>What more do you want?</text>
	</string>


	<string id="dm_intro_12">
		<text>I wonder where in the zone so many zombies come from? One said they crawled out of secret labs after the crash and now they're hanging around. I even come here to the bar sometimes.</text>
	</string>


	<string id="dm_intro_13">
		<text>First time here? Then I suggest you go to the bar. Your coworkers there will give you all the latest news.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_intro_14">
		<text>Don't go near the center of the lake... there's a bunch of zombies. They'll eat more.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_intro_15">
		<text>I don't recommend going anywhere near the center of the lake... There's a lot of dead people out there!</text>
	</string>



	<string id="dm_intro_16">
		<text>You know where all the zombies in the zone come from? They say that after the explosion, they came out of all the labs. experimenting on them.</text>
	</string>



	<string id="dm_intro_17">
		<text>Don't go to the center of the lake, man, you're gonna end up dead.</text>
	</string>




	<string id="dm_intro_18">
		<text>You keep in mind, Radar's already around here. Don't you dare go north!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_intro_19">
		<text>You don't want to lose your brains, don't go north from here!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_intro_2">
		<text>Watch out for the bridge, okay? There's a lot of stray dogs out there. If you flap your ears, they'll eat you in two seconds!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_intro_20">
		<text>You take care of yourself as a person! It's two steps to Radar. If you go north, whoops, and you're ready for another asshole!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_intro_21">
		<text>It's like walking through a minefield, only worse! There's a hell of a lot going on here at times, you can't relax for a second!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_intro_22">
		<text>I advise you to increase your attention, and once you've increased it, don't relax. If you relax, you're gone, you're dead!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_intro_23">
		<text>You've got to keep your ears open at all times! Sleep half-eyed! Shit can happen at any time!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_intro_24">
		<text>Watch out for scumbags! It's like a cockroach infestation.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_intro_25">
		<text>Destroy the so-called Monolithians as soon as you see them! Very dangerous - real fanatics!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_intro_26">
		<text>There are some assholes here who call themselves Monolithians... They're not afraid of pain. If you run out of ammunition, they'll throw themselves at you and try to chew your throat off. In general, if you see it, shoot immediately, don't hesitate!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_intro_3">
		<text>Listen up! You see a tunnel, don't go in it. I'm telling you right away, because not everyone is smart enough to stay out of the ass. They won't even take you out of there, you'll be in pieces on the walls. This is the Zone, okay?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_intro_4">
		<text>Hey, hobo. I'll give you some free advice - you'd better not go behind the factory - bandits have been seen there. Rumor has it they're coming here from the cordon, through the gate.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_intro_5">
		<text>Why do you walk alone? This place is full of skinheads, they can catch you at any time! Lately they've become quite brazen, even attacking roadblocks, I hear.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_intro_6">
		<text>Be warned if you're not in the know! There's been a lot of gang activity around here lately. It's the second shooting with them in a week. Be careful, keep your eyes open, they've already sent six loners to the afterlife.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_intro_7">
		<text>You didn't happen to hear what the military suddenly needed in the research building, did you? What are they doing out there today?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_intro_8">
		<text>You pay attention here! There's a bunch of thugs in the main building. They have no conscience or pity, I'd strangle them all!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_intro_9">
		<text>You don't want to go into the Dark Valley alone. The killers are nesting in one of the buildings. We're still trying to smoke them out. Don't get hurt, boy!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_intro_help_1">
		<text>Brother, help!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_intro_help_10">
		<text>Help me, somebody!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_intro_help_11">
		<text>Guards, I'm hit! Come here!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_intro_help_12">
		<text>Help! I'm dying!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_intro_help_2">
		<text>Guys, first aid kit!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_intro_help_3">
		<text>Get the first aid kit in here!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_intro_help_4">
		<text>Shock control, boys! Hurry up!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_intro_help_5">
		<text>First aid kit, men!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_intro_help_6">
		<text>Somebody! Give me the first aid kit!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_intro_help_7">
		<text>Buddy, first aid kit... first aid kit!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_intro_help_8">
		<text>Help, man!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_intro_help_9">
		<text>Share your first aid kit, buddy, huh?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_intro_help_13">
		<text>Hey, man, can I borrow your first aid kit?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_intro_help_14">
		<text>Man, you got a first aid kit?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_intro_help_15">
		<text>Bro, you got a first aid kit?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_intro_help_16">
		<text>Man, help me out!</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="list_trader_repair_0">
		<text>The cost of repairing weapons in the first slot:</text>
	</string>
	<string id="list_trader_repair_1">
		<text>The cost of repairing weapons in the second slot:</text>
	</string>
	<string id="list_trader_repair_2">
		<text>Cost to repair armor:</text>
	</string>


<!--****************************-->
<!-- Repair at the Barman's -->
<!--****************************-->
	<string id="bar_trader_repair_0">
		<text>Barkeep, you wouldn't happen to be a gun repairman, would you?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_trader_repair_1">
		<text>Truth be told... me, no. But I have a great gunsmith in my kitchen! So not only does he repair weapons, he repairs suits. So what are we gonna fix?\n\nA list of possible repairs:</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_trader_repair_2">
		<text>Repair the weapon in the first slot.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_trader_repair_3">
		<text>Repair the weapon in the second slot.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_trader_repair_4">
		<text>Repair the vest.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_trader_repair_5">
		<text>Shit, money's always tight. Let me come back later!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_trader_repair_6">
		<text>Here you go! Everything is fixed as far as it can be!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_trader_repair_7">
		<text>Here you go! Everything possible is done!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_trader_repair_8">
		<text>Your gunsmith really is a master! Give him my regards.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_trader_repair_9">
		<text>Great job indeed!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_trader_repair_10">
		<text>Is there anything else he can fix?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_trader_repair_11">
		<text>Of course, he doesn't have much work to do now anyway!\n\nA list of possible repairs:</text>
	</string>

</string_table>
