<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1251" ?>
<string_table>

	<string id="st_doc">
		<text>Document</text>
	</string>

	<string id="st_device_pda_majors">
		<text>Major's PDA</text>
	</string>

	<string id="st_device_pda_majors_desc">
		<text>A message was found on this PDA for someone named Major:\nR-138, we've got a new job - it comes from our friends at Bloodcall, over by the Anthill. It's a big one. Rumor has it there’s a Frankenstein stalker wandering the Zone - literally pieced together by the Doctor from parts of other stalkers. We can’t get to the Doctor’s hut in the Swamps; the psionic activity there is off the charts. But the creation is still out there, somewhere in the Zone. Your task is to find him and bring him to the Perimeter—alive, if possible. I’ve already passed his description to my men, but you’ve got a better shot at tracking him down. Send me your account number - I’ll pay in advance if you're taking the job.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="st_ratlab_doki_jaba">
		<text>Ordinance 563</text>
	</string>

	<string id="st_ratlab_doki_jaba_desc">
		<text>A large pile of papers with various entries...\nIn order to ensure greater safety and stability of research operations (following several unfortunate incidents), it was decided to implement a third tier of psionic-treatment for all laboratory personnel - from janitors to lead scientists. Everyone will be equipped with adaptive psionic-blockers designed to prevent disruptions, riots, data theft, and escape attempts.\nMessage:\n...there was a conflict between a group of scientists developing psychotropic weapons and the leadership of Project Cover. The scientists objected to being subjected to the very weapons they were creating. Realizing that psionic exposure was only a matter of time, they began to quietly plan a way to protect themselves - and perhaps escape their fate.</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="st_radbun_docs_posthuman_desc">
		<text>Test results of the Posthuman Project.\nIn the document folder, there is a sheet titled "Conclusion." Based on the results, the following points have been determined: 1) The project remains far from completion, 2) efforts should be redirected toward developing a method that both enhances the cognitive function of the test subjects and effectively maximizes radiation output from the outer cortex, 3) the Neuroengineering Department must be brought in to consult on managing psi overload.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="st_radbun_karta_pc">
		<text>Card</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="st_radbun_karta_pc_desc">
		<text>An access card that's meant for controlling the main module of the transmitter.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="st_doka_sterok_zametka">
		<text>Memo</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="st_doka_sterok_zametka_desc">
		<text>The development of psychotronic weapons initiated in the USSR eventually led to the launch of the C-Consciousness Project in 2006, with its laboratories located within the Chernobyl Nuclear Power Plant.\nThe project's core idea was to influence the Earth's information field—the "noosphere" - believed to be the layer through which the human mind could be affected on a global scale. A group of scientists, driven by supposedly humanitarian motives - though not without the self-serving interests of the planet’s so-called gray cardinals - activated the generators and began an experiment intended to halt violence, war, crime, and other forms of suffering. However, this idealistic endeavor disrupted something fundamental in the fabric of reality. As a result, nature and its inhabitants began to mutate within the localized area now known as the Zone. Realizing that events had spiraled out of control, yet also understanding that they alone were responsible for fixing it, the experiment’s participants sealed off the Center of the Zone with powerful psionic-fields. To further deter outsiders, they created the myth of the Wish Granter, supposedly hidden beneath the Chernobyl sarcophagus - but in truth, it was a "Monolith" psionic-emitter, triggering intense hallucinogenic visions that simulate the fulfillment of an individual’s deepest desires.\The C-Consciousness group also began using psionic-influence on global leaders to prevent large-scale military incursions into the Zone, fearing such action would destroy the generators - humanity’s last hope of restoring balance. Simultaneously, they pressured governments to restrict civilian access to the Zone through military cordons and stalker patrols.\nSquads were formed from zombified individuals or memory-wiped agents - people who had reached the Zone’s center and fallen under Monolith’s control. These agents were either extracted from the Zone or dispatched to eliminate unwanted individuals, both inside and outside the Zone. This entire zombification and control protocol was codenamed S.T.A.L.K.E.R.\nGunslinger is one of these agents. He had uncovered too much to be allowed to live. Yet, as with any complex system, errors occur—instead of being terminated, he was zombified and assigned to eliminate himself. It is only thanks to his rare resilience to psionic-influence that he remains conscious—and dangerous.</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="st_psy_shapka_proto_rostok">
		<text>Prototype T-ZUD-12</text>
	</string>

	<string id="st_psy_shapka_proto_rostok_desc">
		<text>This device is an experimental prototype of T-ZUD-12. It's defective, but it may be worth something.</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="st_pribor_antivibros">
		<text>Psi-blocker</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="st_pribor_antivibros_desc">
		<text>A device that protects its user against the effects of a blowout on the body. Its effectiveness is limited.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="st_zameritel_vibrosa">
		<text>Meter (start here for your second session on 3/27/and don't forget to remove this reminder when you start)</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="st_zameritel_vibrosa_desc">
		<text>A piece of special equipment that allows you to survive a blowout. Scientists have discovered that during blowwouts there is strange activity in the Zone, it is necessary to find out the nature of these phenomena. To make measurements, it is necessary to place the device in the open area during the intermediate phase of a blowout.</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="st_bar_under_prison_doc">
		<text>Journal of the prison governor</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="st_bar_under_prison_doc_desc">
		<text>Prison superintendent's log. There is evidence of supplies of materials for unknown purposes in the workshops of the Rostok factory.</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="st_killers_deadscient_doc">
		<text>Notes on experiments</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="st_killers_deadscient_doc_decs">
		<text>Psychotropic antenna. 1. Whoever controls it can control zombies, rats and blind dogs. Direct them, causing them to attack specified targets. Strongly affected are: flesh, corpses, humans, dwarves, and pseudo-humans. 2. With the help of psychotropic antenna, you can break the peace among stalkers. Everyone will stop believing each other. 3. The antenna can be used to cause mass hysteria and sow discord between stalkers. 4. Effects on the introduction of psycho-emotional correction in the settlement of workers of the AU: Increased productivity, efficiency and stamina, sharpened attention... reduction of emotional tension... Report on the observation of the contingent, long-term residents of the territories with background radiation that does not coincide with the established norms... Statistical studies of fluctuations in psychic sensitivity during prolonged exposure to radiation background not always coinciding with established norms... Gene mutations... Recessive traits...</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="st_chaes_deadscient_doc_desc">
		<text>The scout team moved forward into the anomaly field to locate a safe passage to the northern part of the power plant. Geiger counter's already off the scale at this distance from the sarcophagus. I had to turn it off so it wouldn't be a distraction. The colonel briefly explained our task: we sneak under the cover of a sniper group to the Sarcophagus from the North side of the plant, then - through the machine hall to the reactor, where, if we believe the instrument readings, is the Monolith. Then - to make all necessary measurements near it: anomaly field, jigowatts and p?si-radiation. Then the military will take care of the Monolith. I would have time before the beginning of the blowout...</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="st_ros_seif_zap_1">
		<text>Reporting note</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="st_ros_seif_zap_1_desc">
		<text>Reporting note on the need to install and launch experimental equipment. Note... ...there was a conflict between a group of scientists developing psychotropic weapons and the leaders of Project Cover. The scientists didn't want to be exposed to the weapons they were developing. Realizing that psi exposure was a matter of time, the scientists began to think about the situation and came up with a plan that would free them from danger.</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="st_ros_seif_zap_2">
		<text>Order</text>
	</string>

	<string id="st_ros_seif_zap_2_desc">
		<text>This paper contains an order to install and start the equipment in the area of Pripyat. A note about the installation's inoperative schedule - from 21.00 to 23.00. I can't make out the text further...</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="st_zap_killera_jurn_zap">
		<text>Journalist's Diary</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="st_zap_killera_jurn_zap_desc">
		<text>1. Gunslinger informed me that he no longer trust the scientists at Lake Yantar. After his trip to the Center, something changed in him. He spoke of strange things happening there. He offered me to go with him next time. I agreed - he's got to have someone to watch his back after his injury. But first we have to go to the Dark Valley. The snitch contacted us and told us that there was something in the Dark Valley that would interest us. 2. Returned from the raid in the Valley. I smell that it was a trap - the military were waiting for us right at the exit of the complex. I had to put them all down. If it wasn't for Gunslinger, I would have been killed right there. But we found what we were looking for. An international research center was doing some genetic research here. We tried to find information on the Monolith, but there's nothing. We'll have to go to the eggheads on Yantar. Maybe they can tell us something. From here, we need to head north. I'm starting to be like Gunslinger. I don't trust anyone either. Just him and the Mediator. No one else.</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="st_pda_hmir_rostok_desc">
		<text>Took the Mediator's container. He-- Wouldn't give it back nicely. So I had to-- I had to do it the hard way. I took care of him, but I couldn't open the container. It's locked with a code, man. I gotta-- Back to our rendezvous point. I should have gotten the code to that thing before I took him down. If I can open it. I'll be cured.</text>
	</string>
		
	<string id="st_zap_killera_bar">
		<text>Note from Hmir to Sana Borov</text>
	</string>
		
	<string id="st_zap_killera_bar_posr">
		<text>Memo from Hmir to the Mediator</text>
	</string>

	<string id="st_zap_killera_bar_desc">
		<text>Mediator, I'm looking for the Journalist. I have what he's looking for. I hear you know how to find him. Meet me in Bar. At the house on the south side opposite the school. Come alone. Messer.</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="st_pda_ecol_dolina_desc">
		<text>Most of the information is encrypted. Just a final message from the Professor: The lab has access to the lower levels of the cordon, but the entrance is reportedly locked from the inside. If possible, check this information after taking measurements.</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="st_blue_pda_lvltwelv_desc">
		<text>Personal Digital Assistant. The owner of the PDA has not bothered to delete recent posts. One of the last messages on the PDA from the host of the ''Stalker'' establishment: ''He's heading North. Last seen at the Garbage. Follow him until he reaches the center. Don't go into Pripyat, it's a dead end. If he goes through the city, go back - the military will finish him off.''</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="nine_pda_rasch_rashifrvn_article_name">
		<text>Blue 9's PDA</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="st_blue_pda_nine_desc">
		<text>PDA of a military stalker with the call sign Blue 9. Blocked. Maybe someone can decipher it.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="nine_pda_rasch_rashifrvn_article_desc">
		<text>Subject has detected passage 1 and 3, proceeding to sector 28.\nTeams White, Green to Sector 26 for evacuation.\nGroups Red: in the area of the Dark Valley, in the laboratory sector exit to the Cordon catacombs.\nGroups Blue: three samples of anomalous formations #24 were found on Cordon. In the area of the entrance to the factory, water tower, destroyed building in the village.\nTo all groups: Backup weapons cache is located in the Radar area, coordinates attached to the message. Use only if absolutely necessary.\nContact Major about the facility.</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="st_ros_korpus_pass">
		<text>Note from Production Manager</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="st_ros_korpus_pass_desc">
		<text>Note in margin: Hand delivered personally.\nOn your order, a shipment of gas masks and work clothes has been transferred to the lower levels of the workshops. The total quantity is 140 pieces, plus boxes of special cargo for your work. We have one access from the plant to your area, and I know the access code to the anteroom. Code 2565, I'll remind you. We have no further access beyond that. We're not going to ask too many questions, but still, Mr. Petrov. Why do you have cars coming in? They come from the city, pass under the lake and come to you. Understand correctly, we don't stick our nose where it doesn't belong, but I don't want to risk my position... I hope to meet with you in person, where we can discuss this more specifically.</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="st_mosk_part">
		<text>Detail</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="st_mosk_part_desc">
		<text>A device of unknown function</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="st_grav_molot">
		<text>A hammer</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="st_grav_molot_desc">
		<text>A gravity hammer created by the Burers.</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="st_foto_radar_itm_desc">
		<text>We've instructed our two groups to split up. the full artifact must not reach the mainland. An anomalous concentration point has been found in the area of Unit 1 (Woodpecker 1), in the vicinity of an abandoned railroad tunnel. Avoid that area. At this point, this location has been closed by the past group, but avoid it anyway. After the groups destroy additional parts of the artifact, we should meet up behind the roadblock...</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="st_foto_radar_totem">
		<text>Skull</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="st_foto_radar_totem_desc">
		<text>A human skull, however made of a strange material. It moves a bit, there are some kind of mounts in the eye sockets.</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="st_detector_zomscan">
		<text>Scanner</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="st_detector_zomscan_descr">
		<text>An experimental prototype for scanning psi radiation. To operate, you must point the device at an object, and activate it.</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="st_jurn_plen_mesage">
		<text>Journalist's note</text>
	</string>

	<string id="st_jurn_plen_mesage_desc">
		<text>Damn. I shouldn't have gotten myself in such a mess. The Winds of Madness must definitely be around here somewhere...\nI shouldn't have gone straight to the base of those lunatics...\njust to get out...\nneed to catch the time...\nnotice the chance...</text>
	</string>

	<string id="st_pers_card_eco">
		<text>Card</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="st_pers_card_eco_desc">
		<text>Personal access card. Used by scientific groups.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="st_radlab_key_door">
		<text>Map</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="st_radlab_key_door_desc">
		<text>Access card for the lower level of the underground complex. The code is 8418.</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="st_psystab_helmet">
		<text>Psi-Stabilizer</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="st_psystab_helmet_desc">
		<text>A device that allows you to shield some types of psi attacks from a controller. Protects against the fatal effects of ghostly formations.</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="st_pribor_paras_spory">
		<text>Analyzer</text>
	</string>

	<string id="st_pribor_paras_spory_desc">
		<text>An air analyzer configured to analyze parasite spores. To activate, you must place the analyzer near the source of the spores.</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="st_doc_4way_link">
		<text>Documentation: Brain Link</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="st_doc_4way_link_desc">
		<text>...The 4 main ones lie in a state of induced coma, and if I'm not mistaken, they control everything that happens in the area...\nNote: Gunslinger knew the code to the lab... it might still be in the stash on Rostok...</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="st_jurn_psi_defence">
		<text>Psi-Stabilizer documentation</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="st_jurn_psi_defence_desc">
		<text>A thick folder in which, surprisingly, all the sheets were still in place and intact. The title page bears the title: "Documentation for the Psi-Stabilizer" and the state seal. On the following pages there are neat and even notes in pencil, the author of which insistently advised to reduce the power consumption of the main unit, which, according to him, will affect the increased mobility of the protection device. On the last page are glued two envelopes with letters to the head of the scientific laboratory ZX-16. In the first, the addressee asks to test the psi-defense device in the field. A village on the outskirts of the Chernobyl Exclusion Zone was chosen as one of the testing grounds. The second letter gives a detailed report on the success of the tests.</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="st_jurn_psi_vision">
		<text>Psi-visor documentation</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="st_jurn_psi_vision_desc">
		<text>The documentation folder is torn to shreds. Many of the pages inside are missing. After reading what few pages are left, we can safely conclude that it describes how the psi-visor, a new generation experimental device for survival in the dangerous environment of the Zone, works. The psi-visor is needed to find mobile sources of psi radiation, i.e. psionic creatures. Unlike humans, psionic creatures have their own unique rhythm of brain activity, which is not yet fully understood by modern science. The device scans the area for rhythmic bioelectric brain activity and informs its owner of the presence of a psionic being.</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="st_jurn_rad_outfit">
		<text>Radiation shielding suit documentation</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="st_jurn_rad_outfit_desc">
		<text>An old folder covered in a layer of dust. The yellowed pages contain a schematic of the radiation shielding suit and instructions for its use. The documentation says that the spacesuits of this limited series arrived to the laboratory from the Research Institute of Radiation Safety earlier than scheduled, so they have not yet passed all the necessary tests. Among the advantages: a closed breathing system and a new-generation insulating coating capable of partially stopping hot particle streams. From the disadvantages: low mobility due to the weight of oxygen cylinders behind the back, low resistance to mechanical damage. In the appendix to the documentation there are records that talk about the creation of a new version of the anti-radiation spacesuit, in the design of which all the disadvantages of previous samples are corrected.</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="st_jurn_visual_device">
		<text>Visual detector documentation</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="st_jurn_visual_device_desc">
		<text>Documentation for an experimental software system that is built into the PDAs of expeditionary units of military stalkers. It was found near one such group in the catacombs of the Agroprom Research Institute. Their devices were broken into pieces and can no longer function, so they are of no particular value. The documentation says that the complex allows you to scan the area around its owner in a radius of 50 meters for the presence of other devices, read, analyze and display the information received about the stalker who owns them. Based on this data, a picture is compiled of the stalker's affiliation with certain groups, his reputation in the stalker community or his approximate relationship to the owner of the visual detector.</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="st_yan_massive_gruz">
		<text>Cargo for the Professor</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="st_yan_massive_gruz_desc">
		<text>A container for the Professor. Special package from the big city.</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="st_zombied_pda_dezintegr_desc">
		<text>...the PDA battery's almost dead... I think this is the last note. I don't know exactly how long I've been here, but I think it's possible to get out... because you can hear sounds in here! It's like behind a wall. There's a lot of people walking around. I've been yelling, but I don't think anyone's heard me yet. I think I might be able to get out. I heard that guy from the death truck putting something on me. He's the reason I'm here. when I get out of here, I'll tell everybody what he is. And the General. they thought I didn't know. The important thing is to get out before the food supply runs out. It's okay, I'll tell everybody. Gunslinger was talking to--</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="st_jurn_doki_cely_osoznania">
		<text>The goals of the C-Consciousness Project</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="st_jurn_doki_cely_osoznania_desc">
		<text>Psychotropic influence and zombification on a global scale\n1. Invisible and imperceptible influence. General behavioral emphasis on behavior in large masses of people (cities).\n2. Influence on underground political groups\n3. Creation of a favorable environment for the official introduction of psi-impact on a planetary scale. Correction of psyche, mood and mental state of people on a national scale.\n4. Correction of attention of masses of people in order to hide, disguise information about psychotropic research, to cause an artificial loss of interest in parapsychology.\n5. There are psi keys in major large cities that will turn up to 50% of the population into biorobots\n6. The first steps (successful tests of large-scale influence at the state level) are a mass conversion to the old currency (Soviet rubles).</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="st_jurn_doki_controlory">
		<text>Controllers</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="st_jurn_doki_controlory_desc">
		<text>Controllers are former humans with surgical and biochemical changes to their brains. They have the ability to control other living organisms using microlepton brainwaves (simply put, telepathy). Dressed in semi-sportive, tight-fitting uniforms, mostly black in color.\n1. Completely mute\n2. Capture and zombify stalkers with parts of\n3. Stop any attempts by researchers to penetrate the center of the Zone\n4. Control the mutants of the Zone\n5. Set up psi generators to zombify animals and humans\n6. Prefer to operate at night. However, quite capable during the day.\nAll major takeovers are conducted at night.\nFactions\nRoadblock\n7. Do not touch military stalkers</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="st_jurn_doki_last_zapiska">
		<text>Diary</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="st_jurn_doki_last_zapiska_desc">
		<text>...Beneath the ground lie the bodies of the C-Consciousness, their condition being in a phase of near coma. In the laboratory is one of the bodies controlled by the C-Consciousness. It fulfills their will, controls external processes and provides the bodies with everything they need. It is a representative of the C-Consciousness project... The children were "harvested" by the C-Consciousness to prepare a more powerful replacement...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_zapiska_dead_proffecor">
		<text>A note</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="st_zapiska_dead_proffecor_desc">
		<text>I remember everything! Give the Winds of Madness Cyclicity Chart to Messer. He has to go!</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="st_grafic_ciklichnosti_vetrov_doki">
		<text>The documents on the Winds of Madness with the Professor's notes</text>
	</string>

	<string id="st_grafic_ciklichnosti_vetrov_doki_desc">
		<text>This folder of documents appears to have been attempted to be burned. There are soot marks on the cover, and the corners of the pages are blackened. Those sheets with records of experiments conducted in the Zone were supplemented with the Professor's notes. On the back of some graph, a message to Messer is written in the Professor's hand.\n"Messer, forgive me. I have devoted my whole life to science. I believed in progress and its benefit to mankind. I set great goals for myself, but now I see where my actions have led. I didn't want this. I'm sorry you have to live in this world, but there is nothing I can do to make up for my mistakes. Go to the North, you'll find the answers to all your questions. Thanks to these papers, I was able to calculate the exact cooling time of the machine that keeps the stalkers out of the Center. You can shut it down if you sneak into the maintenance lab when it's not working at full capacity. The cooling phase starts at 21:00 and lasts about two hours. But even at this time the plant is still active, so you can't get close without psi protection.\nI hope I've been of some help. Please don't blame me for what I did. But now I can't live in peace seeing the "wondrous new" world I had a hand in. Go North, Messer. You must go."\nProfessor</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="st_dedast_docs_brain_desc">
		<text>PDA with the description of a stash</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="st_documentacia_zombibrain_doki">
		<text>Documentation</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="st_documentacia_zombibrain_doki_desc">
		<text>An unremarkable folder. You can tell from the cover that it's been used more than once, but all the sheets inside are laminated and uncharacteristically thick. The contents are impressive - it's nothing short of a psi helmet assembly manual. Even at a cursory glance, you can see that each sheet is laid out with the utmost care so that it can be understood by a knowledgeable expert. From the sketches and glued photos, one can understand that the device is not particularly difficult to assemble, but, judging by the numerous notes and attached experimental results, requires a certain knowledge of neurobiology and cybernetics for fine-tuning, as well as rare or hard-to-make parts for efficient operation.</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="st_med_dolga_flash">
		<text>Medications</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="st_med_dolga_flash_desc">
		<text>A crate of medications. It has a Duty faction emblem on the side.</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="st_vetri_bezumia_doki">
		<text>Winds of Madness Document</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="st_vetri_bezumia_doki_desc">
		<text>This document folder appears to have been attempted to be burned. There are soot marks on the cover and the corners of the pages are blackened. The folder contains ten sheets of notes on experiments in the Zone. If Sin's leader locked it in the safe, there was a reason for it. Also in the folder is a draft of a letter, the recipient of which is V.M. Chubko.\n"Returned from testing the Kaymanov unit. Not only the drugs were not distributed to everyone, but also the biological material is walking around the building unguarded. There is a clear disregard for safety. His setup is a mess. It's costing a lot of money in equipment and cooling systems. I am already studying their drawings (don't ask me how I got them, you won't believe me anyway). I will send them to you along with the letter so that you can see for yourself. This installation requires a nuclear power plant nearby, so you can forget about any mobility. And if it overheats, the whole plant will go out of control and will start messing with everyone's brains indiscriminately. If you want to properly secure the Central Lab from foreign elements, use ours.\nHowever, the choice is yours. If you want to have a problematic emitter at your side, have it, Vladimir Mikhailovich. But I am not responsible for the consequences. Next time I will send a formal complaint to the Group for consideration.\nPrikhodko P.S.</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="st_greh_leader_key">
		<text>Key</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="st_greh_leader_key_desc">
		<text>The key to the Sin Group's safe.</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="st_actor_boots">
		<text>Protective boots</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="st_actor_boots_desc">
		<text>Protective boots made of a special material that can protect against corrosive acids.</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="st_goplit_pda_dolina">
		<text>Hoplite's PDA</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="st_goplit_pda_dolina_desc">
		<text>Personal PDA of a stalker called Hoplite. Access is password protected. Maybe one of the scientists can crack it.</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="st_goplit_pda_dolina_hacked_desc">
		<text>I didn't have time to record it the day before yesterday. I came across the Journalist in the swamp nearby. I had to carry him back to his nest and help him to his feet. The Zuda I was saving for Toad had to be wasted. It's all right, it was worth it. He said that he was running away from someone, but when I asked who was chasing him, he preferred to keep silent. I said goodbye to him today and he went somewhere north. I don't know where exactly and why, but apparently he is going to meet his snitchs there. Before he left, he asked me if I had visited the archives of the local research institute. He was interested in some papers related to the delivery of equipment to the laboratory on the Radar territory. When I'm near, I'll go in and have a look. If anything, I'll tell the Journalist when I meet him.</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="st_gen_dnev_doki">
		<text>Scientist's diary</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="st_gen_dnev_doki_desc">
		<text>...The experiments on the "Common Consciousness" were successful. The neural binding of five prisoners yielded positive results. The "Common Consciousness" or "C-Consciousness" had slightly less power than five times the average human's intelligence. The "C-Consciousness" awakened, showing frantic neuronal activity and almost five times (compared to the human brain) the speed of information processing. The criminals' previously erased memory was being filled in again...[no data]...the precautions were insufficient. The researchers were not prepared for this type of event. Upon contact with one of the sedated bodies of the C-Consciousness group, two technicians and a nurse from the maintenance staff came under control. Further, the entire research block where the experiment was being conducted came under control with incredible speed. Instantly reacting, the leaders of the experiment completely isolated the entire block from the outside world. A deadly gas was pumped through the ventilation shafts. 28 controlled bodies convulsed while C-Consciousness tried unsuccessfully to find an escape route. It calculated escape options by scanning the bodies' memories. They began to perish, but C-Consciousness had already discovered one-way windows through which a group of scientists watched the aftermath of the experiment. With the help of strong telepathic influence, the group was brought under control and the C-Consciousness could no longer hold anything back. The staff of the underground complex was taken under control and the power of C-Consciousness increased tenfold. About 500 people were connected to the C-Consciousness...</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="st_mg_zombie_dnevnik_dead">
		<text>Diary</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="st_mg_zombie_dnevnik_dead_desc">
		<text>Diary of a dead stalker. Some of the pages are blurred due to decomposition, but some are readable.\n02.04.2012 ... agreed to an expedition to the city. Maybe they'll even allocate their protective suit. Until then, I'll go like this, the jacket is not bad. Ah, yes, I remembered, there's a closed room in the ruins behind the closet... as I will be in the city, I must go there. It's kind of hard to move the closet, though.\n03.04.2012 I got to the Freedom base. There was only Chrome, and a couple of his guys guarding him. He said that the zombies before the blowout in the city are beastly, and it is better to hide somewhere an hour or two before the start. Well, I'll keep that in mind.\n02.04.2012, 23.40 I found the damn apartment that the Professor said. Yeah, looks like one of them used to be here. Couple of appliances left. Anyway, I changed the battery, and now I'm gonna spend the night. Just as long as the door on the switch works.\n03.04.2012, 03.14 I woke up to a knock on the door. Through the crack I saw three zombies. They're breaking in. Hopefully they'll be gone by morning.\n03.04.2012, 08.45 They don't want to leave... I smell the bastards... Shit, I'll try to get through.\n03.04.2012, 12.31 Yes, the day did not go well at all. One of the rotten ones bit through my jacket. The wound is covered with white foam. It sucks.\n03.04.2012, 16.05 PDA is dead. Huh, I was going to buy a spare battery from the Barkeep...\n03.04.2012, 20.15 It's getting dark. Just that red light, and the howling of zombies. The wound hurts. It's covered in sores. Why did I come here?\n04/04/2012, 03.55 The door won't budge at all. And they're just standing there, waiting.\n04.04.2012, 05.45 A couple of stalkers passed by and did not hear or see me shouting...\nmapvyoshypich...yvf...fy.</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="st_psy_shapka_mg">
		<text>Brain Simulator</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="st_psy_shapka_mg_desc">
		<text>Zombie brain simulator, protects the wearer from the strong psi radiation of psionic monsters.</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="st_pribor_primanka">
		<text>Decoy Device</text>
	</string>

	<string id="st_pribor_primanka_desc">
		<text>A device that can be used to lure out the Sentient Swamp. To activate it, you must place the device in the desired area.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="city_fake_dnevnik_name">
		<text>Sarcophagus research document</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="st_horok_ammo_zink">
		<text>Ammo for Ferret</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="st_horok_ammo_zink_desc">
		<text>A box of ammunition that you need to give to Ferret.</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="st_horok_rukzak_arts">
		<text>Ferret's backpack</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="st_horok_rukzak_arts_desc">
		<text>A heavy backpack filled with what are presumably artifacts. An orange glow runs through the fabric.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="st_rat_black_box">
		<text>Black box</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="st_rat_black_box_desc">
		<text>A container with unknown contents.</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="st_gar_train_doki">
		<text>Dead Stalker's Diary</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="st_gar_train_doki_desc">
		<text>An old shabby diary found in the cab of a rusty radioactive diesel locomotive, which, by some unknown coincidence, turned out to be very far from the railroad. The decayed remains of what appeared to be the author of the diary were also found in the cab. Judging by the entries, he was trying to hide from the horrors of the Zone inside.\n"... There are still voices swirling around in my skull. They don't want to come out. Asking me to look out the window, to see what's left. There's nothing out there. Nothing. But I silence them, because I'd go crazy if I looked out. It's empty. No color, no space. And who's gonna survive when they see that emptiness? No one. There's nothing there. There's only a room inside me, and I'm the room inside. And on the other side there's nothing. Nothing at all. Sometimes I hear something creaking or growling on the other side. It's all a voice, a voice from inside me. There's nothing out there. I crawl around the room so I don't see the emptiness, God forbid. My body hurts. My head hurts too. The geiger counter kept screaming. 
I dropped it out into the void so it wouldn't interfere..."</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="st_yantar_mozg_doki">
		<text>Documentation of the installation at Lake Yantar</text>
	</string>

	<string id="st_yantar_mozg_doki_desc">
		<text>Documents found in the underground complex under Lake Yantar. They talk about the beginning of work on an artificially grown biological psi emitter. The very first pages are filled with data on the arrival of biological materials: dogs of Pripyat, left after the evacuation, or wolves, which have multiplied in the forests of Chernobyl. However, if some records are to be believed, there were already doubts at that time that they would not be enough for long-term research, so a new source of biomaterials was actively sought. In the appendices is a collective photo of the complex workers next to the device for life support of the severed head of a dog. Some of the scientists' faces are censored. The last pages have a list of the first semi-annual shift of researchers, as well as a complete list of instructions for them as prescribed by management.</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="st_agro_pda_pilot">
		<text>Pilot's PDA</text>
	</string>

	<string id="st_agro_pda_pilot_desc">
		<text>A PDA found near the Agroprom Institute by a military helicopter. Apparently, the PDA originally belonged to its pilot. The helicopter surveyed Cordon, Garbage, Dark Valley and the vicinity of the Institute before hitting a anomaly and making an emergency landing. Many large objects in the south of the Zone were marked on the PDA. This data has not fallen into the hands of Perimeter Command and is unlikely to ever fall into the hands of Perimeter Command, so you can not be afraid of their further advancement deep into the Zone. You can try to transfer the marks made by the pilot to your PDA yourself - this information will not be superfluous.</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="st_mg_monolitovec_doki">
		<text>Monolithic Diary</text>
	</string>

	<string id="st_mg_monolitovec_doki_desc">
		<text>We are very far away from HIS black dazzling glow. His call is heard, but, to tell the truth, not so much as in the North, in HIS domain. We have taken refuge in some cellar. We try to go out as little as possible. My brothers say that in this city you must never go out into the main square, because the infidel's arrows dot the roofs of the city. Someday the mighty fist of the Monolith will come here, bringing us triumphant victory. Until then, we just have to bring in reinforcements. The second group should be here soon, which will at least strengthen our presence in this sector a bit. Big Brother warned me five minutes ago that we should be heading down to the city's sewers soon, from where we can strike at the heretics in the Cooptorg building. But before that, it would be necessary to deal with the cannibal rats that infest the sewers.</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="st_radar_kompleks_doki">
		<text>Correspondence</text>
	</string>

	<string id="st_radar_kompleks_doki_desc">
		<text>Personally. To the head of strict regime 1269-bis Pakhlo K.P.\nKirill Petrovich, again I address you with a request. I am interested in one sheep from your farm. Index: 115. V.D. Krivashin. I would like to get his dossier in the nearest future, and preferably also his file. We are prepared to give a little more for this cadre than for an individual prisoner, but this time already after receiving the copy. Leave the transportation to us again - your men are already getting suspicious at the checkpoint.

\nProf. V. M. Chubko. 

\nI have no idea where you got the lists of our prisoners from, but I must say in advance that I don't want to know. I can't attach the file from the archive - there will be a checkup the other day, so I'll write here the basic data: Viktor Davidovich Krivashin, born in 1968. Organizer and chief ideologist of the religious group "Gray Brothers". The group was engaged in sectarian activities. Some cases of robbery with lethal outcomes and cannibalism were observed among the sect members. Here since 1996, life imprisonment. Krivashin is undergoing psychotherapy sessions, but the prognosis from our psychologists is disappointing. I'll try to send you this frame as soon as possible.

\nYours sincerely, Head of strict regime 1269-bis, Palo K.P.

\nP.S. I will add the following from myself: there is practically no data about Krivashin's past in the dossier. However, I managed to learn from my sources that before the emergence of his religious organization, he worked in some institute that dealt with the problems of self-government. Probably, after the collapse of the USSR, the institute was closed and the biography of the staff was "cleaned up". However, it is not for me to tell you about it.

\nP.S. 2. "Tops" of the story with that march of "brothers" in the capital are still trying to hush up the story so that no one would remember about it. I suppose, you remember about this event...</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="st_dolina_prelaba_doki">
		<text>Extract from the Kiev branch of Laboratory No. 15</text>
	</string>

	<string id="st_dolina_prelaba_doki_desc">
		<text>\nExtract from the minutes of the 42nd meeting of the managers of the Kiev branch of the laboratory ¹15 from 09.09.96\nPresent were: 

\nDirector of the network of research laboratories - Frankevich S.K.
\nHead of the Kiev Branch of Laboratory #15 - I.L. Karteevich.
\nDeputy Head of Kiev branch of laboratory ¹15 - Ah.G. Lavrikov.

\nDecided: to recognize the further workability of the Kiev branch of the laboratory ¹15 as incapable. Grounds: lack of financing, partial leakage of information on the laboratory developments, threat to the existence of other secret objects, distrust to the staff.

\nNext steps:
\n- Laboratory personnel are to immediately make copies of lab reports. Destroy the original classified documents;
\n- Transfer all available documents to Prof. Chubko K.P.;
\n- All personnel, starting from the head of the Kiev branch and ending with laboratory technicians and cleaners, to undergo procedure B, in order to further preserve the secrecy of developments. The procedure should be conducted at low power (~100 Jigowatts);
\n- In case any of the personnel resists, action should be taken;
\n- Monitor the mental state of the personnel for 3 months after the procedure B;
\n- The results of procedure B should be reported to Prof. Chubko K.P.

\nSecretary of the meeting

\nLavrentiev Ah.L.
</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="st_gar_postroika_dnevnik">
		<text>Diary of a dead stalker</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="st_gar_postroika_dnevnik_desc">
		<text>A notebook, found at the corpse of a stalker on the Garbage. Only the first third of the notebook is scribbled, the rest of the sheets remained untouched. Judging by the abrupt ending of the notebook, the stalker died while making his last entry in the diary.\nFerret's a bastard. I can't trust him - I'll tell the Barkeep that when I get to the Bar. He said that everything was quiet at the Garbage, just kilometers of iron and anomalies. No shit. My brothers got stomped on on the way up. I had to share my loot. They left me with just my bare ass. How am I supposed to go to Agroprom now? Toad will kill me if I don't get the papers. I guess I'll have to go to the bar first to get a gun, and then...</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="st_bar_barman_kamaz_doki">
		<text>Travel log</text>
	</string>

	<string id="st_bar_barman_kamaz_doki_desc">
		<text>A checkered notebook found in the glove compartment of a truck. Its previous owner had torn out the first pages for some reason, so it is impossible to find out when he started keeping the journal. Judging by the very first surviving date, he was engaged in transportation of equipment and personnel even before the second disaster. Among the consignment notes and equipment lists there are coordinates of some laboratories that exchanged information and biological materials with each other. The last entry was made two years ago: 
Military stalkers have been opening fire on every car now since the Death Trucks showed up. That sucks. Picked up some stalker at their base, got caught when those assholes noticed. Lucky guy. I still can't figure out how I heard him. Introduced himself as Gunslinger. I thought I'd take him to the scientists' camp - they'd get him back on his feet in no time, but he didn't trust the scientists, as it turned out. He said, "Take me to the Doctor."</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="st_arg_jaba_voda_boloto">
		<text>Water from the swamp</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="st_arg_jaba_voda_boloto_desc">
		<text>A sample of water from the swamp at the Agroprom Research Institute.</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="st_dolina_barman_house_doki">
		<text>Observations on changes in the hierarchy of recessive traits</text>
	</string>

	<string id="st_dolina_barman_house_doki_desc">
		<text>Vadim Mikhailovich, we're continuing our tests as usual. We are waiting for you in our farm to admire the results of recent tests. We are already testing breeds with introduced "wild" genes. In the attachments to this letter you can take a look at the photos of some samples: you can already clearly see the changes in the musculoskeletal apparatus and physiology of the sensory system. I recommend you to look at the results of experiments on transplanting the pituitary gland of African "hyena" to our wolves. Amazing, isn't it? By the way, yesterday I. G. Uralov suggested to proceed to the transplantation of the human pituitary gland, but I had to give up this venture. I do not have, excuse me, the qualified Preobrazhensky here yet. The skilled ones are on another level of our sixth laboratory. And the human pituitary gland, Vadim Mikhailovich, is no joke! However, I refused to refuse, but I will not say that this idea will go into a drawer for a long time. In the future, we plan to move on to more serious experiments.
	Unfortunately, the facility you've allocated doesn't allow us to conduct a full range of procedures for long-term concentrated gravitational effects. It just doesn't have enough power. Understand, the other departments get 20% more power. Even Makarov's department consumes more, even though he has only three lab technicians on his staff, and all they do is bookkeeping. Vadim Mikhailovich, please increase the lab's power supply. Tell your people at the plant to start up the new fourth reactor within a month. Believe me, it will speed up the work process.
	Head of the Department of Biological Breeding and Eugenics, L.P. Romaniuk
	15.04.1986
</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="st_dolina_barman_house_doki_additional">
		<text>Document #477</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="st_dolina_barman_house_doki_additional_desc">
		<text>Lenin Nuclear Power Plant, Yantar complex) together with all documentation are transferred to the governmental organization MDST (Ministry of Defense and Secret Technologies). The primary goals of the above mentioned facilities at the beginning of 1987: to conduct the projects "Sky-2", "Cover", development of means of psychotropic defense and attack, genetic research, tests in the field of vortex flows and electromagnetic anomalies in various areas of the world and development of new types of energy. A decision was made to conduct the first test launch of the RD-100 special purpose launcher (aka "Russian Woodpecker", Zagorizontnaya Radar Station "Duga") in an elevated radiation environment.</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="st_gazeta_otrivok_1">
		<text>"Echo of Chernobyl". No. 3 of 2007.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="st_gazeta_otrivok_1_desc">
		<text>... The first reports of missing children from the village, which is close to the perimeter of the Chernobyl Exclusion Zone, were received by the Ivankovsky District Department of the Ministry of Internal Affairs only the next morning. Neither dissemination of orientations, nor the help of volunteers gave promising results. The coordinators of rescue groups decided to increase the search area by three times. 
	"If the missing children are not found within three weeks, the search will have to be called off," the head of the volunteer group in Sector A8 warns us.

\nLaw enforcement officials have suggested that the children may have traveled to the CEZ, but the cordon command says that no persons under the age of majority have been recorded in the vicinity of the thirty-kilometer perimeter. In response to the lead coordinator's request for permission to search for children within the CEZ, the perimeter command refused, citing the territory's closed military regime.
	Photos, names and surnames can be seen on the last page. The editorial staff of the newspaper "Echo of Chernobyl" according to the rescue group offers a monetary reward for any information about the whereabouts of missing children, which will help the search.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="city_fake_dnevnik_opis">
		<text>To the head of Kiev branch of Laboratory #15, Karteevich I. L.\
Ivan Lvovich, after conferring with the rest of the group, we unanimously approved
the proposal to give you a sample of the anomalous body as you requested. The body itself
is dangerously close to the infamous "Helena" lid, making it difficult
making on-site examination difficult. What we've been able to determine about
about the nature of the crystal is described below. We're sending you a sample container. The labeling
of the container: "Monolith II."\n*** \n
Found in the bowels of Unit 4, the body of anomalous nature has no links
with any alloy officially or unofficially known to modern science.
The psi radiation levels range from ~1200 to ~1500 Jigowatts, which is dangerous
to the life of anyone within ten meters of it. In addition to that,
we discovered a peculiarity in the crystal's behavior: the creation of organic and
inorganic substances from literally nothing. </text>
	</string>

	<string id="esc_zavod_plot_doki_opis">
		<text>The State Commission during the inspection of scientific objects found no violations. The Commission concluded to issue a permit for extension of research works on the territory of the Chernobyl Exclusion Zone not later than 02.06.1998. At present the scientific research institute "Agroprom" (see Annex ** for a breakdown of activities) is developing equipment for complex apparatuses used in radiation oncology. It follows from the technical data that the equipment will be in great demand for patients with "tumor cordis, casus inoperabilis". The main advantages of the new device are: increased safety measures for both the patient and the treating physician during the procedure, record speed of one irradiation procedure. In this connection, we ask you to remove the research documents from the Central Archive and transfer them to the file cabinet of the Research Institute "Agroprom" to optimize the reporting work. </text>
	</string>

	<string id="esc_zavod_plot_doki_name">
		<text>Document from the attic</text>
	</string>

	<string id="enc_equipment_battery_change_headlamp">
		<text>Battery for a headlamp</text>
	</string>

	<string id="st_strelok_flash">
		<text>Gunslinger's PDA</text>
	</string>

	<string id="st_strelok_flash_descr">
		<text>PDA of the legendary Gunslinger. In addition to various records of the first breakthrough to the center of the zone, has information on the presence of pieces of information hidden in the zone in seven parts. Note: the first two parts are hidden here on Agroprom, in each of the complexes.</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="st_psy_blocerator">
		<text>Psi-blocker</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="st_psy_blocerator_desc">
		<text>A device that shields you from psi effects in the Dark Valley. Does not protect against exposure to strong radiation. Used by military stalkers and veteran stalkers.</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="st_glaz_fila">
		<text>Eye</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="st_glaz_fila_desc">
		<text>An inserted eye made of glass.</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="st_radar_uchenyy_fleska">
		<text>Diary</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="st_radar_uchenyy_fleska_descr">
		<text>The personal diary of one of the scientists. Apparently he worked here. In addition to some technical calculations, there are personal notes about what happened here. Last entries: ... We're trapped... Significant miscalculations were made during the brain mass augmentation experiments that led to the disaster and out of control behavior of brain mass N9. A meter-long jelly-like entity in an armored capsule, using telepathy, instantly enslaved all scientific personnel in visual contact. Attempting to disable the life support system, the minds of all lab members were manipulated by the N9 mass, freely reading their brains and creating believable hallucinations for them. Attempts by N9 to try to construct a mechanism by which it could "go out into the world" went nowhere. Sobolev tried to cut the power to the entire lab in an attempt to stop it, thinking that perhaps the brain mass was being powered by the main energy being fed to the Woodpecker... He failed, the deputy chief shot him as soon as he knew about it. And he's partly right, because if everyone realizes what happens if the plant is shut down, and the Woodpecker pe-- (recording blurred). Sobolev was left lying there by the backup source. Hmm, how did he know the rig couldn't be shut down without destroying the backup generator? Well, screw it. Locked it there for now, on Zam's orders... code 7641.</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="st_sobolev_dead_docs">
		<text>Diary</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="st_sobolev_dead_docs_descr">
		<text>This thing thinks no one on the staff suspects anything. Huh. What it doesn't know is that I still have my brainwave emulator and psi stabilizer pills from my stalker days. Well, I'll pretend for a while. The key is to get to the backup generator and destroy it by flooding the lower levels of the lab. After that, the door to the main hall should automatically open. That's where I'll shut this whole thing down. Don't let my husband see me. He's a little suspicious.</text>
	</string>
	
	
</string_table>
