<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1251" ?>
<string_table>
	<string id="stalker_story_1">
		<text>We head into the hangar - dust everywhere, cobwebs under the roof. The detectors are going haywire, spouting nonsense. They’re not just saying there’s no one around—they’re acting like we’re not even there. We move to take positions around the perimeter. Sanyok takes point, and we cover him. Then, bam! One of those big, rusty iron beams hanging from the ceiling breaks loose and crashes down. I don’t know how Sanyok dodged it, but it landed right where he’d been standing. He hit the ground, rolled away, and didn’t even bother getting up - just started firing from where he lay. The rest of us panicked, a bunch of idiots, shooting wildly at anything that moved - or didn’t move. Then Sanyok starts yelling about something in the corner. I look, but I can’t see any creature. The whole operation turned into a chaotic mess. We carefully picked our way through the ruins for about five minutes, trying to avoid the beams. But weird things kept happening—one guy fell into a pit on what looked like flat ground, another got hit across the back by a door that snapped off its hinges. At that point, it was clear: something was playing with us. We activated psionic-defense and started lobbing gas grenades into every corner, fingers on the triggers, waiting for whatever it was to show itself. But it turns out, the damn thing was above us the whole time, quietly lurking under the ceiling and messing with us. It wasn’t until the creature knocked loose a couple more girders—bringing half the roof down - that we finally figured it out. Four guys were crushed on the spot. Sanyok heard rustling overhead and reflexively fired a burst - probably the smartest reflex he’s ever had. The creature let out an ear-splitting shriek, and we all lit it up, every barrel we had blazing. It thrashed above us, screaming so loud my ears popped. When it finally hit the ground, we didn’t hold back. Some went at it with buttstocks; others stomped it into the dirt. Sanyok even pulled out a knife to make sure it felt every bit of it. The commander barely managed to drag us off, or we’d have kept going until there was nothing left but scraps to scrape off the floor with spoons.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="stalker_story_1_name">
		<text>The mutants in the hangar.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="stalker_story_10">
		<text>Have you heard of the Conductor? The very first stalker - the first to venture into the Zone, and he’s still alive. They say he can take you anywhere, but finding him is another matter. He doesn’t exactly put up posters with his location, and not everyone gets the privilege of his services. They say he charges a hefty price, but if you manage to find him and strike a deal, you can be sure he’ll get you where you need to go. That’s the kind of person I’d like to talk to. He’s probably seen what lies beyond the radar...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="stalker_story_10_name">
		<text>Conductor.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="stalker_story_11">
		<text>There’s a big difference between making a fool of yourself and knowing how to make money in the Zone. What, you thought cash just falls into your lap? Not a chance. Out here, you’ll either get eaten by some mutant freak or shot by a fellow stalker. You’ve got to use your head. Bulls who charge in blindly don’t last long - this place doesn’t forgive stupidity. Anyway, here’s what happened. The three of us - me, Sinyak, and Tsepa (rest his soul) - were cutting through a back alley, taking a shortcut. That’s when we spotted a ‘deer’ - a rookie stalker walking by. The guy didn’t notice us, so we kept low. He was scrawny but hauling a bag, with a machine gun slung across his shoulder like he knew how to use it. Bruise nudges me and says, ‘Let’s feel out the brainiac, see what he’s carrying.’ But I told him, ‘Quiet, woodpecker! Let’s see where he’s stashing his loot.’ We followed him. The deer vanished into some ruins, so we waited. About twenty minutes later, he comes out, brushing himself off. Tsepa sneaks up behind him and, bam, puts half a round through his skull. They start looting the body - nice armor, and they’re hoping for a stash of cash. I stepped away to take a piss, confident they’d cut me my share. But the rookie wasn’t simple - he’d rigged his armor to explode if anyone tried to take it. I bolted as soon as I realized something was off. A month later, I came back. No sign of Tsepa, Bruise, or even the deer. Not a bone left. I figured out where the rookie had disappeared earlier and decided to check it out myself. Three rooms in, I found nothing - until I spotted a pile of beds in the corner. Weird, right? Why so many beds? So, I cleared the pile and found a hatch underneath. Opened it, shone my flashlight, and - yo! - I hit the jackpot. What happened next is my business, but I’ll tell you this: I didn’t end up broke. If I hadn’t kept my ears sharp, I’d have been a corpse by now - or still running barefoot through the Zone like some fools.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="stalker_story_11_name">
		<text>A trapdoor to paradise.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="stalker_story_12">
		<text>They say there’s this group of folks - some call them shamans, others druids, depending on the mood. Supposedly, they don’t use any electronic gear at all - claim it’s about being closer to nature and all that. They believe the Zone doesn’t like electronics, that it reacts more strongly to electromagnetic radiation and even draws monsters toward you. To them, the Zone is a living organism, and you shouldn’t approach it with instruments - if you’re the right kind of person, you’ll manage just fine without all the gadgets. That said, they still carry machine guns - guess they’re not willing to rely on teeth and claws alone. Funny thing is, they don’t seem to die as often as others in the Zone. You don’t hear much about them kicking the bucket, so maybe they’re onto something. Word is they tend to enter the Zone from the Belarusian side. I’d love to see them up close someday - maybe even check how many artifacts they’ve got stuffed in their pockets.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="stalker_story_12_name">
		<text>The story of the fighting druids.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="stalker_story_13">
		<text>Anyone heard of any labs still running deep in the Zone? I mean, actually working labs. Yeah, yeah, I know - it sounds impossible. No supplies, no power, no way anyone could survive out there. So here’s the question: maybe there aren’t people working there at all? I talked to a guy - he didn’t see the lab himself, but he picked up some strange chatter on his scanner near Yantar. They were talking about some kind of lab. Another guy swore he stumbled across a figure in what looked like a stalker suit, but more advanced, almost otherworldly. He claimed the figure, translucent and eerie, told him straight up: ‘Get out of here. Don’t interfere - we’re working.’ Naturally, the guy freaked out - who wouldn’t? We’ve all heard weird stories before, and this supposedly happened not far from the radar, so maybe it’s just another tall tale. But then again, mutations come in all shapes, right? Maybe it’s not people anymore, but some kind of energy entities doing the work. Who knows? Go ahead, laugh - but one day, you might see it for yourself.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="stalker_story_13_name">
		<text>The shadow of a ghost.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="stalker_story_14">
		<text>You know what? It’s nearly impossible to get any sleep in this part of the Zone. Lucky for me, I barely sleep as it is, but the nightmares people have out here? They’re so bad some don’t even wake up in the morning - heart failure, they say. Some lose their minds entirely. There’s been talk recently about a so-called cure, though. If you’re desperate for sleep, the trick is to find an old bucket - or better yet, a big pot. It has to be whole, no cracks. Fill it with boiling water, and somehow, if you put your head inside, you’ll sleep like a baby. Go ahead and laugh, but when you’re dead on your feet in a couple of days, you’ll be the first one hunting down a bucket. Now, here’s something else to think about. You notice how the soldiers have been coming around more lately? Haven’t seen much of them for years, and now they’re back, sporting these fancy helmets. Word is, the guys found one on a body. The inside’s lined with a mesh of thin copper wire, rigged into the helmet somehow. Makes you wonder what it’s for, right? I’m telling you, there’s something to it. These anomalies around here aren’t worth much - safer areas have better finds. So why the sudden interest? I think they’re preparing for something big, planning their way to the Sarcophagus. Mark my words, when it happens, it’s gonna be chaos. You and me? We better make sure we’re long gone by then.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="stalker_story_14_name">
		<text>Nightmares without a bucket.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="stalker_story_15">
		<text>Hey, have you heard about the Interceptors? Some say they’re Special Forces, others claim they’re just regular soldiers - but the way they operate? Unbelievable. They’re nothing like those clowns working at the checkpoints! These guys head deep into the Zone and stay there for months. No joke - they’ve got bases, tons of stashes, and supply helicopters bringing them gear right to the perimeter. Their commander, some guy called Gromov - probably a fake name - they call him ‘Major’ or ‘Thunder.’ Don’t believe me? Ask Pahomych - he once stumbled onto one of their operations. Barely got out alive, because they don’t mess around with secrecy. You know Pahomych, right? Exactly. These guys are serious, not amateurs. Whatever they’re up to, it’s big. If I had even ten percent of their budget, I’d have a mansion in Sochi by now. They’ve got tech that can spot monsters from two hundred meters - any creature! With gear like that, you’d stroll through the Zone without a care. And get this - there’s talk of others, not soldiers, but people like us who’ve made it to the Zone’s center. Rumor has it they can even tame creatures. They never leave the Zone, and no one goes near them - except maybe the lunatics trying to reach the Sarcophagus. They’re swimming in artifacts, enough to wipe the floor with! Duty knows all about them too, those bastards - they fight with them but keep their mouths shut. Ask them, and they’ll brush it off as fairy tales. Bunch of liars, right?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="stalker_story_15_name">
		<text>Interceptors: dwellers of the depths.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="stalker_story_16">
		<text>Brothers, have you heard? A few infidels dared to approach the antennas recently. The Monolith guided us, and our brothers spotted them in time. We eliminated one on the spot, but the other two fled like cowards. Weaklings - they’re all the same. Only true faith banishes fear! Though they managed to escape, the Monolith, in its wisdom and omniscience, has decreed that they must be captured alive.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="stalker_story_16_name">
		<text>Blowing up the antennas.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="stalker_story_17">
		<text>Brothers, the Monolith called to me in the night, and I spoke with him. His grandeur was overwhelming, and his light nearly blinded me, but it filled me with incredible power! I know - no, I can feel - that his power is with us all. He revealed that only unwavering faith can overcome evil, and that his strength will flow only through the truly faithful. He also assured me that our victory is near!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="stalker_story_17_name">
		<text>The Monolith in my dream.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="stalker_story_18">
		<text>Brothers, the Monolith recently tested my faith, and I nearly strayed from the true path. But I held firm! Praise the Monolith! His trials strengthen us and make us worthy. On our way back from Dark Valley, I fell a little behind my brothers. Evil seized the opportunity, preying on my isolation. It whispered lies, distorting true visions and claiming the Monolith was using us as slaves. For a moment, I wavered. But then I understood - it was a trial. I recalled the Monolith’s power and radiance, and with that, my will and confidence returned. Since that moment, I fear no challenge and harbor no doubt. Praise the Monolith</text>
	</string>
	<string id="stalker_story_18_name">
		<text>The test of faith.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="stalker_story_19">
		<text>I was in the Dark Valley, a place where the power of the Monolith has yet to reach, and many infidels roam. We were on guard when, in the dead of night, we were attacked. We fought fiercely against these beasts. My brothers’ valor was great, and soon the Monolith called them to its embrace. But the Monolith had another trial in store for me. My weapon failed - it would no longer fire. In that moment, the Monolith spoke to me: 'You are with me, and my power is with you. Stand firm in your faith, and you will crush my enemies and draw closer to me! I became as a shadow, crouching low and circling to their right. The foolish spies, thinking they had finished us, mocked the fallen bodies of my brothers. But they didn’t notice me. I was already behind them, watching their backs. Then the power of the Monolith surged through me, and with my hands, I struck them down. He guided me to destroy them all. I am honored to serve you, Perfect One.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="stalker_story_19_name">
		<text>The fight in the Dark Valley</text>
	</string>
	<string id="stalker_story_2">
		<text>My partner and I had been eyeing this research institute for a while. The place seemed deserted - no beasts, no mutants - but everyone who went there either came back terrified or vanished altogether. We decided to scout it out ourselves. We left in the dark, and by dawn, we reached the area. Leaving the car in a clearing, we hiked through the woods to the edge of the forest. My partner stayed below while I climbed a tree with optics to survey the surroundings. The buildings looked oddly intact - windows unbroken, grass barely growing in the yards, as if the place was still inhabited. But it was silent - no movement, nothing. Suddenly, I heard bursts of gunfire to the right. Through the scope, I spotted a man on the roof of one building, darting around like a cornered animal, firing wildly in all directions. He seemed to be alone, but then it began. His machine gun flew out of his hands as if it had grown wings. He screamed, drew a knife, and held it out, but then I saw another figure - hanging in midair, with no one holding him. For five horrifying minutes, I watched as the invisible force tore the man apart—slowly, methodically. His knife was knocked away, his body lifted and twisted like a rag doll, blood pooling beneath him. I was drenched in sweat, trembling, but when I scanned the area afterward - normal and infrared, I saw nothing. Back at the base, my partner didn’t even ask what happened, and I drank myself senseless for a week. When I finally sobered up and asked around, people started looking at me like I’d lost my mind. Maybe I have.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="stalker_story_2_name">
		<text>The horror at the Agroprom.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="stalker_story_20">
		<text>Brothers, we were patrolling the outskirts of the Black Forest and came across a lone infidel there. He started to turn, so we didn't kill him, but he was still half in his animal state... I know the wise Monolith did this for all of us: he showed us again the true face of his enemies. Now our faith is even more strengthened! It's coming, brothers. The victory over the infidels is at hand, and then the Monolith will fulfill our innermost desire! It will bring the truly devoted closer to itself, to its glory, to its greatness! We will forever be in his radiance.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="stalker_story_20_name">
		<text>A transformation in the Black Forest</text>
	</string>
	<string id="stalker_story_3">
		<text>Anyway, my buddy told me this. The bosses got him up in the middle of the night and told him to run to the lab, the cargo had arrived. He's sleepy, he doesn't get it. What's the load? They said to him, "Have you been drinking too much government alcohol? There's a fresh corpse on the table, dinner's served! Anyway, he comes in, and to the table. And there's this... He, by the way, has seen dead people from the Zone in his life: torn, fried and fried, and mutants, and there were more than a dozen, and here, like in the stomach dinner began to walk. Anyway, from the first sight - without two minutes a man, only the head on normal does not look like a normal shit: a healthy such a pumpkin lumpy. And the body's a fucking concentration camp, skin and bones. But that's what he figured out later, but at first, he said, "I see a mess of some kind: everything's upside down, covered with orange-red stuff - blood, like...". Those Hondurans didn't spare any ammunition. Do-olg...search for anomalous objects, geez...no fucking search!... He said it was a mixture of a colander and a torn heating pad.......and they obviously took a good walk on it in their shitpants; not an object, but a piece of meat in black rags. Anyway, he spent the rest of the night and half the morning hunching over. It seems that this is the same creature that the locals know as an illusionist: black rags, visions of stalkers, a meter-wide head... The funny thing about his face, those who saw it thought it was a kind of a face. No, he has a natural personality, but it's small: his blinkers don't open and his nose is like a pin, though his mouth is huge, like a joint at the gate. He walks around and hangs his head on his chest - he can't keep it straight... And guess what these things eat for lunch. Fungi! Mushrooms! In short, everyone has seen - the Zone is full of mushrooms, so "old people" give a tooth that these things squeeze juice out of them. You know what he had stashed in a pouch on his side? Well? Oh, come on! Anyway, his brains were jerky in there. You know whose? Controllers!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="stalker_story_3_name">
		<text>The pathologist's dinner.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="stalker_story_4">
		<text>There was a fool who joined us here... So, we're going to have a five-minute rest, and he immediately gets on his heel and relaxes. When he walks, he's the last one to get his ass off the ground. So he relaxed... he fell behind, and there's his controller - by his brains! - and it's done. Who is new to our business, remember. A rustle or a suspicious breeze... At least let a bunny run by... although bunnies here - God forbid... In a word, you have to be ready every second. To have magazines and grenades on hand and a machine gun on continuous. If you see something, plant half a horn at once; if there is something behind the bushes - also hit it, and then ask. This is a young fighter's course: they won't give you an outfit, they'll eat you up before you can fart! Yeah, about the controllers, that's a separate story. Let's say you shoot off on a rustle - and fall immediately, in the same second! On your back or whatever. The controller clings if he sees you - he needs to concentrate or something. While you're sunbathing in the shade, listen with both ears - whether there's a rustle, whether some crap is coming to you. You can quietly click the magazine, and grenades should also be prepared... In general, if everything is quiet, you count to three and... And off you go! Get the hell outta here! Did you suck it up? Eh, salazhata... Take care of yourself every second - that's the only way to survive here...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="stalker_story_4_name">
		<text>Easy controller extraction</text>
	</string>
	<string id="stalker_story_5">
		<text>I'm thinking... I'm not even thinking, I'm just speculating... What if everything here is an experiment on people? It's probably some kind of green men. Why? As good a version as any... I wonder: if this is some sort of testing ground, what exactly are they running around here? Checking to see which artifacts we drool over the most? Or are they bombs of some kind, huh? Sprouted them all over the world, in all kinds of laboratories, the rich have splurged... No, well, that's great!... That would be my pleasure! They bought some crap from under the table... A lot of money spent... Like "we have the best", envy, sheep... and it... it... fucks up...! Oh, great. Oh, I can't! Oh... ugh... And in general, of course, who the hell knows what's really going on... Unless the one who went for the radar can tell us about it... Well, yes, they may know, but they can't tell us - they're mooing and drooling. Maybe that's why they let me in... Eh... That's why all sorts of thoughts come to mind... It's not fun at all...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="stalker_story_5_name">
		<text>Pitfalls</text>
	</string>
	<string id="stalker_story_6">
		<text>So... I remember someone asked me something yesterday and I forgot... Oh, I remember. There are, then, curious, why in the Zone only our eggheads are swarming, and foreigners and do not show their noses, although there are three thousand Nobel Prize materials... So, I'll answer point by point. First of all, why should we meddle here, when we can give ours a grant, with such conditions that it will bring you everything you need on a platter? Well, secondly, they've actually been here, a lot. It's the last two years foreigners are afraid to go into the Zone... there was one big bummer with them. Now they're just buying up materials and information. The pay is pretty good, so a lot of loners work for them, and looters too... Didn't you hear about this story? Oh, come on! The whole Zone was on its ear, and you fell out of the sky. All in all, the reservation was a big one. There are thirty scientists from half the world... all the luminaries, of course, back and forth... We prepared in earnest: we had money to eat, equipment - mountains. We took with us a platoon of military specialists for protection, three of our guides, loaded onto shielded BATERs and set off. What-what... They came back a week later... twelve men in a junked-up BATER. They came to the barb at the Rotten Forest, and there they were already waiting... Looters... Yeah... They don't give a shit where people got out of... They put almost everyone down. Only three made it outside the perimeter, two of us and one egghead. The man from impressions moved powerfully attic... Well, he quickly by the scruff of the neck - and treat. He's writing a book about the Zone now. Ours is still okay - experience helped. Although... they probably moved in their own way too: one went to the radar and disappeared, and the other went to the Big Land. And the Zone took the rest. Have you heard of the Town of Thirty-Two? That's where they got caught. At first everything seemed quiet... well, within limits... They were shooting and measuring, collecting samples, poking at anomalies with instruments... And then they started going crazy. Mass. The people began to slowly roof ride. I our - the one who retired - told me... Who started tearing his throat with his nails, who smashed his head against the wall, and who simply - the barrel in his mouth, and... And then there's the beast. Whoever was in their right mind barricaded themselves in the house. You're imagining it, aren't you? Outside, it's night and all the neighborhood critters, and inside, people are going crazy one by one. In short, in the morning, those who could still think, somehow got out. We drove straight back, without a road; we even caught a couple of anomalies... Got to the Rotten Forest... And of those who stayed there, no one was ever found. Guys just say there's a dramatic increase in controllers in those places. Yes... Since then, no one has been coming to the Town of Thirty-Two, and you can't lure a foreigner to the Zone with a stick...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="stalker_story_6_name">
		<text>Chronicles of the egghead globalists.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="stalker_story_7">
		<text>So that's what I was gonna say. I was there when they took that illusion, I was there! I just happened to be in those parts! My car, my "Niva", the right front wheel flew off: the bolts sheared off on a bump. And there's zero parts. I swore a lot, and then I thought, let me go to the factory and pick up the right ones. Well, it was a kilometer walk there, back and forth - half an hour! And I've been there before... Suddenly I see Dutyers! Not just a patrol, a half a hundred of them! Well, I think it's a fucking compote. Just like that, he fell into the bushes. "If they notice and start searching," I think, "then I'm fucked. I'm lying in a hole, and I'm trying not to breathe. And there's a shooting! I've only heard that kind of gunfire once in my life... when they took First Base, the old guys, remember? Anyway, I'm lying there, listening in both ears... It's going bang, and then it's going bang!.. After about five minutes it gets quiet and nobody seems to be coming to me. Well, I got the nerve to stand up a little and look through the binoculars. And these quickly pull out of the shop... crumpled like this, dragging a bunch of their stiffs and illusa on a tarpaulin... There's nothing left of illus... They've gone into the ravine. Then I hear the engines roar and the sound goes away. I waited some more, I don't see anyone. I'm going in. Well, clearly, you can't find anything after Duty! But interesting! That was something, I'll tell you! They almost dug through the walls. Beams across the floor, a piece of the roof collapsed. Knee-deep in shell casings - a natural shooting range. Blood, some kind of debris. I didn't find anything useful, though - just two horns full and a machine gun lying there, crushed by the beam, impossible to pull out... I forgot about the bolts, of course... I went back to the car, thought for five minutes, took a bolt off the other wheels... and drove slowly... And if I had gone out there earlier for half an hour... Yeah...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="stalker_story_7_name">
		<text>The illusion of duty.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="stalker_story_8">
		<text>Yeah, that's how I got all the way to the outskirts of Pripyat. So I thought the first thing I'd do was look around. I also found a higher point - there was a big boiler house with a pipe. Well, I went in carefully... I look, everything seems to be in order - dust is lying, there are no traces... I got into the furnace and crawled: there were steps inside the pipe. I'm fine, even the soot is no longer dirty - it's petrified... Carefully sticking out... It's beautiful! Half the city in the palm of your hand! Pulling out my binoculars and looking around... (slight pause) And then... I was about to slide down, and then a thought popped up: what's going on under my very nose, and I didn't look! I bend a little over the edge, look at one side, then the other... Oh-oh! That would be a hit! There's a dwarf walking around the courtyard! I'm almost going down! It's okay that he can't see me yet. But I can't blow his turret off: the "kalash" hangs on my back, and the pipe is narrow, so I can't turn around. From the "Makarov" that is under my arm - a shitty business, there are fifty meters, and the difference in height... in short, if I don't hit at once - and I won't - then it's definitely dead. I'm sitting here thinking. I'm just checking to see what he's doing. And he's doing something he doesn't understand. At first, he was cheerfully, with fire, digging through a pile of junk - only pieces were flying left and right. And then all of a sudden he just stood there, frozen. I think I was listening. And then it got really messy. The trash in that pile started moving on its own. The dwarf quickly jumped back, stood like a pillar, put his hands to his head, turned his palms somehow cunningly... and into him ka-ak flying! All sides! Iron, bricks, roofing felt, branches... He was covered headfirst like that. Well, I guess that's it. Kitty's dead, he won't piss again... No way! For two seconds this junk was lying there, and then just like that, it splashed in all directions! There were some pipe scraps, so they stuck right into the concrete fence. Carla stood there for another half a minute, thought about something, and then turned around and went into the building. I took another minute to catch my breath. "Well," I think, "it's time to get out of here. And then all of a sudden there was a whiff of smoke. And then it started to get hot. Fuck you! Someone started a fire from downstairs! After a minute, I couldn't breathe. I shoveled myself out to the edge of the chimney - there's no platform there, I'm sitting with my legs hanging down... But the smoke still eats my eyes, there's not enough air... in short, we have to leave immediately! Thank God, I always carried forty meters of cord with me just in case of fire... I was sure that fire... Anyway, I folded it in half - it wasn't very thick - I fixed it on the pipe, torn my handkerchief in half, wrapped it around my shoelaces, and climbed up, praying to all gods... I had only one thought in my head: just don't fall off! No insurance, nothing, the cord cuts the palms of the hands... And, of course, by the law of meanness, five meters to the ground it was not enough. I had to jump. What can I do? Oh, I'm so screwed! I was lucky I didn't break anything... But I got skinned and pulled my right leg - big time! Then I thought I'd torn a ligament. And then yanked from there so that the gold medal in the race, probably would have won...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="stalker_story_8_name">
		<text>Gray's in Pripyat.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="stalker_story_9">
		<text>I couldn't believe my eyes at the time. I mean, there are some pretty girls out there, right? But this one was... she's... Perfect. Yeah. Here. Perfection. It felt like the world around her was black and white and blurry, she was alone in color and sharpness. How she moved! I've never seen that before either. I got a lump in my throat. She doesn't need that science! What's she gonna do here in the Zone? Yeah, in the Zone. It was towards evening. There's a separate nine-story building by the bus power plant. First something flashed in the window on the first floor. I quickly took off the safety of my AK, and then I saw him coming out of the entrance... I wanted to wipe my eyes - what can you expect from the Zone? And she fits. And I'm standing there like a fool, staring... I keep my automatic rifle ready, though - I'm used to it... Then she noticed me... She smiled... She said hello... And I'm listening and not hearing, looking at her. She was wearing a blue outfit, brightly colored... but not a halachon, but almost tight... Her figure is something fantastic! It was only then that I realized that I wasn't listening to what she was saying - I was standing there smiling ear to ear... She turned out to be from the research group. Asked if there was any way I could help her. Hey! I'd go into an anomaly for her. Said she was dealing with these, what's-her-name... endemics of the Zone. You know, plants that are only found here. Said she ran away from the guards because there's no leeway with them, and came here alone. I don't know. I believed it. I agreed to help her by bringing her something. Two days later, he came as agreed. Nearly broke five times while reassembling it. I'm walking, and I have only one thought in my head: I'm going to see her again! And nothing. I didn't even see the house where I met her. Here we go... But what a woman she was! I mean, she was glowing from the inside out.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="stalker_story_9_name">
		<text>Male loneliness.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="Stories">
		<text>Stories from the zone</text>
	</string>
</string_table>
