<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1251" ?>
<string_table>

	<string id="dm_action_info_0">
		<text>I'm sorry, I don't have time to chat right now.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="dm_action_info_1">
		<text>I’d rather wait until those handsome men in uniform go on their lunch break. No point hanging around here - I've got to get back to the Big Land, but they won’t let me through! I’m not the only one trying to get out, but none of us have managed to slip past yet.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_action_info_10">
		<text>There’s something nearby that the brass in shoulder straps are after. No one’s ever come this way before - everything was stripped clean, the cables cut long ago. And now, somehow, they’ve found it. I couldn’t even get close to the building. They spotted me and opened fire. Lucky for me it didn’t punch a hole right through.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_action_info_100">
		<text>I didn’t hear a thing - same story as always.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_action_info_11">
		<text>We’re putting together a team of people who don’t wet themselves at the thought of heading underground in the Zone. There’s an old factory with a maze of tunnels beneath it - word is, there’s all kinds of gear down there. Always something worth grabbing. Could be interesting.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_action_info_12">
		<text>Not new - old! They say this used to be Gunslinger’s main base. Makes you wonder... if we look hard enough, maybe we’ll find something he left behind.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_action_info_13">
		<text>I nearly got myself into trouble an hour ago. Six months back, this place was quiet - nothing but peace. Now it’s crawling with bandits in track pants hiding behind every bush. Unreal.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_action_info_14">
		<text>You're lucky, stalker - the bandits didn’t drag you in. Their base is just next door. If it were up to me, I’d take the place out myself. For now, though, we’re just keeping an eye on it. This is just an outpost - their main base is deeper in, closer to the center of the Zone.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_action_info_15">
		<text>They say there used to be a serious classified lab here. Uh-huh. Part of me wants to find the entrance - bet there’s a ton of valuable loot inside. But on the other hand… the place gives me the creeps.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_action_info_16">
		<text>Did you know that before the disaster, there was an underground research complex in what's now the Dark Valley? I don't know exactly what they were doing down there, but I doubt it was anything good. There are all kinds of stories about the place - most of them bad. Some downright terrifying.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_action_info_17">
		<text>Why? What do you want to hear? Fine, I’ll tell you something! Duty - sure, they act like the Zone’s police, and yeah, they know how to keep things under control, sure. But I don’t like them one bit. Always acting like they own everything - don’t take this, don’t touch that, don’t carry that out of the Zone... And now they’ve even decided what people can and can’t talk about back on the Big Land! They say they want to destroy the Zone, piece by piece. Well, that’s soldiers for you - dreamers, the lot of them, even if they used to wear real uniforms. And the worst part? Word is, they’ve got backing from the very top.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_action_info_18">
		<text>This territory is under Duty’s control now, and our rules are the only law that matters here. We guard the Zone’s borders and keep the hotheads in check. Every day, thrill-seekers and starry-eyed rookies roll in by the trainload, dreaming of adventure... and then they drop like flies before the sun even sets.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_action_info_19">
		<text>Have you ever been to our transshipment base? It’s not just ours - lots of people pass through. The best part is, it’s clean, safe from most of the Zone’s nastier surprises, and it’s where all the news flows in. You can always pick up something useful or just chat about life. Shame Baldy left with a group the day before yesterday - I missed him this time around.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_action_info_2">
		<text>Let’s head to the camp - you’ll hear all the latest rumors there. That’s where most rookies like you end up anyway, either to gain some experience or catch a breather. We’ve got soldiers nearby, so don’t worry too much - but don’t get careless either. They won’t hesitate to shoot if you make the wrong move. There’s a spot near the merchant, our local trader, where you can settle in and rest for a while.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_action_info_20">
		<text>This place is safe now, stalker - and we do our best to keep it that way. There's always a crowd around here. Some folks have settled in and never venture beyond the outskirts, while others are gearing up for their next raid. It's a shame Iroquois didn’t make it back - he had a knack for showing rookies like you the ropes, always talking about the “way of the truth.”</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_action_info_21">
		<text>Did you hear Duty's running a new recruitment drive? I considered it for a moment, but then thought - why the hell would I need that? Back on the front line every other day, strict discipline, constant orders... I’ve done my two tours already. That’s more than enough for me.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_action_info_22">
		<text>In case you haven’t heard - here’s the word: we’ve opened up additional recruitment. If you’ve got at least some experience under your belt, come on over. You won’t regret it.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_action_info_23">
		<text>I don’t know anything. Just keep moving.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_action_info_24">
		<text>Fuck off - I’m not supposed to talk to you!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_action_info_25">
		<text>Sorry, I’d rather not waste time on this conversation.</text>
	</string>



	<string id="dm_action_info_26">
		<text>They say if you catch some kind of illness in the Zone, it can drive you mad… You lose your sense of self entirely - and eventually, you just die.</text>
	</string>




	<string id="dm_action_info_27">
		<text>Damn, you ever hear about the stuff out here? Rabies and worse. It’s bad - real bad. If you catch it, you’re as good as dead.</text>
	</string>



	<string id="dm_action_info_28">
		<text>When a blowout hits Lake Yantar, all the equipment there goes haywire. If things go south, find cover - any shelter will do.</text>
	</string>



	<string id="dm_action_info_29">
		<text>Ever been to the swamps? They say there was some kind of massacre out there. It's dangerous - rumor has it the rain’s acidic, and the air’s filled with strange fumes...</text>
	</string>



	<string id="dm_action_info_3">
		<text>Shit, I'd love to get into that factory... word is, there are some pretty interesting documents stashed away in there.</text>
	</string>



	<string id="dm_action_info_30">
		<text>I heard there are some scientists running research down in the valley. They even hired one of our own for security. Haven’t heard from them in a while, though.</text>
	</string>




	<string id="dm_action_info_31">
		<text>Get out of here before nightfall! It's still daylight now, but once the sun sets...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_action_info_32">
		<text>Stalker, move out! We're taking down the cordon. We only hold it during the day - come nightfall, we’re gone. It’s too dangerous around here after dark.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_action_info_33">
		<text>You see, come nightfall, you’ve got to take cover - and make sure it’s behind something solid. Around here, it feels like we’re under siege once the sun goes down.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_action_info_34">
		<text>Well, buddy, looks like you haven’t heard the news - come nightfall, you’d better be bedding down far away from here. Even a grenade launcher won’t always save you when it gets dark!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_action_info_35">
		<text>You know what? Let Duty, Freedom, and all the looters fight over who owns this scrap - doesn’t matter to me. Fuck it.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_action_info_36">
		<text>We’re running things here now, stalker. There’s enough trouble out there already - now these outsiders are making our lives even harder...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_action_info_37">
		<text>Just a heads-up - this place isn’t safe even during the day. There’s some kind of conflict going on between the local gangs.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_action_info_38">
		<text>You tell me - this is our turf, right? Makes it easier for us to contain whatever crap comes crawling out of the Zone’s center. Let the eggheads poke around if they want, but Duty and those looters? They need to clear out.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_action_info_39">
		<text>Didn’t you hear? There’s a new route past the Duty patrols to the perimeter. From Yantar, cut through the thick brush to Agroprom - easy as that, and you're out with the loot.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_action_info_4">
		<text>Nothing, alright? I don’t know a damn thing! I’m just scraping by, trying to earn my daily bread. I’m too scared to go deep into the Zone - screw that place! And back home, there’s no work, and my wife’s always on my case... I’ve got to survive somehow, don’t I? Out here in the Garbage, if you walk around long enough, you can scavenge enough artifacts to afford food and a drink. That’s all I need.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_action_info_40">
		<text>What are you doing here? Heading to Yantar, or trying to sneak some artifacts past the Bar?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_action_info_41">
		<text>I won’t deny it - your fellow stalkers occasionally bring us some very curious anomalous formations… artifacts, as you call them. Given the loose control over these parts, this area has turned into quite the smuggling route.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_action_info_42">
		<text>Come on, man - we’ve carved out a path so you don’t have to bump into Duty patrols on your way to the Big Land! Yeah, they’re still around, sure. But as long as they don’t catch wind of it, we can steer clear of them.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_action_info_43">
		<text>I just got back from Yantar. Figured I’d sell some stuff to the scientists like usual - but they’ve holed up in their bunkers, won’t even come out during the day unless it’s to meet the next helicopter. So if you’re heading that way, keep your eyes open - you might end up missing your chance.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_action_info_44">
		<text>There’s ongoing research in the Yantar zone, but lately, too many people have turned up dead. That’s why we’re posted here - guarding the approaches.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_action_info_45">
		<text>I don’t know what to tell you. I was planning to head back to our complex - Yantar, you know the place. But now? They say if it was dangerous before, it’s completely impassable now. Maybe they’re exaggerating… but maybe not.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_action_info_46">
		<text>I’ve been to Yantar - science there is practically shut down. They’re scared, hiding, only surviving off what the helicopters bring in. Then again, there’s corpses everywhere. Spend a week living among the dead and fear stops meaning much. It’s a nice place. Just not a pretty one.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_action_info_47">
		<text>Fuck those dogs, always lurking with the dead! There’s more of them every day in this godforsaken complex - and they’re getting bigger, too.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_action_info_48">
		<text>We're doing our best to keep the dead from spreading beyond the lab complex. Honestly, we could use an extra hand - if you're up for it. We're running low on manpower.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_action_info_49">
		<text>You know, we’ve been conducting our own reconnaissance. I’ve been mapping the main movement routes of the quasi-living - what you’d call the dead. Care to share any observations of your own?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_action_info_5">
		<text>That’s just how it is. Some scavenge around the Garbage, picking up scraps, while others push deeper into the Zone. Sure, the rewards out there are richer - but not everyone dares. Rookies without experience don’t stand a chance, and without proper gear, it’s a one-way trip.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_action_info_50">
		<text>Have you ever had to shoot one of those dead things coming out of the lab? Look at them - they don’t feel pain, they’re not afraid of anything... it’s like there’s nothing left in their heads at all.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_action_info_51">
		<text>I'm gonna go get a job at the lab! ... Alright, relax, man - just joking. Once you’re in there, you’re done for. Best case? You die quick.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_action_info_52">
		<text>I'm warning you - don’t go into the lab. But hey, if you’re dead set on it, I won’t stop you. Just don’t expect to come back alive.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_action_info_53">
		<text>Listen, I need to warn you - you really shouldn’t go near the lab. No one should. What happens there causes severe, irreversible changes to both your mind and body.</text>
	</string>



	<string id="dm_action_info_54">
		<text>Whoa there! Let me enlighten you - save your poor, lost soul. Alright, listen up: don’t go skiing out to the center of the lake. It’s seriously messed up out there. People vanish, and sometimes... they come back. At night. But this isn’t some vampire tale - these are dead men’s stories. That’s just how it is.</text>
	</string>



	<string id="dm_action_info_55">
		<text>Have you seen those brainy types in their UN-blue gear? Lately, they’ve been spooked. They barely step off their base without bringing an entire regiment - APCs, helicopters, the whole show - just to guard them.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_action_info_56">
		<text>What’s it to you? Don’t bother them with dumb questions, and they won’t bother you either.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_action_info_57">
		<text>You see, we usually don’t leave the bunkers without proper security - conditions out here just don’t allow it. I’m something of an exception; I’m not a fan of big expeditions, all the commotion, or the military presence. But I’m afraid I don’t have anything useful to tell you just yet.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_action_info_58">
		<text>I'm in love with our quirky scientist - totally crazy about her, man! She almost never leaves her bunker, but when she does, like the other day… oh man! Troops everywhere, helicopters, armored vehicles - you’d think a damn battleship was about to roll in. Or at least an armored train!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_action_info_59">
		<text>I've been here three days, just watching. The lab’s right over there, yeah? No one’s really been inside since the start. Duty cleared out the bodies up top, but even they stopped going in. Now the scientists are heading in - must’ve figured out how to protect themselves from... something. I don’t know what. So I figured I’d look into it. Place like that’s bound to be full of loot.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_action_info_6">
		<text>Lately, the beasts have been pouring out of the Dark Valley in packs. I don’t know what’s driving them, but they’re scattering like there’s a fire behind them. And over in the eastern sector, mutants are crawling around like bedbugs - we barely have time to shoot them. That’s the situation.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_action_info_60">
		<text>What are you after? Heading to the lab too? Let me guess - you heard the story about miracle devices and scattered artifacts? Damn... When are you people gonna learn to let it go?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_action_info_61">
		<text>I work here, young man - just doing my job, serving science and humanity. And as for that abandoned lab, the one every stalker assumes I know all about - I'll tell you this: I don’t know, and I don’t want to know! I’ve never been interested in that place, and I intend to keep it that way. Understood?!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_action_info_62">
		<text>Maybe the scientists came up with some kind of device - who knows? I wonder what’s really hidden in that lab. Even if there’s nothing valuable, it’s still fascinating!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_action_info_63">
		<text>Thinking of joining Freedom? Why not? They seem like smart people - and if they’re a bit laid-back, all the better! I don’t need someone barking orders at me. I know what I’m doing - I’ve been out here for months...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_action_info_64">
		<text>I saw an old man on the hills - he's got a huge dog. What's he doing there?</text>
	</string>


	<string id="dm_action_info_65">
		<text>I was talking to a Dutyer the other day. Smart guy - but narrow-minded, like a tank. See, we’ve got different philosophies. The Zone isn’t something you destroy - it has to be understood, tamed, assimilated. And for that, we need open access to information. Sooner or later, someone will figure something out, something useful. But them? They restrict, forbid, cover everything up... Bunch of bastards, honestly. Then again, I get it - when you’ve got the whole state machine backing you, thinking for yourself isn’t exactly required.</text>
	</string>


	<string id="dm_action_info_66">
		<text>There’s a little hamlet nearby - used to be quiet, but now something nasty’s stirred up. Best to steer clear. That’s why I’m taking the long way around... Just saying - you’ve been warned.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_action_info_67">
		<text>You there, stalker - let me warn you right off. That village? Bloodsuckers settled there a long time ago... maybe something even worse. So watch yourself if you go there.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_action_info_68">
		<text>What’s new? Nothing much - no artifacts around here for a long time. Those houses over there used to be crawling with bloodsuckers; we cleared them out as best we could. Now I’m stuck here, and I just... can’t bring myself to go back. Maybe it’s intuition, maybe something else. But I won’t go. It’s dead out there.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_action_info_69">
		<text>I’m getting the hell out of here. Four weeks on the barrier is enough - I’m done. The Woodpecker’s been active around the clock, and it’s getting more aggressive by the day.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_action_info_7">
		<text>These days, a lot of people are turning into garbage pickers. Back then, no one even glanced at the piles - radiation strong enough to boil your balls in thirty minutes. But now that loot’s scarce, they suit up, pop some anti-radiation chems, and dive in. There’s plenty to find, though it’s mostly just scraps.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_action_info_70">
		<text>If you're coming with us, I respect that. If not - then stay out of the way. We need real men, not dead weight. Got enough of that already.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_action_info_71">
		<text>You're posted at the roadblock, huh? Good - nice to have another solid person around. We set this place up and held it together pretty well... until the beasts showed up. It's rough now. We need every gun we can get!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_action_info_72">
		<text>Keep your eyes open, bro - radiation and fanatics are everywhere. Now let’s get on with it.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_action_info_73">
		<text>You should’ve waited, stalker. Always chasing after everyone... Tell me something - do you even know what’s in there? Exactly, you don’t. You don’t know if there’s food, or what kind of traps are waiting. So why are you all rushing in like a herd of elk?!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_action_info_74">
		<text>The path to the center is open, got it?! We’re heading straight in. Now everyone’s going to flood in behind us. The key is to be among the first - grab the best loot while there’s still something left to squeeze.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_action_info_75">
		<text>Go on, see for yourself! Don’t you want to know what’s really going on down there? If not... well, maybe you’re just scared. There’s got to be something big! You’ve heard of the Wish Granter, right?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_action_info_76">
		<text>They’re like kids, for God’s sake - chasing after the Wish Granter, dreaming of some artifact Klondike.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_action_info_77">
		<text>I just want to see what’s beyond the horizon, man. Maybe, just maybe, we’ll find some kind of answer to all this madness they call the Zone.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_action_info_78">
		<text>Have you seen the high-rises? That’s Pripyat. Just beyond it is the power plant. I’d love to get there someday... but who knows what’s lurking in those buildings now.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_action_info_79">
		<text>Let me break it down for you: that’s Pripyat. Beyond it lies Chernobyl. We don’t know what’s happening there - or who might be living there now. But this is our place. We’ll dig something up to scavenge, like always.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_action_info_8">
		<text>I don’t know, man! I’m just heading to the bar to meet some people. You’ve never been there? Seriously? Alright, listen - just head straight north from here. You won’t get far before you stumble right into it. It’s a solid place, especially for a rookie like you - it’s like a check-up with the doctor. Plenty of seasoned stalkers hang around there; they’ll set you straight. Only catch is, Duty patrols that stretch. Whether they let you through or give you grief... well, that’s up to them.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_action_info_80">
		<text>Pripyat! Shit, pinch me - finally made it! Just a short walk from here to the power plant. But who knows what you’ll run into now... what kind of beast might be lurking, sharpening its teeth just for you.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_action_info_81">
		<text>Hey, buddy, tell me something - do you hear that voice too, or am I the only one losing it? It just keeps talking... and talking... won't shut up.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_action_info_82">
		<text>Damn it, another one... Alright, listen up - for the tenth time, I’m explaining this. People around here are hit with some kind of telepathic influence. Voices, ones you can’t hear from the outside, keep calling them toward the center of the Zone. They promise to grant any wish to whoever manages to reach and touch... something. Yeah - that’s right. Some kind of Monolith.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="dm_action_info_83">
		<text>You hear that voice too? Pretty wild - like a record spinning in your head. Shame it’s stuck on the same damn track: “Come to me and you’ll be happy.” Been repeating it for two hours straight...</text>
	</string>

	<string id="dm_action_info_84">
		<text>Can’t you figure it out? You’re heading to the power plant - same as us! What else is there to say? If only we could clear out those possessed bastards blocking the way...</text>
	</string>


	<string id="dm_action_info_85">
		<text>The power plant’s just next door, what does that tell you?</text>
	</string>


	<string id="dm_action_info_86">
		<text>There it is - the ChNPP, just a stone's throw away. It's all that's left. But those bastards are dug in tight; they won't let us through. That's fine... we'll deal with them.</text>
	</string>


	<string id="dm_action_info_9">
		<text>Listen, friend - don’t you know anything about Agroprom? I thought about heading there myself, but people just laughed. Said the place’s gone to hell, stripped bare ages ago - only anomalies left now. I don’t know if they’re serious or just messing with me. I’m new here, so when the locals talk, I tend to believe them... but maybe they’re just having a laugh. Bastards.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_action_info_94">
		<text>Wait up! Move quickly, but don’t rush blindly! There are Monolith freaks around here - they know the city like the back of their hand and they’ve set up ambushes. Watch your step!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_action_info_95">
		<text>I'm warning you - most of the city’s still under Monolith control. They've set up ambushes all over and know every corner of this place. Keep your eyes sharp and your weapon ready.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_action_info_96">
		<text>What I’d really love is to carpet bomb this whole damn town. Bastards are everywhere - unless they’re hiding in sandboxes or flowerpots. People have already died because of those assholes!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_action_info_97">
		<text>Look, I don’t know what the hell this Monolith really is. Maybe it’s not eternal - maybe there’s not enough to go around. So what are we supposed to do, just wait around on all fours? If we make it there, I promise - you’ll be right behind me.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_action_info_98">
		<text>Duty has to break through to the center - if not first, then at least among the first! Just think about it, stalker: what if some lunatic - because let’s face it, most of you are half-crazy, paranoid, or downright brain-dead - gets their hands on something that really can grant any wish? Huh? Then what?!</text>
	</string>

	<string id="dm_action_info_99">
		<text>I don't feel like talking.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="dm_action_info_101">
		<text>Oh, nothing much. I'm just trying to survive and make a living.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_action_info_102">
		<text>I'm building up experience and saving every bit of money I can. Once I’ve got enough, I’ll get myself a proper gun, decent armor - and then I’m heading straight for the center of the Zone.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_action_info_103">
		<text>The Zone drew me in. I came here by accident - like some kind of illegal excursion - and before I knew it, I was hooked. The people here are real, whether they're friends or enemies. And the danger... that constant sense of death lurking close? It makes you feel truly alive. Makes you appreciate every moment you've got.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_action_info_104">
		<text>I'm resting up after my last raid. Made it almost all the way to the Barrier - we set up a line of defense against all the hell that spills out of the center. A good crew came together for it - Sanya Shaggy, Lyokha Koresh, Maldi... all decent guys, real solid. I scored some good loot too, sold it to the dealer, and figured I’d catch my breath here for a while. It’s calmer here than deep in the Zone. Easier, you know?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_action_info_105">
		<text>You’re asking me that?! It’s because of people like you that we’re stuck out here. What do you all see in this damn Zone? You come in droves, die off like flies, and still more of you keep coming! And now you're asking me what I'm doing here? I should be asking you what the hell you're doing here. Whatever - I've got no time for this. Just get lost!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_action_info_106">
		<text>Military secrets!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_action_info_107">
		<text>It's nothing, really. It's nothing.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_action_info_108">
		<text>I'm just taking in the beauty of this place. It’s nothing like the outside world. You might not agree, but I think people either can’t - or won’t - find a common language with nature. And in the end, their actions hurt her. Still, in her own way, she tries to send them a signal... but they just keep ignoring it. Uh-huh.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_action_info_109">
		<text>It's none of your business!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_action_info_110">
		<text>Never mind...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_action_info_111">
		<text>What business is it of yours?!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_action_info_112">
		<text>Ever since I was a kid, I’ve been drawn to unexplored places. So when I first heard about the Zone, I came without hesitation. And honestly? It’s the most extraordinary place I’ve ever seen.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_action_info_113">
		<text>I’m fulfilling my duty to humanity - and that’s not just some grand phrase, it’s the truth. Saving them from what? From the Zone and everything it creates. We have to wipe out this breeding ground of evil and infection before it wipes us out!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_action_info_114">
		<text>I recently joined Duty, and I’m loving it. The guys here are the real deal - disciplined, reliable. You always know what needs to be done and who’s in charge.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_action_info_115">
		<text>I’ve got a lot of friends in Duty, so I decided to join up. Took me a few months to finally make the call - and now I look back and think, “What was I so worried about?” It’s great here. A hell of a lot safer than roaming the Zone alone.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_action_info_116">
		<text>Well, there’s not much to do in the Zone, really - hunt for loot, fight, uncover its secrets... and then make sure everyone has equal access to what’s found. That’s what I keep busy with, day in and day out.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_action_info_117">
		<text>Dude, I’m protecting the Zone from the government. We can’t let them take control - if they do, it’ll all go to hell, and we’re as good as dead!</text>
	</string>




	<string id="dm_cool_info_0">
		<text>You don't want to head into the Garbage - too much wildlife out there. It’s like a crossroads of the Zone; you could run into just about anything.</text>
	</string>






	<string id="dm_cool_info_1">
		<text>Rumor has it that various special services are recruiting stalkers for their own ends. Wouldn’t be surprised if every other stalker out here is on someone’s payroll - from one intelligence agency or another.</text>
	</string>



	<string id="dm_cool_info_10">
		<text>They say artifacts hold the very power of anomalies - and some can even create new ones. But once they do, they lose their value. The anomalies they produce don’t last long, and they’re usually weak.</text>
	</string>



	<string id="dm_cool_info_100">
		<text>I haven't heard anything like that, sorry.</text>
	</string>



	<string id="dm_cool_info_11">
		<text>I saw a guy hanging around the bar - gray as mold, like something rotten. Gave me the creeps.</text>
	</string>



	<string id="dm_cool_info_12">
		<text>A springboard is an anomaly - like a whirligig - that forms between similar objects, like trees. Walk between them, and it'll tear you apart... half to each tree.</text>
	</string>




	<string id="dm_cool_info_13">
		<text>There are places in the Zone where a new kind of anomaly might exist - ones that transform any creature caught in them within seconds. These mutations aren't usually fatal. Sometimes, if a person wanders in, they might even retain a shred of their sanity - though not for long. That’s how rumors of strange, never-before-seen mutants start. But they don’t last. Not once an armed stalker spots them.</text>
	</string>



	<string id="dm_cool_info_14">
		<text>You ever hear of the Killers? They’re not after artifacts - they hunt stalkers. Track them down and carry out contracts. Cold, precise, and deadly.</text>
	</string>



	<string id="dm_cool_info_15">
		<text>If you're bringing up the same crap that’s been pissing me off for the past two days, then go to hell! If I knew - and it wasn’t classified - I’d tell you! But I don’t know a damn thing! What did the scientists discover? Where did command disappear to? How the hell should I know? The guy’s on leave, not like he owes us any explanations!</text>
	</string>




	<string id="dm_cool_info_16">
		<text>There's something called induced fields - anomalies that aren’t exactly where the instruments say they are. Some claim it's a kind of distortion, maybe even a defense mechanism. That’s why, deep in the Zone, stalkers trust their instincts and eyesight more than any gadget.</text>
	</string>




	<string id="dm_cool_info_17">
		<text>They say some mutants can do more than just control you - they can mess with your mind, make you see things. One moment you're walking a flat road, the next you're falling off a cliff. Or worse, you start shooting at people who aren't even there.</text>
	</string>





	<string id="dm_cool_info_18">
		<text>Legend. They say it’s a small group of stalkers who’ve somehow learned to communicate with the monsters. You almost never see them outside the Zone - their base is supposedly deep in the center. Rumor has it they possess unimaginable riches, with the mutants themselves helping them hunt for artifacts. Word is, Duty knows about them and wants them wiped out, but officially? They just say it’s all fairy tales.</text>
	</string>






	<string id="dm_cool_info_19">
		<text>They say military stalkers are equipped with monster detectors - able to spot any creature within 200 meters. That’s why they move through the Zone so safely.</text>
	</string>






	<string id="dm_cool_info_2">
		<text>I don’t know if you’ve heard, but there’s a group of military stalkers called Intercept. They’re an elite special unit operating deep within the Zone. They’ve got multiple hideouts, a supply chain that still works - helicopters drop off gear now and then. The unit is led by Major Gromov, better known as Grom. No one really knows what their goals are. They operate with total autonomy, shifting policies on the fly. Sometimes they work with stalkers, but more often they shoot first. What they’re really after - no one can say.</text>
	</string>





	<string id="dm_cool_info_20">
		<text>There’s been a large expedition spotted in the Zone - officially, they’re UN environmentalists. In reality, it’s a U.S. military-scientific task force. Their goals aren’t clear, but a few things stand out. For one, they didn’t bring a single local guide. That either means they have their own sources of intel on the Zone... or their mission is so classified that even having outsiders around in a supporting role is unacceptable.</text>
	</string>




	<string id="dm_cool_info_21">
		<text>They say there’s a group of stalkers people call shamans—sometimes druids. They never carry electronic gear, as if trying to stay closer to nature. According to them, the Zone reacts more aggressively to electronics - its radiation, they claim, draws anomalies and mutants toward you. They believe the Zone is a living organism and shouldn’t be disturbed by devices, insisting that a person is already well-equipped by nature to survive here without extra tech. Of course, they still carry assault rifles. Guess they don’t have teeth and claws to rip enemies apart, no matter how “tough” they are. Strangely enough, they don’t seem to die in the Zone nearly as often as you’d expect. So maybe they’re onto something. I’ve never met any of these druids myself, they say they usually enter the Zone from the Belarus side.</text>
	</string>





	<string id="dm_cool_info_22">
		<text>It's a strange day today. Global bad luck is magically replaced by incredible good luck. It's a strange place I've come across. Weird.
...It all started yesterday, when out of the bushes and foggy evening gloom the silhouette of a large wooden house with a sagging roof in several places appeared in front of me. It looked like it used to be a village school and then some kind of hospital. It looked like a dead dragon. And where there's a dragon, there's gold," a misplaced thought popped into my head. Cheering myself up thus, I went in through the sprawling, rotten door. The dining room. Another unfamiliar odor pierced among the usual pile of rottenness and desolation. I redouble my caution, carefully inspecting every corner.(start here for your second session on 8/9/25 and don't forget to remove this reminder when you start)
And I fall. I fall very unpleasantly, on my sore leg. A couple minutes later, I come to my senses. As it happens, I've fallen into the basement. But. How could I not have noticed a hole two meters by one and a half meters in the floor? Fantastic bad luck. It's time to get out, though my leg hurts like hell, and I hit my head pretty hard. I managed to get to the ladder to the top. I crawl up and I can't believe it! At the top of the stairs, there's a KPPU! A universal first aid kit! Only military and special forces are equipped with such complexes. Finding such a thing in the Zone is like finding a thirsty source in the desert. I'm falling in. A few injections and it's almost fine: fatigue and bad mood have disappeared, and I can use my leg almost freely. In general, we can live. Let's move on.
Second floor. I step carefully: the steps and the wooden floor can hardly hold me. Out of the corner of my eye I notice a glint at the end of the corridor. I approach slowly. A door. What could be shining here? I don't see anything. I try to open the door: it yields, but with difficulty. I push harder. It moves a little more, like it's being held by a powerful spring. I slung my automatic behind my back and put my whole body on it. The door felt like lead, I only moved it a couple of centimeters! What the hell is this? I put my feet on the jamb and pressed as hard as I could. It's yielding, bitch! It's like someone let go of the door and I hit the floor. I lay there, cursing the door, resting. I just tried to get up, and it slammed! I flew two meters to the opposite wall of the corridor. That's it, I've had enough! I put a line into the door: splinters flew, slanting and dusty rays of sunlight broke through the holes. I even admired it, even though my rage was off the scale. I kicked open the door, and fell into the room, a former classroom now filled with broken beds. I look around. There's a body lying in the aisle between the beds. A military stalker. Ex. A long time ago, already well rotted. I was a bit stunned to see such a thing. The soldier was fully equipped (I had already calculated the value of all this stuff). There were a couple of questions. Not even a couple, but three. How did he end up here alone? Why had he left the first aid kit downstairs? And finally, the main one. Who killed you, you sick bastard?

Weird day today. Global bad luck magically turns into incredible good luck. Very strange. But you gotta take it while it's good. And run while it's still quiet. I bend over the corpse. His eyes are open, it's like he's looking at me. No, he's looking at me! Quietly turns his head in my direction. I hit him with the butt of my gun. The machine gun flies through the body as if it doesn't exist and crashes to the floor with all its might. I lose my balance and fall on my side. What's going on? The wreckage of the beds stirred and began to shift. I'm going to get hit! What the hell...

... It burst like a liquid balloon. Filled the whole room with his juice. So funny in its will to live - it scratches at the rusty bars that pierced it, wheezes something. Well, the day wasn't wasted - it was amusing to watch this miserable lump of flesh come here for its own filthy greed. Well, what he came with, he died with. It's a kind of justice, too.
</text>
	</string>







	<string id="dm_cool_info_23">
		<text>The Zone attracts people like a giant magnet. Or like a pile of shit - flies, or whatever you like.</text>
	</string>






	<string id="dm_cool_info_24">
		<text>Some say the Zone is alive and even intelligent. Someone - that the Zone is the spawn of the sins of Mankind and hell on Earth. Somebody starts talking nonsense about alien experiments. I don't know.</text>
	</string>




	<string id="dm_cool_info_25">
		<text>In my opinion, the Zone is neither alive, much less intelligent. It's a place with its own laws, that's all. An alternate biosphere. And it's just like in nature: If you break the law, you die. Just like that, without emotion. And all these miracles, higher minds, universal conspiracies - well, people need to believe in something. And it is not for me to dissuade them, especially since they are my best clients.</text>
	</string>





	<string id="dm_cool_info_26">
		<text>Some come here out of curiosity, some for exoticism, but most come for money. And I'm one of them. Usually, the first and second ones leave here, and very quickly. The third - according to circumstances.</text>
	</string>






	<string id="dm_cool_info_27">
		<text>I can't understand why many and many people consider the Zone a scary place? I totally disagree. It's like a return to nature. First man corrupted nature, took its wealth, violated its laws. And now nature is taking its course. Rips up man's creations, accumulates new wealth and changes the laws. There is no place on Earth more interesting! And more beautiful.</text>
	</string>




	<string id="dm_cool_info_28">
		<text>Nowadays, everyone is his own craftsman. So they do what they want.
What was it like in the old days? Experts were respected, people came for advice. And there were more of us
more of us. And now what? It's just me and Semyon the gunsmith and a bunch of small cops, 
who, to be honest, don't have a clue. They're putting optics on a gun. What an idea.
I remember when there used to be more unique weapons. Not the kind that could twist seven barrels into one, but guns with a deeper meaning.
I'm sure you've heard the stories about the self-defeating shotgun. Well, I've held this shooting complex myself.
 First of all, it's not a shotgun. It's an FN2000-based rifle system. But the only things left from the base are the trigger mechanism (and that has been remodeled), the barrel, and the grenade launcher. The case, electronics, optics - everything was redesigned. The essence of these modifications... Roughly speaking, the Optical Targeting System was taken, the one that our soldiers can't bring to their senses lately. And refined it. How Micah managed to cram it into such a compact case, and with good protection against interference - I can't imagine. He was such a master. And the main thing. On the basis of this compact OSC (control element), he built in an automatic firing system. That's so simple and ingenious! You set the firing mode, point it at the target, it automatically opens fire. He called it a self-timer. When we tested it, I was amazed. Target engagement is almost one hundred percent, no malfunctioning of the sight when pulling the trigger, not to mention saving ammunition! Just aim carefully and don't forget to reload in time. Yes, and in the disconnected state, the complex works with ordinary optics, no inconvenience.
Micah gave it to Black. Black wasn't the last master either, even though he was a stalker. Half a year ago, he died in the Zone. Eternal memory. So the Zone got his self-breaker. That's where we should look. And to make a second one. Think about it. Militaries put such EWS on helicopters, and even then, without a hundred percent guarantee of triggering. No, it won't work. If we could find the prototype itself, and dig in properly... 
Uh-huh.</text>
	</string>



	<string id="dm_cool_info_29">
		<text>There was a fool here - he was relaxing on his heel until his controller took him to the Zone.
Remember dukhman... Shorah there or a strange movement - you do not care. Calmly drop the horn on the firing sector, hit the bushes and trees. Switch to continuous.  This ain't no training school! They'll eat you up before you can fart!  
So you shoot the Horn and fall behind cover on your back. If the controller can see you, he has to focus on the victim. While you're sunbathing on your back, you flip the mate and put the Kalash on short bursts. You pop a round, count to three, and jerk... get the hell outta here! 
Suck it up?! You suckers. If you're like me, you'll live to see the end of your life. before you're discharged.</text>
	</string>





	<string id="dm_cool_info_3">
		<text>Have you heard anything about the Saint? They say he comes out of his hideout at night, somewhere on Radar, and wanders around Bar... you know?</text>
	</string>




	<string id="dm_cool_info_30">
		<text>You ever seen a kid's footprints here in the zone? Fresh ones! Sometimes you can get a little freaked out by what goes on here.</text>
	</string>




	<string id="dm_cool_info_31">
		<text>Scientists are sniffing around. I don't know what secret they've dug up, but the military's got their tails in a twist. They're already poking around Agroprom and Dark Valley, searching and searching...</text>
	</string>



	<string id="dm_cool_info_32">
		<text>There's more and more shit coming out of the city every day, and Duty and Freedom are going on another raid. How long can we hold this barrier alone?</text>
	</string>




	<string id="dm_cool_info_33">
		<text>The mutants are trying harder and harder to get past the barrier. It's been tough lately! If some of them would stop being so stupid, we'd take them down easy!</text>
	</string>




	<string id="dm_cool_info_34">
		<text>Anecdote. Stalker decided not to drink vodka anymore. Walked around the Zone, walked, tired, sat down on a stump to rest.
Okay - just get the bottle, I will not open it, just look at it.
Alright, alright, I'll open the bottle, but I won't pour it into the glass.
No, I'll pour it, I'll pour it into the glass, but I won't drink it, I definitely won't.
I'll just put the vodka in my mouth, but I won't swallow it, I'll just hold it in my mouth. That's all.
No, you can't do that, you have to take a sip. Just one sip.
I took a sip. Pour more, take a sip. Another...
I didn't want to drink, but I did! Quit drinking here, damn Controllers!!!! Stalker was upset...
</text>
	</string>





	<string id="dm_cool_info_35">
		<text>An anecdote remembered. Comes experienced Stalker to the young:
-Hi, let's go to the Zone, the monsters hunt monsters, from anomalies to turn away from anomalies, artifact search!
-Yeah, I don't know how to do it yet...
-What is there to know - pour and drink!!! - shared his experience Stalker...
</text>
	</string>




	<string id="dm_cool_info_36">
		<text>If you want to earn money - at the entrance to the bar, or at the scientists' bunker on Yantar there are bulletin boards, there are all sorts of ads about work. You can make a lot of money if you put your mind to it...</text>
	</string>




	<string id="dm_cool_info_37">
		<text>There was a fool here, relaxing on his heel until his controller took him to the Zone.
Remember, Dukhmans... You don't care if there's a shock or a strange movement. Calmly drop the horn on the firing sector, hit the bushes and trees. Switch to continuous.  This ain't no training school! They'll eat you up before you can fart!  
So you shoot the Horn and fall behind cover on your back. If the controller can see you, he has to focus on the victim. While you're sunbathing on your back, you flip the mate and put the Kalash on short bursts. You pop a round, count to three, and jerk... get the hell outta here! 
Suck it up?! You suckers. If you're like me, you'll live to see your demob.
</text>
	</string>




	<string id="dm_cool_info_38">
		<text>What's the news? We're sitting here, the beasts come at us, we shoot them off, and then they come again, only even stronger. There's been a few military choppers around. and it looks like they even flew over the Woodpecker.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_cool_info_39">
		<text>What's new here? same old, same old. Mutants, anomalies. Although, the military's been flying around in choppers. So at least once on the beast - no, nothing...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_cool_info_4">
		<text>New. What do they say? You can't believe it all, you won't have enough faith. Here, they say, some experienced stalker came from the inner regions, brought something unprecedented, made a lot of money... I can think of a hundred stories like that myself!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_cool_info_40">
		<text>I've seen military choppers! Imagine, they passed over us, and behind Woodpecker - one! Well, I think they'll get hit now! No shit, they went on, circled there, and went back the same way. That's a normal move, huh?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_cool_info_41">
		<text>Eh, the center of the zone is very close... There must be a lot of riches lying around out there.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_cool_info_42">
		<text>Now, as it became possible to pass relatively quietly to the center of the Zone, the stalkers flew there like flies to honey! Yeah. Greed is not the best human quality after all.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_cool_info_43">
		<text>What a life we're living! By the time all those from the bar and the perimeter get here, we'll have the cream of the crop. We'll pick up the good stuff and let the others do the small stuff.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_cool_info_44">
		<text>They say it really exists, the Black Monolith. Somebody's already gotten to it and made a big wish for it.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_cool_info_45">
		<text>Listen, buddy! I know things happen in the Zone. I've seen it. But these stories about instant monolithians are bullshit and nothing more!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_cool_info_46">
		<text>Don't you know that? Two of our guys, the ones who were the first to get to the center, made it to the monolith and made a wish. They dreamed of islands in the warm sea all their lives, so now they're sunbathing somewhere in the tropics, no other way!</text>
	</string>


	<string id="dm_cool_info_47">
		<text>I go to the peddler, and he says: until you pay off your debt, I'll keep your AK.
Fucking asshole! How can I work off my debt without a gun? Am I going into the zone with a bare ass? But I took a couple of TT's, some smokes, food for a week and went. Last raid, a guy showed me where an abandoned research institute was, but he scared me so much that I shouldn't go there. But if it's a research institute, there must be a lot of stuff there, right? So I went.
... to the site. The woods come right up to the fence, very convenient. I cross over, and beyond the fence, the yard is strangely clean. I cautiously approach the door, turn the knob...
... Damn stairs! What idiot designed this research institute? Nothing but stairs, corridors, passages. A couple more flights of stairs and I'll die. Good thing I thought to bring a kapron cord, I've already unwound 300 meters. What the hell is that door? Ugh, I'm on the roof! Well, what's that lying there? (Here the guy stopped talking, swallowed convulsively. I asked again: "Well, what was lying there?")
- An AK with a double horn. I remember I was terribly happy, even jumping for joy that I wouldn't have to pay back my debt. 
- And was it only an AK?
- No, not only.
...I saw a package lying nearby. Something big wrapped in roofing felt. I started to unwrap it, stupid me, and as soon as I unwrapped it, it turned me inside out! I wondered why there was such a sweet-smelling smell here. It was a corpse! Not even a corpse, but a real dismemberment. The body was almost cut into pieces, the skull was cut open... I got off the roof quickly, yanked back up the ladders, thanks to the cord, I ran to the door to the yard... And there's no door! That is, I can see it, but I feel the wall with my hand! Then I remembered, thank God, that at first the door seemed to be in another place, I started to fumble around, OPAH! There it is, the door! I find the handle, I open it... And there is not a courtyard, but a sea of some toothy tentacles swaying, the closest ones are also reaching out to me. It's disgusting! If I hadn't drained the starch on the roof, I'd have died here for sure. And then, like an epiphany! I looked closely at these tentacles - something's wrong. There's no shadow! The sun is hot, but there's no shadow! I realized it was a trick, an optical illusion. I gathered my courage, I thought I was going to die, so I rushed outside. But I didn't see the threshold because of my tentacles, I got caught. And the yard was covered with asphalt. Anyway, the result is on my face. I was still running through the woods, I almost fell into a mosquito's head, but I got out...
That's the story. Maybe the guy's lying. He was drunk as a pig, and he wanted to get to know the road. I checked it out, though. He did owe the dealer, and after that story, he got loose.
</text>
	</string>




	<string id="dm_cool_info_48">
		<text>One of Sin's squads was found in a previously inaccessible area. How did they manage to get through unscathed and then survive here for weeks? It just doesn't make any sense! Looks like we underestimated these guys.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_cool_info_49">
		<text>Hey, we found our Miklouha! Alive, and the guys he was with survived, too. We got past Woodpecker, and then we were here for a month, couldn't get out.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_cool_info_5">
		<text>There's something fishy brewing here. Rumors are going around that the Duty commander, a big shot, not just on some business from the Zone, but with the freedom fighters to negotiate. Well, they would have made peace in the open, but they've made a mess of things! This case smells bad, that's how it is. On the other hand, old men say they started fighting for a bad reason. I don't think they'll drag us all into some new meat grinder, those office freaks from the Big Land...!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_cool_info_50">
		<text>Did you hear that? The military's on a roll, they'll be here in a minute! They found out that Woodpecker's dead, they want to grab all the stuff at once!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_cool_info_51">
		<text>They just got word! The army is planning a large-scale landing on the power plant. My advice! If you want to grab some of the loot, hurry up!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_cool_info_52">
		<text>It's a total mess! Just when the corridor opened, the power plant started to be cleaned of all kinds of shit, and now the military are here! You have no shame, no conscience!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_cool_info_53">
		<text>What I don't understand is this. How could the freedom fighters hold out here for a month? Did they wear invisible hats? It's a hell of a place.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_cool_info_54">
		<text>Do you understand what's going on here? No, I respect Miklouha even more now. What's up with that? Four weeks and more to endure, and not to lose any of the guys!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_cool_info_55">
		<text>Some of us have lost our minds. They were always tough guys, but now they're drooling. It's scary!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_cool_info_56">
		<text>As we get closer to the power plant, the unknown telepathic influence intensifies. Some are starting to go crazy, others are having disturbances and visions. Maybe now would be a good time to back up a bit.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_cool_info_57">
		<text>Look, people are really freaking out here. Someone sees a pebble and suddenly starts yelling that it's his fucking artifact, that he was the first one to see it, and the rest of us can go south. Another Jar on a cloud shows up with his partners, who disappeared a few years ago... No, there's something sick going on here!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_cool_info_6">
		<text>The military's doing something. Searching, digging. Before, only choppers flew to Yantar - to protect scientists, supplies and equipment. But now there's an invasion! They've started organizing raids, riding on APCs. We've already seen them on Agroprom, in the Dark Valley, again. I don't know.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_cool_info_7">
		<text>Somebody tried to get through Woodpecker again. Well, that's the end of it, of course, and that's the end of the man. You ain't heard of Woodpecker? Oh, come on, man! It's the biggest hell in the whole neighborhood! The only trouble is, the horror stories about it are mostly true.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_cool_info_8">
		<text>Besides bandits, the military has started to come here too. Before, once in a hundred years you'd see a helicopter, but now they're almost all over the Zone. Did they lose something or something?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_cool_info_9">
		<text>I want to warn you, stalker. The military has gone crazy around here lately! They used to guard the scientists quietly and peacefully, but now it's as if someone has tipped their tails! They're running around. Your brother's been shelled more than once, and we've had two wounded this week.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_help_thanks_1">
		<text>Thank you very much.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_intro_0">
		<text>Don't bully the soldiers, you'll get a bullet in no time. And any of our guys who are around here might get hurt.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_intro_1">
		<text>I see you don't know your way around here yet, so I'm warning you in a neighborly way! Don't mess with the military. If you see them, get the hell out of here, because they've got no brains. They'll shoot you first, and then they'll look at your papers.</text>
	</string>



	<string id="dm_intro_10">
		<text>Dutyers run this place. Keep it in mind, so you don't get in trouble.</text>
	</string>




	<string id="dm_intro_100">
		<text>Good day, stalker. What do you want?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_intro_101">
		<text>Good day.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_intro_102">
		<text>Good day!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_intro_103">
		<text>Hey, man.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_intro_104">
		<text>Hi.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_intro_105">
		<text>Oh, hello!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_intro_106">
		<text>Hello.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_intro_107">
		<text>Greetings!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_intro_108">
		<text>Hello, stalker.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_intro_109">
		<text>Greetings, stalker.</text>
	</string>


	<string id="dm_intro_11">
		<text>You are in an area where order is maintained by members of the Duty group. Any request of the patrol must be obeyed without question.</text>
	</string>


	<string id="dm_intro_110">
		<text>Hey, you, stalker!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_intro_111">
		<text>Hello.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_intro_112">
		<text>Wow! What a bunch of people!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_intro_113">
		<text>And who do we have here?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_intro_114">
		<text>What more do you want?</text>
	</string>


	<string id="dm_intro_12">
		<text>I wonder where in the zone so many zombies come from? One said they crawled out of secret labs after the crash and now they're hanging around. I even come here to the bar sometimes.</text>
	</string>


	<string id="dm_intro_13">
		<text>First time here? Then I suggest you go to the bar. Your coworkers there will give you all the latest news.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_intro_14">
		<text>Don't go near the center of the lake... there's a bunch of zombies. They'll eat more.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_intro_15">
		<text>I don't recommend going anywhere near the center of the lake... There's a lot of dead people out there!</text>
	</string>



	<string id="dm_intro_16">
		<text>You know where all the zombies in the zone come from? They say that after the explosion, they came out of all the labs. experimenting on them.</text>
	</string>



	<string id="dm_intro_17">
		<text>Don't go to the center of the lake, man, you're gonna end up dead.</text>
	</string>




	<string id="dm_intro_18">
		<text>You keep in mind, Radar's already around here. Don't you dare go north!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_intro_19">
		<text>You don't want to lose your brains, don't go north from here!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_intro_2">
		<text>Watch out for the bridge, okay? There's a lot of stray dogs out there. If you flap your ears, they'll eat you in two seconds!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_intro_20">
		<text>You take care of yourself as a person! It's two steps to Radar. If you go north, whoops, and you're ready for another asshole!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_intro_21">
		<text>It's like walking through a minefield, only worse! There's a hell of a lot going on here at times, you can't relax for a second!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_intro_22">
		<text>I advise you to increase your attention, and once you've increased it, don't relax. If you relax, you're gone, you're dead!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_intro_23">
		<text>You've got to keep your ears open at all times! Sleep half-eyed! Shit can happen at any time!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_intro_24">
		<text>Watch out for scumbags! It's like a cockroach infestation.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_intro_25">
		<text>Destroy the so-called Monolithians as soon as you see them! Very dangerous - real fanatics!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_intro_26">
		<text>There are some assholes here who call themselves Monolithians... They're not afraid of pain. If you run out of ammunition, they'll throw themselves at you and try to chew your throat off. In general, if you see it, shoot immediately, don't hesitate!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_intro_3">
		<text>Listen up! You see a tunnel, don't go in it. I'm telling you right away, because not everyone is smart enough to stay out of the ass. They won't even take you out of there, you'll be in pieces on the walls. This is the Zone, okay?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_intro_4">
		<text>Hey, hobo. I'll give you some free advice - you'd better not go behind the factory - bandits have been seen there. Rumor has it they're coming here from the cordon, through the gate.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_intro_5">
		<text>Why do you walk alone? This place is full of skinheads, they can catch you at any time! Lately they've become quite brazen, even attacking roadblocks, I hear.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_intro_6">
		<text>Be warned if you're not in the know! There's been a lot of gang activity around here lately. It's the second shooting with them in a week. Be careful, keep your eyes open, they've already sent six loners to the afterlife.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_intro_7">
		<text>You didn't happen to hear what the military suddenly needed in the research building, did you? What are they doing out there today?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_intro_8">
		<text>You pay attention here! There's a bunch of thugs in the main building. They have no conscience or pity, I'd strangle them all!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_intro_9">
		<text>You don't want to go into the Dark Valley alone. The killers are nesting in one of the buildings. We're still trying to smoke them out. Don't get hurt, boy!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_intro_help_1">
		<text>Brother, help!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_intro_help_10">
		<text>Help me, somebody!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_intro_help_11">
		<text>Guards, I'm hit! Come here!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_intro_help_12">
		<text>Help! I'm dying!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_intro_help_2">
		<text>Guys, first aid kit!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_intro_help_3">
		<text>Get the first aid kit in here!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_intro_help_4">
		<text>Shock control, boys! Hurry up!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_intro_help_5">
		<text>First aid kit, men!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_intro_help_6">
		<text>Somebody! Give me the first aid kit!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_intro_help_7">
		<text>Buddy, first aid kit... first aid kit!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_intro_help_8">
		<text>Help, man!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_intro_help_9">
		<text>Share your first aid kit, buddy, huh?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_intro_help_13">
		<text>Hey, man, can I borrow your first aid kit?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_intro_help_14">
		<text>Man, you got a first aid kit?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_intro_help_15">
		<text>Bro, you got a first aid kit?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_intro_help_16">
		<text>Man, help me out!</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="list_trader_repair_0">
		<text>The cost of repairing weapons in the first slot:</text>
	</string>
	<string id="list_trader_repair_1">
		<text>The cost of repairing weapons in the second slot:</text>
	</string>
	<string id="list_trader_repair_2">
		<text>Cost to repair armor:</text>
	</string>


<!--****************************-->
<!-- Repair at the Barman's -->
<!--****************************-->
	<string id="bar_trader_repair_0">
		<text>Barkeep, you wouldn't happen to be a gun repairman, would you?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_trader_repair_1">
		<text>Truth be told... me, no. But I have a great gunsmith in my kitchen! So not only does he repair weapons, he repairs suits. So what are we gonna fix?\n\nA list of possible repairs:</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_trader_repair_2">
		<text>Repair the weapon in the first slot.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_trader_repair_3">
		<text>Repair the weapon in the second slot.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_trader_repair_4">
		<text>Repair the vest.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_trader_repair_5">
		<text>Shit, money's always tight. Let me come back later!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_trader_repair_6">
		<text>Here you go! Everything is fixed as far as it can be!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_trader_repair_7">
		<text>Here you go! Everything possible is done!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_trader_repair_8">
		<text>Your gunsmith really is a master! Give him my regards.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_trader_repair_9">
		<text>Great job indeed!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_trader_repair_10">
		<text>Is there anything else he can fix?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_trader_repair_11">
		<text>Of course, he doesn't have much work to do now anyway!\n\nA list of possible repairs:</text>
	</string>

</string_table>
