<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1251" ?>
<string_table>

	<string id="dm_action_info_0">
		<text>I'm sorry, I don't have time to chat right now.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="dm_action_info_1">
		<text>I’d rather wait until those handsome men in uniform go on their lunch break. No point hanging around here - I've got to get back to the Big Land, but they won’t let me through! I’m not the only one trying to get out, but none of us have managed to slip past yet.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_action_info_10">
		<text>There’s something nearby that the brass in shoulder straps are after. No one’s ever come this way before - everything was stripped clean, the cables cut long ago. And now, somehow, they’ve found it. I couldn’t even get close to the building. They spotted me and opened fire. Lucky for me it didn’t punch a hole right through.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_action_info_100">
		<text>I didn’t hear a thing - same story as always.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_action_info_11">
		<text>We’re putting together a team of people who don’t wet themselves at the thought of heading underground in the Zone. There’s an old factory with a maze of tunnels beneath it - word is, there’s all kinds of gear down there. Always something worth grabbing. Could be interesting.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_action_info_12">
		<text>Not new - old! They say this used to be Gunslinger’s main base. Makes you wonder... if we look hard enough, maybe we’ll find something he left behind.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_action_info_13">
		<text>I nearly got myself into trouble an hour ago. Six months back, this place was quiet - nothing but peace. Now it’s crawling with bandits in track pants hiding behind every bush. Unreal.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_action_info_14">
		<text>You're lucky, stalker - the bandits didn’t drag you in. Their base is just next door. If it were up to me, I’d take the place out myself. For now, though, we’re just keeping an eye on it. This is just an outpost - their main base is deeper in, closer to the center of the Zone.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_action_info_15">
		<text>They say there used to be a serious classified lab here. Uh-huh. Part of me wants to find the entrance - bet there’s a ton of valuable loot inside. But on the other hand… the place gives me the creeps.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_action_info_16">
		<text>Did you know that before the disaster, there was an underground research complex in what's now the Dark Valley? I don't know exactly what they were doing down there, but I doubt it was anything good. There are all kinds of stories about the place - most of them bad. Some downright terrifying.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_action_info_17">
		<text>Why? What do you want to hear? Fine, I’ll tell you something! Duty - sure, they act like the Zone’s police, and yeah, they know how to keep things under control, sure. But I don’t like them one bit. Always acting like they own everything - don’t take this, don’t touch that, don’t carry that out of the Zone... And now they’ve even decided what people can and can’t talk about back on the Big Land! They say they want to destroy the Zone, piece by piece. Well, that’s soldiers for you - dreamers, the lot of them, even if they used to wear real uniforms. And the worst part? Word is, they’ve got backing from the very top.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_action_info_18">
		<text>This territory is under Duty’s control now, and our rules are the only law that matters here. We guard the Zone’s borders and keep the hotheads in check. Every day, thrill-seekers and starry-eyed rookies roll in by the trainload, dreaming of adventure... and then they drop like flies before the sun even sets.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_action_info_19">
		<text>Have you ever been to our transshipment base? It’s not just ours - lots of people pass through. The best part is, it’s clean, safe from most of the Zone’s nastier surprises, and it’s where all the news flows in. You can always pick up something useful or just chat about life. Shame Baldy left with a group the day before yesterday - I missed him this time around.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_action_info_2">
		<text>Let’s head to the camp - you’ll hear all the latest rumors there. That’s where most rookies like you end up anyway, either to gain some experience or catch a breather. We’ve got soldiers nearby, so don’t worry too much - but don’t get careless either. They won’t hesitate to shoot if you make the wrong move. There’s a spot near the merchant, our local trader, where you can settle in and rest for a while.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_action_info_20">
		<text>This place is safe now, stalker - and we do our best to keep it that way. There's always a crowd around here. Some folks have settled in and never venture beyond the outskirts, while others are gearing up for their next raid. It's a shame Iroquois didn’t make it back - he had a knack for showing rookies like you the ropes, always talking about the “way of the truth.”</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_action_info_21">
		<text>Did you hear Duty's running a new recruitment drive? I considered it for a moment, but then thought - why the hell would I need that? Back on the front line every other day, strict discipline, constant orders... I’ve done my two tours already. That’s more than enough for me.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_action_info_22">
		<text>In case you haven’t heard - here’s the word: we’ve opened up additional recruitment. If you’ve got at least some experience under your belt, come on over. You won’t regret it.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_action_info_23">
		<text>I don’t know anything. Just keep moving.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_action_info_24">
		<text>Fuck off - I’m not supposed to talk to you!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_action_info_25">
		<text>Sorry, I’d rather not waste time on this conversation.</text>
	</string>



	<string id="dm_action_info_26">
		<text>They say if you catch some kind of illness in the Zone, it can drive you mad… You lose your sense of self entirely - and eventually, you just die.</text>
	</string>




	<string id="dm_action_info_27">
		<text>Damn, you ever hear about the stuff out here? Rabies and worse. It’s bad - real bad. If you catch it, you’re as good as dead.</text>
	</string>



	<string id="dm_action_info_28">
		<text>When a blowout hits Lake Yantar, all the equipment there goes haywire. If things go south, find cover - any shelter will do.</text>
	</string>



	<string id="dm_action_info_29">
		<text>Ever been to the swamps? They say there was some kind of massacre out there. It's dangerous - rumor has it the rain’s acidic, and the air’s filled with strange fumes...</text>
	</string>



	<string id="dm_action_info_3">
		<text>Shit, I'd love to get into that factory... word is, there are some pretty interesting documents stashed away in there.</text>
	</string>



	<string id="dm_action_info_30">
		<text>I heard there are some scientists running research down in the valley. They even hired one of our own for security. Haven’t heard from them in a while, though.</text>
	</string>




	<string id="dm_action_info_31">
		<text>Get out of here before nightfall! It's still daylight now, but once the sun sets...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_action_info_32">
		<text>Stalker, move out! We're taking down the cordon. We only hold it during the day - come nightfall, we’re gone. It’s too dangerous around here after dark.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_action_info_33">
		<text>You see, come nightfall, you’ve got to take cover - and make sure it’s behind something solid. Around here, it feels like we’re under siege once the sun goes down.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_action_info_34">
		<text>Well, buddy, looks like you haven’t heard the news - come nightfall, you’d better be bedding down far away from here. Even a grenade launcher won’t always save you when it gets dark!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_action_info_35">
		<text>You know what? Let Duty, Freedom, and all the looters fight over who owns this scrap - doesn’t matter to me. Fuck it.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_action_info_36">
		<text>We’re running things here now, stalker. There’s enough trouble out there already - now these outsiders are making our lives even harder...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_action_info_37">
		<text>Just a heads-up - this place isn’t safe even during the day. There’s some kind of conflict going on between the local gangs.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_action_info_38">
		<text>You tell me - this is our turf, right? Makes it easier for us to contain whatever crap comes crawling out of the Zone’s center. Let the eggheads poke around if they want, but Duty and those looters? They need to clear out.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_action_info_39">
		<text>Didn’t you hear? There’s a new route past the Duty patrols to the perimeter. From Yantar, cut through the thick brush to Agroprom - easy as that, and you're out with the loot.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_action_info_4">
		<text>Nothing, alright? I don’t know a damn thing! I’m just scraping by, trying to earn my daily bread. I’m too scared to go deep into the Zone - screw that place! And back home, there’s no work, and my wife’s always on my case... I’ve got to survive somehow, don’t I? Out here in the Garbage, if you walk around long enough, you can scavenge enough artifacts to afford food and a drink. That’s all I need.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_action_info_40">
		<text>What are you doing here? Heading to Yantar, or trying to sneak some artifacts past the Bar?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_action_info_41">
		<text>I won’t deny it - your fellow stalkers occasionally bring us some very curious anomalous formations… artifacts, as you call them. Given the loose control over these parts, this area has turned into quite the smuggling route.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_action_info_42">
		<text>Come on, man - we’ve carved out a path so you don’t have to bump into Duty patrols on your way to the Big Land! Yeah, they’re still around, sure. But as long as they don’t catch wind of it, we can steer clear of them.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_action_info_43">
		<text>I just got back from Yantar. Figured I’d sell some stuff to the scientists like usual - but they’ve holed up in their bunkers, won’t even come out during the day unless it’s to meet the next helicopter. So if you’re heading that way, keep your eyes open - you might end up missing your chance.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_action_info_44">
		<text>There’s ongoing research in the Yantar zone, but lately, too many people have turned up dead. That’s why we’re posted here - guarding the approaches.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_action_info_45">
		<text>I don’t know what to tell you. I was planning to head back to our complex - Yantar, you know the place. But now? They say if it was dangerous before, it’s completely impassable now. Maybe they’re exaggerating… but maybe not.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_action_info_46">
		<text>I’ve been to Yantar - science there is practically shut down. They’re scared, hiding, only surviving off what the helicopters bring in. Then again, there’s corpses everywhere. Spend a week living among the dead and fear stops meaning much. It’s a nice place. Just not a pretty one.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_action_info_47">
		<text>Fuck those dogs, always lurking with the dead! There’s more of them every day in this godforsaken complex - and they’re getting bigger, too.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_action_info_48">
		<text>We're doing our best to keep the dead from spreading beyond the lab complex. Honestly, we could use an extra hand - if you're up for it. We're running low on manpower.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_action_info_49">
		<text>You know, we’ve been conducting our own reconnaissance. I’ve been mapping the main movement routes of the quasi-living - what you’d call the dead. Care to share any observations of your own?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_action_info_5">
		<text>That’s just how it is. Some scavenge around the Garbage, picking up scraps, while others push deeper into the Zone. Sure, the rewards out there are richer - but not everyone dares. Rookies without experience don’t stand a chance, and without proper gear, it’s a one-way trip.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_action_info_50">
		<text>Have you ever had to shoot one of those dead things coming out of the lab? Look at them - they don’t feel pain, they’re not afraid of anything... it’s like there’s nothing left in their heads at all.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_action_info_51">
		<text>I'm gonna go get a job at the lab! ... Alright, relax, man - just joking. Once you’re in there, you’re done for. Best case? You die quick.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_action_info_52">
		<text>I'm warning you - don’t go into the lab. But hey, if you’re dead set on it, I won’t stop you. Just don’t expect to come back alive.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_action_info_53">
		<text>Listen, I need to warn you - you really shouldn’t go near the lab. No one should. What happens there causes severe, irreversible changes to both your mind and body.</text>
	</string>



	<string id="dm_action_info_54">
		<text>Whoa there! Let me enlighten you - save your poor, lost soul. Alright, listen up: don’t go skiing out to the center of the lake. It’s seriously messed up out there. People vanish, and sometimes... they come back. At night. But this isn’t some vampire tale - these are dead men’s stories. That’s just how it is.</text>
	</string>



	<string id="dm_action_info_55">
		<text>Have you seen those brainy types in their UN-blue gear? Lately, they’ve been spooked. They barely step off their base without bringing an entire regiment - APCs, helicopters, the whole show - just to guard them.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_action_info_56">
		<text>What’s it to you? Don’t bother them with dumb questions, and they won’t bother you either.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_action_info_57">
		<text>You see, we usually don’t leave the bunkers without proper security - conditions out here just don’t allow it. I’m something of an exception; I’m not a fan of big expeditions, all the commotion, or the military presence. But I’m afraid I don’t have anything useful to tell you just yet.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_action_info_58">
		<text>I'm in love with our quirky scientist - totally crazy about her, man! She almost never leaves her bunker, but when she does, like the other day… oh man! Troops everywhere, helicopters, armored vehicles - you’d think a damn battleship was about to roll in. Or at least an armored train!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_action_info_59">
		<text>I've been here three days, just watching. The lab’s right over there, yeah? No one’s really been inside since the start. Duty cleared out the bodies up top, but even they stopped going in. Now the scientists are heading in - must’ve figured out how to protect themselves from... something. I don’t know what. So I figured I’d look into it. Place like that’s bound to be full of loot.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_action_info_6">
		<text>Lately, the beasts have been pouring out of the Dark Valley in packs. I don’t know what’s driving them, but they’re scattering like there’s a fire behind them. And over in the eastern sector, mutants are crawling around like bedbugs - we barely have time to shoot them. That’s the situation.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_action_info_60">
		<text>What are you after? Heading to the lab too? Let me guess - you heard the story about miracle devices and scattered artifacts? Damn... When are you people gonna learn to let it go?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_action_info_61">
		<text>I work here, young man - just doing my job, serving science and humanity. And as for that abandoned lab, the one every stalker assumes I know all about - I'll tell you this: I don’t know, and I don’t want to know! I’ve never been interested in that place, and I intend to keep it that way. Understood?!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_action_info_62">
		<text>Maybe the scientists came up with some kind of device - who knows? I wonder what’s really hidden in that lab. Even if there’s nothing valuable, it’s still fascinating!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_action_info_63">
		<text>Thinking of joining Freedom? Why not? They seem like smart people - and if they’re a bit laid-back, all the better! I don’t need someone barking orders at me. I know what I’m doing - I’ve been out here for months...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_action_info_64">
		<text>I saw an old man on the hills - he's got a huge dog. What's he doing there?</text>
	</string>


	<string id="dm_action_info_65">
		<text>I was talking to a Dutyer the other day. Smart guy - but narrow-minded, like a tank. See, we’ve got different philosophies. The Zone isn’t something you destroy - it has to be understood, tamed, assimilated. And for that, we need open access to information. Sooner or later, someone will figure something out, something useful. But them? They restrict, forbid, cover everything up... Bunch of bastards, honestly. Then again, I get it - when you’ve got the whole state machine backing you, thinking for yourself isn’t exactly required.</text>
	</string>


	<string id="dm_action_info_66">
		<text>There’s a little hamlet nearby - used to be quiet, but now something nasty’s stirred up. Best to steer clear. That’s why I’m taking the long way around... Just saying - you’ve been warned.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_action_info_67">
		<text>You there, stalker - let me warn you right off. That village? Bloodsuckers settled there a long time ago... maybe something even worse. So watch yourself if you go there.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_action_info_68">
		<text>What’s new? Nothing much - no artifacts around here for a long time. Those houses over there used to be crawling with bloodsuckers; we cleared them out as best we could. Now I’m stuck here, and I just... can’t bring myself to go back. Maybe it’s intuition, maybe something else. But I won’t go. It’s dead out there.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_action_info_69">
		<text>I’m getting the hell out of here. Four weeks on the barrier is enough - I’m done. The Woodpecker’s been active around the clock, and it’s getting more aggressive by the day.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_action_info_7">
		<text>These days, a lot of people are turning into garbage pickers. Back then, no one even glanced at the piles - radiation strong enough to boil your balls in thirty minutes. But now that loot’s scarce, they suit up, pop some anti-radiation chems, and dive in. There’s plenty to find, though it’s mostly just scraps.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_action_info_70">
		<text>If you're coming with us, I respect that. If not - then stay out of the way. We need real men, not dead weight. Got enough of that already.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_action_info_71">
		<text>You're posted at the roadblock, huh? Good - nice to have another solid person around. We set this place up and held it together pretty well... until the beasts showed up. It's rough now. We need every gun we can get!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_action_info_72">
		<text>Keep your eyes open, bro - radiation and fanatics are everywhere. Now let’s get on with it.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_action_info_73">
		<text>You should’ve waited, stalker. Always chasing after everyone... Tell me something - do you even know what’s in there? Exactly, you don’t. You don’t know if there’s food, or what kind of traps are waiting. So why are you all rushing in like a herd of elk?!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_action_info_74">
		<text>The path to the center is open, got it?! We’re heading straight in. Now everyone’s going to flood in behind us. The key is to be among the first - grab the best loot while there’s still something left to squeeze.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_action_info_75">
		<text>Go on, see for yourself! Don’t you want to know what’s really going on down there? If not... well, maybe you’re just scared. There’s got to be something big! You’ve heard of the Wish Granter, right?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_action_info_76">
		<text>They’re like kids, for God’s sake - chasing after the Wish Granter, dreaming of some artifact Klondike.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_action_info_77">
		<text>I just want to see what’s beyond the horizon, man. Maybe, just maybe, we’ll find some kind of answer to all this madness they call the Zone.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_action_info_78">
		<text>Have you seen the high-rises? That’s Pripyat. Just beyond it is the power plant. I’d love to get there someday... but who knows what’s lurking in those buildings now.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_action_info_79">
		<text>Let me break it down for you: that’s Pripyat. Beyond it lies Chernobyl. We don’t know what’s happening there - or who might be living there now. But this is our place. We’ll dig something up to scavenge, like always.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_action_info_8">
		<text>I don’t know, man! I’m just heading to the bar to meet some people. You’ve never been there? Seriously? Alright, listen - just head straight north from here. You won’t get far before you stumble right into it. It’s a solid place, especially for a rookie like you - it’s like a check-up with the doctor. Plenty of seasoned stalkers hang around there; they’ll set you straight. Only catch is, Duty patrols that stretch. Whether they let you through or give you grief... well, that’s up to them.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_action_info_80">
		<text>Pripyat! Shit, pinch me - finally made it! Just a short walk from here to the power plant. But who knows what you’ll run into now... what kind of beast might be lurking, sharpening its teeth just for you.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_action_info_81">
		<text>Hey, buddy, tell me something - do you hear that voice too, or am I the only one losing it? It just keeps talking... and talking... won't shut up.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_action_info_82">
		<text>Damn it, another one... Alright, listen up - for the tenth time, I’m explaining this. People around here are hit with some kind of telepathic influence. Voices, ones you can’t hear from the outside, keep calling them toward the center of the Zone. They promise to grant any wish to whoever manages to reach and touch... something. Yeah - that’s right. Some kind of Monolith.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="dm_action_info_83">
		<text>You hear that voice too? Pretty wild - like a record spinning in your head. Shame it’s stuck on the same damn track: “Come to me and you’ll be happy.” Been repeating it for two hours straight...</text>
	</string>

	<string id="dm_action_info_84">
		<text>Can’t you figure it out? You’re heading to the power plant - same as us! What else is there to say? If only we could clear out those possessed bastards blocking the way...</text>
	</string>


	<string id="dm_action_info_85">
		<text>The power plant’s just next door, what does that tell you?</text>
	</string>


	<string id="dm_action_info_86">
		<text>There it is - the ChNPP, just a stone's throw away. It's all that's left. But those bastards are dug in tight; they won't let us through. That's fine... we'll deal with them.</text>
	</string>


	<string id="dm_action_info_9">
		<text>Listen, friend - don’t you know anything about Agroprom? I thought about heading there myself, but people just laughed. Said the place’s gone to hell, stripped bare ages ago - only anomalies left now. I don’t know if they’re serious or just messing with me. I’m new here, so when the locals talk, I tend to believe them... but maybe they’re just having a laugh. Bastards.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_action_info_94">
		<text>Wait up! Move quickly, but don’t rush blindly! There are Monolith freaks around here - they know the city like the back of their hand and they’ve set up ambushes. Watch your step!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_action_info_95">
		<text>I'm warning you - most of the city’s still under Monolith control. They've set up ambushes all over and know every corner of this place. Keep your eyes sharp and your weapon ready.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_action_info_96">
		<text>What I’d really love is to carpet bomb this whole damn town. Bastards are everywhere - unless they’re hiding in sandboxes or flowerpots. People have already died because of those assholes!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_action_info_97">
		<text>Look, I don’t know what the hell this Monolith really is. Maybe it’s not eternal - maybe there’s not enough to go around. So what are we supposed to do, just wait around on all fours? If we make it there, I promise - you’ll be right behind me.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_action_info_98">
		<text>Duty has to break through to the center - if not first, then at least among the first! Just think about it, stalker: what if some lunatic - because let’s face it, most of you are half-crazy, paranoid, or downright brain-dead - gets their hands on something that really can grant any wish? Huh? Then what?!</text>
	</string>

	<string id="dm_action_info_99">
		<text>I don't feel like talking.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="dm_action_info_101">
		<text>Oh, nothing much. I'm just trying to survive and make a living.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_action_info_102">
		<text>I'm building up experience and saving every bit of money I can. Once I’ve got enough, I’ll get myself a proper gun, decent armor - and then I’m heading straight for the center of the Zone.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_action_info_103">
		<text>The Zone drew me in. I came here by accident - like some kind of illegal excursion - and before I knew it, I was hooked. The people here are real, whether they're friends or enemies. And the danger... that constant sense of death lurking close? It makes you feel truly alive. Makes you appreciate every moment you've got.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_action_info_104">
		<text>I'm resting up after my last raid. Made it almost all the way to the Barrier - we set up a line of defense against all the hell that spills out of the center. A good crew came together for it - Sanya Shaggy, Lyokha Koresh, Maldi... all decent guys, real solid. I scored some good loot too, sold it to the dealer, and figured I’d catch my breath here for a while. It’s calmer here than deep in the Zone. Easier, you know?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_action_info_105">
		<text>You’re asking me that?! It’s because of people like you that we’re stuck out here. What do you all see in this damn Zone? You come in droves, die off like flies, and still more of you keep coming! And now you're asking me what I'm doing here? I should be asking you what the hell you're doing here. Whatever - I've got no time for this. Just get lost!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_action_info_106">
		<text>Military secrets!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_action_info_107">
		<text>It's nothing, really. It's nothing.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_action_info_108">
		<text>I'm just taking in the beauty of this place. It’s nothing like the outside world. You might not agree, but I think people either can’t - or won’t - find a common language with nature. And in the end, their actions hurt her. Still, in her own way, she tries to send them a signal... but they just keep ignoring it. Uh-huh.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_action_info_109">
		<text>It's none of your business!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_action_info_110">
		<text>Never mind...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_action_info_111">
		<text>What business is it of yours?!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_action_info_112">
		<text>Ever since I was a kid, I’ve been drawn to unexplored places. So when I first heard about the Zone, I came without hesitation. And honestly? It’s the most extraordinary place I’ve ever seen.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_action_info_113">
		<text>I’m fulfilling my duty to humanity - and that’s not just some grand phrase, it’s the truth. Saving them from what? From the Zone and everything it creates. We have to wipe out this breeding ground of evil and infection before it wipes us out!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_action_info_114">
		<text>I recently joined Duty, and I’m loving it. The guys here are the real deal - disciplined, reliable. You always know what needs to be done and who’s in charge.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_action_info_115">
		<text>I’ve got a lot of friends in Duty, so I decided to join up. Took me a few months to finally make the call - and now I look back and think, “What was I so worried about?” It’s great here. A hell of a lot safer than roaming the Zone alone.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_action_info_116">
		<text>Well, there’s not much to do in the Zone, really - hunt for loot, fight, uncover its secrets... and then make sure everyone has equal access to what’s found. That’s what I keep busy with, day in and day out.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_action_info_117">
		<text>Dude, I’m protecting the Zone from the government. We can’t let them take control - if they do, it’ll all go to hell, and we’re as good as dead!</text>
	</string>




	<string id="dm_cool_info_0">
		<text>You don't want to head into the Garbage - too much wildlife out there. It’s like a crossroads of the Zone; you could run into just about anything.</text>
	</string>






	<string id="dm_cool_info_1">
		<text>Rumor has it that various special services are recruiting stalkers for their own ends. Wouldn’t be surprised if every other stalker out here is on someone’s payroll - from one intelligence agency or another.</text>
	</string>



	<string id="dm_cool_info_10">
		<text>They say artifacts hold the very power of anomalies - and some can even create new ones. But once they do, they lose their value. The anomalies they produce don’t last long, and they’re usually weak.</text>
	</string>



	<string id="dm_cool_info_100">
		<text>I haven't heard anything like that, sorry.</text>
	</string>



	<string id="dm_cool_info_11">
		<text>I saw a guy hanging around the bar - gray as mold, like something rotten. Gave me the creeps.</text>
	</string>



	<string id="dm_cool_info_12">
		<text>A springboard is an anomaly - like a whirligig - that forms between similar objects, like trees. Walk between them, and it'll tear you apart... half to each tree.</text>
	</string>




	<string id="dm_cool_info_13">
		<text>There are places in the Zone where a new kind of anomaly might exist - ones that transform any creature caught in them within seconds. These mutations aren't usually fatal. Sometimes, if a person wanders in, they might even retain a shred of their sanity - though not for long. That’s how rumors of strange, never-before-seen mutants start. But they don’t last. Not once an armed stalker spots them.</text>
	</string>



	<string id="dm_cool_info_14">
		<text>You ever hear of the Killers? They’re not after artifacts - they hunt stalkers. Track them down and carry out contracts. Cold, precise, and deadly.</text>
	</string>



	<string id="dm_cool_info_15">
		<text>If you're bringing up the same crap that’s been pissing me off for the past two days, then go to hell! If I knew - and it wasn’t classified - I’d tell you! But I don’t know a damn thing! What did the scientists discover? Where did command disappear to? How the hell should I know? The guy’s on leave, not like he owes us any explanations!</text>
	</string>




	<string id="dm_cool_info_16">
		<text>There's something called induced fields - anomalies that aren’t exactly where the instruments say they are. Some claim it's a kind of distortion, maybe even a defense mechanism. That’s why, deep in the Zone, stalkers trust their instincts and eyesight more than any gadget.</text>
	</string>




	<string id="dm_cool_info_17">
		<text>They say some mutants can do more than just control you - they can mess with your mind, make you see things. One moment you're walking a flat road, the next you're falling off a cliff. Or worse, you start shooting at people who aren't even there.</text>
	</string>





	<string id="dm_cool_info_18">
		<text>Legend. They say it’s a small group of stalkers who’ve somehow learned to communicate with the monsters. You almost never see them outside the Zone - their base is supposedly deep in the center. Rumor has it they possess unimaginable riches, with the mutants themselves helping them hunt for artifacts. Word is, Duty knows about them and wants them wiped out, but officially? They just say it’s all fairy tales.</text>
	</string>






	<string id="dm_cool_info_19">
		<text>They say military stalkers are equipped with monster detectors - able to spot any creature within 200 meters. That’s why they move through the Zone so safely.</text>
	</string>






	<string id="dm_cool_info_2">
		<text>I don’t know if you’ve heard, but there’s a group of military stalkers called Intercept. They’re an elite special unit operating deep within the Zone. They’ve got multiple hideouts, a supply chain that still works - helicopters drop off gear now and then. The unit is led by Major Gromov, better known as Grom. No one really knows what their goals are. They operate with total autonomy, shifting policies on the fly. Sometimes they work with stalkers, but more often they shoot first. What they’re really after - no one can say.</text>
	</string>





	<string id="dm_cool_info_20">
		<text>There’s been a large expedition spotted in the Zone - officially, they’re UN environmentalists. In reality, it’s a U.S. military-scientific task force. Their goals aren’t clear, but a few things stand out. For one, they didn’t bring a single local guide. That either means they have their own sources of intel on the Zone... or their mission is so classified that even having outsiders around in a supporting role is unacceptable.</text>
	</string>




	<string id="dm_cool_info_21">
		<text>They say there’s a group of stalkers people call shamans—sometimes druids. They never carry electronic gear, as if trying to stay closer to nature. According to them, the Zone reacts more aggressively to electronics - its radiation, they claim, draws anomalies and mutants toward you. They believe the Zone is a living organism and shouldn’t be disturbed by devices, insisting that a person is already well-equipped by nature to survive here without extra tech. Of course, they still carry assault rifles. Guess they don’t have teeth and claws to rip enemies apart, no matter how “tough” they are. Strangely enough, they don’t seem to die in the Zone nearly as often as you’d expect. So maybe they’re onto something. I’ve never met any of these druids myself, they say they usually enter the Zone from the Belarus side.</text>
	</string>





	<string id="dm_cool_info_22">
		<text>It’s been a strange day global misfortune somehow giving way to incredible luck. And now I’ve stumbled upon an even stranger place. It started yesterday. Out of the bushes and the foggy evening gloom, a silhouette emerged: a large wooden house, its roof sagging in several places. It looked like it had once been a village school, later perhaps a hospital. In the half-light it resembled the carcass of a dead dragon. And where there’s a dragon, there’s gold, a stray thought whispered in my head. Buoyed by that foolish notion, I stepped through the warped, rotting door. A dining hall greeted me. Among the usual stench of decay and abandonment, another, unfamiliar odor cut through. My caution doubled as I began to inspect every corner with slow, deliberate care.\n\nAnd then I fall. I land hard, right on my bad leg. Pain flares white-hot, and for a moment all I can do is lie there. A couple of minutes pass before my head clears. Turns out I’ve dropped into the basement. But how in the hell did I miss a hole in the floor two meters by one and a half? Fantastic luck - of the wrong kind. Time to get out. My leg screams with every movement, and my head’s pounding from the hit. Still, I manage to limp over to the ladder. I climb, slowly, gritting my teeth - and then I see it. At the top, waiting for me like some miracle, is a KPPU: a universal first aid kit. Only the military and special forces carry them. Out here, finding one is like stumbling on a spring in the middle of a desert. I drop down beside it. A few injections later and it’s like night turned to day - fatigue gone, bad mood lifted, and my leg almost working again. Not perfect, but good enough. Alright. Time to move on.\n\nSecond floor. I tread lightly, the stairs and warped boards creak under my weight, ready to give way. A glint catches my eye at the far end of the corridor. I move toward it, slow and cautious, and find a door. Nothing obvious is shining, but when I try the handle it turns stiffly, resisting as if held shut by a powerful spring. Slinging my rifle behind me, I throw my weight against it; the damn thing feels like it’s made of lead, budging only a couple of centimeters. Planting my feet against the jamb, I shove hard until it finally gives - only to pitch forward onto the floor as if something had been holding it shut from the other side. I’m still cursing when the door suddenly slams back with bone-jarring force, flinging me two meters into the opposite wall. That’s it - I’ve had enough. I squeeze off a short burst, sending splinters flying as dusty shafts of sunlight slice through the holes. The sight is almost beautiful, even through my fury. One hard kick and the door flies open, revealing a classroom choked with broken beds. In the aisle between them lies a body, a military stalker, long dead, rotted to the bone but still in full kit, gear worth a small fortune. Three questions hit me at once: How the hell did he get here alone? Why leave a first aid kit downstairs? And most of all... who killed you, you poor bastard?\n\nWeird day today - one moment it’s all bad luck, the next it’s unbelievable fortune. Strange as hell. Still, you take the good when it comes, and move fast while the quiet lasts. I lean over the corpse. His eyes are open, fixed on me, or no, not fixed... moving. He’s looking at me. Then, slowly, his head turns toward me. I swing my rifle butt down hard, only for it to pass clean through his body as if he’s not even there, smashing into the floor with bone-rattling force. I stumble sideways, hitting the ground. What the hell? The splintered wrecks of the beds around me begin to stir, shifting in a slow, unnatural ripple. Something’s moving. I’m about to get hit - what the hell is going on...\n\n ...It burst like a balloon full of foul liquid, spraying the whole room with its stinking juice. Pathetic thing, still clawing at the rusted bars that had skewered it, wheezing out some last, ragged noise. Almost funny, in its stubborn will to live. Came crawling in here for its own filthy greed - and left the same way, a broken lump of meat. In its own way, that’s justice.</text>
	</string>







	<string id="dm_cool_info_23">
		<text>The Zone pulls people in like a giant magnet.. or like flies to a pile of shit - take your pick.</text>
	</string>






	<string id="dm_cool_info_24">
		<text>Some say the Zone is alive - maybe even intelligent. Others claim it’s the spawn of humanity’s sins, a piece of hell on Earth. And then there are those who ramble about alien experiments. Me? I don’t know.</text>
	</string>




	<string id="dm_cool_info_25">
		<text>In my opinion, the Zone is neither alive nor intelligent. It’s simply a place with its own rules - an alternate biosphere. And, as in nature, if you break the rules, you die. No malice, no emotion - just cause and effect. As for the miracles, higher powers, and grand conspiracies... people need something to believe in. And it’s not my job to talk them out of it, especially since they make for my best clients.</text>
	</string>





	<string id="dm_cool_info_26">
		<text>Some come to the Zone out of curiosity, others for the novelty - but most come for money. I’m one of them. The curious and the thrill-seekers usually don’t last long; they leave almost as quickly as they arrive. The ones chasing profit... well, that depends on the circumstances.</text>
	</string>






	<string id="dm_cool_info_27">
		<text>I’ve never understood why so many people think the Zone is a frightening place. I couldn’t disagree more. To me, it’s a return to nature. First, humanity corrupted nature - took its wealth, broke its laws. Now nature is taking its course, tearing down what we built, gathering new riches, and rewriting the rules. There’s no place on Earth more fascinating... or more beautiful.</text>
	</string>




	<string id="dm_cool_info_28">
		<text>These days, everyone’s their own craftsman, doing whatever they please. Back in the old days, real experts were respected - people came to us for advice, and there were more of us around. Now? It’s just me, Semyon the gunsmith, and a bunch of small-time cops who, frankly, don’t know a damn thing. They’re out there slapping optics on rifles like it’s some kind of revelation. I remember when weapons used to be unique. Not gimmicks with seven barrels welded into one, but guns that carried a deeper meaning. You’ve heard the stories about the self-defeating shotgun, I’m sure. I’ve held that thing myself.\n\nFirst off, it’s not really a shotgun - it’s a heavily modified rifle system based on the FN2000. But at this point, all that remains from the original are the barrel, the grenade launcher, and a reworked trigger mechanism. The casing, electronics, optics, everything else was redesigned from the ground up. The core of the modification? They took the Optical Targeting System - the same one the army’s been struggling to get working, and refined it. Don’t ask me how Micah managed to cram it into such a compact frame, or how he shielded it so well against interference. He was a master. But the real breakthrough was this: he built an automatic firing system around that compact OTS. Simple. Brilliant. You select the firing mode, aim, and the system opens fire on its own. He called it a “self-timer.” When we tested it, I was stunned. Almost one hundred percent hit rate. No sight drift when pulling the trigger. And the ammo savings? Incredible. Just line up the shot and remember to reload. Oh, and when it’s powered down, it still works with standard optics, no inconvenience at all. Micah gave it to Black. And Black, well, he wasn’t just some lucky stalker; he was a real master in his own right. Half a year ago, though, he died out there in the Zone. Eternal memory. The Zone took his “self-breaker,” too. That’s where it is now, out there somewhere. That’s where we’d need to look if we ever wanted to build another. And building a second one... that’s no small thing. Think about it: even the military only mounts systems like that on helicopters - and even then, they can't guarantee they'll trigger correctly. No, it’s not something you just whip up in a workshop. But if we could find the prototype itself - really dig into it, tear it apart, understand how Micah pulled it off... Yeah. Then we’d have a shot.</text>
	</string>



	<string id="dm_cool_info_29">
		<text>There was this fool once, just lounging around on his heel, taking it easy, until a controller dragged him straight into the Zone. You remember how it is out there, dukhman. Something shifts weird, you hear a whisper, see a shadow - don’t think, don’t wonder. Just empty the mag on the sector and hose the bushes and trees. Flip to full auto and keep your finger down. This ain’t no training yard. Out here, they'll chew you up before you can even fart.\n\nYou fire off the horn and drop on your back behind cover. If the controller's got eyes on you, he has to focus on the poor bastard you just tagged. While you're soaking up the sun flat on your spine, you flip your buddy over, switch your Kalash to short bursts. Pop off a round, count to three - and then bolt. Get the hell out of there.\n\nSuck it up? You wish. If you're anything like me, you'll live long enough to see the end of your life before you're discharged.</text>
	</string>





	<string id="dm_cool_info_3">
		<text>You heard anything about the Saint? They say he slips out of hiding at night, somewhere near Radar, and starts wandering around the Bar. You know anything about that?</text>
	</string>




	<string id="dm_cool_info_30">
		<text>Have you ever seen a kid's footprints here in the Zone? I've seen fresh ones! Sometimes you can get a little freaked out by what goes on here.</text>
	</string>




	<string id="dm_cool_info_31">
		<text>The scientists are sniffing around again. I don’t know what kind of secret they’ve uncovered, but the military’s got their backs arched like cats. They’re already sweeping through Agroprom and Dark Valley - searching, scouring, like they’re chasing something they don’t understand.</text>
	</string>



	<string id="dm_cool_info_32">
		<text>There's more and more shit coming out of the city every day, and Duty and Freedom are going on another raid. How long can we hold this barrier alone?</text>
	</string>




	<string id="dm_cool_info_33">
		<text>The mutants are pushing harder every day, testing the barrier like it’s nothing. It’s been rough lately, too rough. If some of them weren’t so brain-dead, we’d drop them like flies. But no, they’re learning..</text>
	</string>




	<string id="dm_cool_info_34">
		<text>I've got a story for you. There was this stalker who swore off vodka. Walked the Zone all day, got tired, sat on a stump to rest. Says to himself, 'Alright, I’ll take the bottle out, just to look at it, not open it.' Then: 'Fine, I’ll open it, but I won’t pour.' A beat later: 'Okay, just a little in the glass, but I won’t drink it.' Then: 'I’ll just hold it in my mouth. No swallowing.' And finally: 'Well, one sip won’t hurt.' One sip turns into another, and another. 'Didn’t want to drink, but I did!' he cried. ‘Try quitting out here—damn Controllers!’ Poor bastard was crushed.</text>
	</string>





	<string id="dm_cool_info_35">
		<text>Heard this one the other day. An old, seasoned stalker walks up to a rookie and says, “Hey, come with me to the Zone - hunt monsters, dodge anomalies, find artifacts!” The rookie shrugs, “I dunno... I don’t really know how to do all that yet.” The old stalker just laughs, raises a flask, and says, “What’s there to know? Pour and drink!” — and that was the extent of his wisdom.</text>
	</string>




	<string id="dm_cool_info_36">
		<text>If you want to earn money - there are bulletin boards with all sorts of ads about work at the entrance to the Bar, or at the scientists' bunker on Yantar. You can make a lot of money if you put your mind to it...</text>
	</string>




	<string id="dm_cool_info_37">
		<text>There was some idiot here once, just lounging on his heel, taking it easy—until a Controller dragged him off into the Zone. Listen, Dukhmans, you see a jolt or something move weird? Don’t freeze up. Just stay calm, drop the mag on the fire sector, spray the bushes and trees, then switch to full auto. This ain’t basic training,they’ll chew you up before you even fart.\n\nSo: you light up the horn, fall flat on your back behind cover. If the Controller sees you, he’s got to focus on the target. While you're sunbathing like a corpse, flip your mate over and set the Kalash to short bursts. Fire off a shot, count to three, and then run like hell.\n\nSuck it up? Ha! Bunch of amateurs. If you're like me, you'll make it to your discharge in one piece.</text>
	</string>




	<string id="dm_cool_info_38">
		<text>What's the news? We're sitting here, the beasts come at us, we shoot them, and then they come again, only even stronger. There's been a few military helicopters around, and it looks like they even flew over the Woodpecker.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_cool_info_39">
		<text>What’s new around here? Same as always: mutants, anomalies, nothing special. Though the military’s been buzzing around in helicopters again. You’d think they’d at least bag a beast for once... but nope. Nothing.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_cool_info_4">
		<text>What’s new? You hear a lot, but don’t go believing everything, or you’ll run out of faith real quick. Word is, some veteran stalker crawled out from deep inside the Zone, brought back something no one’s ever seen, made a fortune overnight... Sure. I could tell you a hundred stories just like it. Doesn’t make any of them true.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_cool_info_40">
		<text>Saw military helicopters today, no joke. Imagine it: they flew right over us, low. Then one peeled off toward Woodpecker - just one. I figured, 'That’s it, they’re gonna get lit up for sure.' But nope. They just circled a bit, turned around, and flew right back the way they came. Like it was nothing. Real normal, huh?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_cool_info_41">
		<text>Eh, the center of the Zone is very close... There must be a lot of riches lying around out there.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_cool_info_42">
		<text>Now that it's gotten easier to slip through to the center of the Zone, stalkers are swarming in like flies on honey. Yeah... Greed’s never been humanity’s finest trait.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_cool_info_43">
		<text>What a life we're living! By the time all those from the Bar and the perimeter get here, we'll have the cream of the crop. We'll pick up the good stuff and let the others do the small stuff.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_cool_info_44">
		<text>They say the Black Monolith really exists. Somebody's already gotten to it and made a big wish for it.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_cool_info_45">
		<text>Listen, buddy - I’ve seen some wild shit in the Zone, no doubt. But those stories about people turning into Monolithians on the spot? That’s just crap. Total bullshit, nothing more.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_cool_info_46">
		<text>You didn’t hear about that? Two of our guys, first ones to reach the center, made it all the way to the Monolith and made a wish. Spent their whole lives dreaming of some tropical island, warm sea and all. So now? They’re probably sunbathing in the damn tropics. No other way!</text>
	</string>


	<string id="dm_cool_info_47">
		<text>I've got this story I heard from someone. It goes something like: "So I go to the peddler, and he says, ‘Until you pay off your debt, I’m keeping your AK.’ Bastard! How the hell am I supposed to work off a debt without a gun? What, go into the Zone with my bare ass? But I grabbed a couple of TT's, some smokes, a week’s worth of food - and went anyway. On my last raid, some guy pointed out an abandoned research institute, said I should steer clear. Spooked me bad. But come on, if it’s a research institute, there’s gotta be something good there, right? So I went...\n\n...and made it to the site. Trees come right up to the fence, real convenient. I slip over, and the yard’s weirdly clean on the other side. Too clean. I creep up to the door, twist the knob... and bam, stairs. Goddamn stairs. Who the hell designs a research institute like this? Nothing but stairs, corridors, passageways. Another flight and I swear I’ll drop dead. Lucky I brought a kapron cord - already unspooled three hundred meters. Then I spot this door, weird as hell. Open it, and, shit, I’m on the roof. Fine. And there, lying just ahead.. (Here the guy froze, swallowing hard. I asked again: “So? What was lying there?”)\n\n“An AK. Double mag.”, “I remember - I was so damn happy, even jumped for joy. Thought, ‘Great, now I don’t have to pay back my debt.’”, “That all it was? Just the AK?”, “No. Not just that.”\n\nI saw this package lying nearby, something big, wrapped in roofing felt, and like an idiot, I started unwrapping it. The moment I peeled it back, it turned me inside out. I’d been wondering what that sweet smell was... It was a corpse. Not just a corpse, a full-blown dismemberment. The body was hacked up, skull split open. I bolted, scrambled back down using the cord, ran for the door to the yard, but it wasn’t there. I saw it, but when I reached out, it was just solid wall. Then I remembered, thank God - that earlier the door seemed like it had been in a different spot. I started fumbling, and opa! There it was. Found the handle, opened it... and instead of the yard, there was this sea of toothy tentacles swaying in the sunlight, the closest ones already reaching for me. Absolutely foul. If I hadn’t emptied my guts on the roof, I’d have died right there. But then, like a flash, I noticed something wrong. No shadows. The sun was blazing, but those things cast nothing. Just a trick, an illusion. I gathered what nerve I had left, figured I was dead either way, and dove through. Didn’t see the step, tripped hard - and faceplanted right onto the asphalt. That’s why my face looks like this now. Still, I got up, ran for the woods, nearly fell into a mosquito’s head on the way out... but I made it."\n\nThat's the story. Maybe the guy's lying. He was drunk as a pig, and he wanted to get to know the road. I checked it out, though. He did owe the dealer, and after that story, he got loose.</text>
	</string>




	<string id="dm_cool_info_48">
		<text>One of Sin's squads was found in a previously inaccessible area. How did they manage to get through unscathed and then survive there for weeks? It just doesn't make any sense! It looks like we've underestimated these guys.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_cool_info_49">
		<text>Hey, we found our Miklouha - he's alive! And the guys he was with made it too. We made it past Woodpecker, but then got stuck here for a month. No way out.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_cool_info_5">
		<text>Something shady’s going on. Word is the Duty commander, a real big shot, wasn’t just out here on some Zone business, but actually met with the Freedom boys to negotiate. If they were gonna make peace, they would've done it out in the open. Instead? Total mess. The whole thing stinks. And you know, the old-timers say that war didn’t start for any good reason in the first place. I just hope those desk jockeys from the Big Land don’t drag us into another meat grinder...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_cool_info_50">
		<text>Did you hear that? The military’s on the move - they’ll be here any minute! Word is they found out the Woodpecker’s dead and now they’re rushing in to grab everything at once!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_cool_info_51">
		<text>Word just came in - the army’s gearing up for a full-scale assault on the power plant. My advice? If you want a piece of the loot, you better move fast!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_cool_info_52">
		<text>It’s a complete mess! The moment the corridor opened, they started clearing the power plant of all kinds of shit, and now the military’s here too! No shame, no conscience!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_cool_info_53">
		<text>What I don't understand is this: how could the fighters from Freedom hold out here for a month? Did they wear invisible hats? It's a hell of a place.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_cool_info_54">
		<text>Do you even get what happened here? No joke, I respect Miklouha even more now. Think about it: four weeks stuck out there, holding on, and he didn’t lose a single man!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_cool_info_55">
		<text>Some of us have lost our minds. We were always tough guys, but now some of us are just.. doing nothing and drooling. It's scary!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_cool_info_56">
		<text>As we get closer to the power plant, the unknown telepathic influence intensifies. Some are starting to go crazy, others are having disturbances and visions. Maybe now would be a good time to back up a bit.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_cool_info_57">
		<text>People are really losing it out here. Someone sees a pebble and starts screaming it’s their damn artifact, claiming they saw it first and everyone else can go screw off. Then some guy named Jar shows up, floating on a cloud like nothing happened, along with his partners who vanished years ago. No, something’s seriously wrong here...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_cool_info_6">
		<text>The military’s up to something - searching, digging. It used to be just helicopters flying to Yantar to protect the scientists, bring in supplies, that kind of thing. But now? It’s an invasion. They’ve started launching raids, rolling in on APCs. We’ve already spotted them in Agroprom, the Dark Valley... again and again. I don’t know what they’re after.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_cool_info_7">
		<text>Somebody tried to get through the Woodpecker again. Well, that's the end of it, of course, and that's the end of the man. You haven't heard of Woodpecker? Oh, come on, man! It's the biggest hell in the whole neighborhood! The only trouble is, the horror stories about it are mostly true.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_cool_info_8">
		<text>It's not just bandits anymore, now the military's showing up too. Used to be you’d see a helicopter maybe once in a blue moon, but now they’re swarming the Zone. What, did they lose something out here?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_cool_info_9">
		<text>I have to warn you, stalker. The military has gone crazy around here lately! They used to guard the scientists quietly and peacefully, but now it's as if someone has drivem them insane! They're running around. Your brother's been shot by them more than once, and we've had two wounded this week.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_help_thanks_1">
		<text>Thank you very much.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_intro_0">
		<text>Don’t fire at the soldiers, one wrong move and you’ll catch a bullet fast. Worse, any of our guys nearby could get caught in the crossfire if you provoke them.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_intro_1">
		<text>I see you don't know your way around here yet, so I'm going to give you a friendly warning! Don't mess with the military. If you see them, get the hell away from them, because they've got no brains. They'll shoot you first, and then they'll look at your papers.</text>
	</string>



	<string id="dm_intro_10">
		<text>Dutyers run this place. Keep that in mind, so that you don't get in trouble.</text>
	</string>




	<string id="dm_intro_100">
		<text>Good day, stalker. What do you want?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_intro_101">
		<text>Good day.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_intro_102">
		<text>Good day!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_intro_103">
		<text>Hey, man.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_intro_104">
		<text>Hi.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_intro_105">
		<text>Oh, hello!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_intro_106">
		<text>Hello.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_intro_107">
		<text>Greetings!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_intro_108">
		<text>Hello, stalker.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_intro_109">
		<text>Greetings, stalker.</text>
	</string>


	<string id="dm_intro_11">
		<text>You’ve entered a zone under Duty control. Obey all patrol commands without hesitation, no exceptions.</text>
	</string>


	<string id="dm_intro_110">
		<text>Hey, you, stalker!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_intro_111">
		<text>Hello.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_intro_112">
		<text>Wow! What a bunch of people!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_intro_113">
		<text>And who do we have here?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_intro_114">
		<text>What more do you want?</text>
	</string>


	<string id="dm_intro_12">
		<text>Ever wonder where all the zombies in the Zone come from? I heard one guy say they crawled out of some secret lab after everything went to hell, and now they just wander. I’ve even seen a few drift into the area near the Bar now and then.</text>
	</string>


	<string id="dm_intro_13">
		<text>First time here? Then I suggest you go to the Bar. Your fellow stalkers there will give you all the latest news.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_intro_14">
		<text>Don't go near the center of the lake... there's a bunch of zombies there. They'll hunt you down.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_intro_15">
		<text>I don't recommend going anywhere near the center of the lake... There's a lot of dead people out there!</text>
	</string>



	<string id="dm_intro_16">
		<text>You know where all the zombies in the Zone come from? They say that after the explosion, they started crawling out of the labs - products of experiments gone wrong.</text>
	</string>



	<string id="dm_intro_17">
		<text>Don't go to the center of the lake, man, you're gonna end up dead.</text>
	</string>




	<string id="dm_intro_18">
		<text>Keep this in mind — Radar's just up ahead. Don’t even think about going north!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_intro_19">
		<text>You don't want to lose your brains, don't go north from here!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_intro_2">
		<text>Be careful the bridge, okay? There's a lot of stray dogs near there. If you loiter around there, they'll find you and chew you up you in two seconds!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_intro_20">
		<text>You need to be careful out here. It's a stone's throw to Radar from here. If you go north, you'll get into serious trouble and you'll get messed up badly.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_intro_21">
		<text>It's like walking through a minefield, only worse! There's a hell of a lot going on here at times, you can't let your guard down for a second!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_intro_22">
		<text>I advise you to never let your guard down here - don't relax. If you relax, you're gone, you're dead!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_intro_23">
		<text>You've got to keep your ears and eyes open here at all times! Sleep with one eye open! Shit can happen at any time!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_intro_24">
		<text>Watch out for scumbags! It's like there's a cockroach infestation here.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_intro_25">
		<text>Shoot down any Monolithians as soon as you see them! They're very dangerous - real fanatics!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_intro_26">
		<text>There are some assholes here who call themselves Monolithians... They're not afraid of pain. If you run out of ammunition, they'll throw themselves at you and try to chew your throat off. If you see any of them, shoot immediately, don't hesitate!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_intro_3">
		<text>Listen up! If you see a tunnel, don't go into it. I'm telling you right away, because not everyone is smart enough to stay out of them. If you go in, and get into trouble - no one will take you out of there. If you run into anomaly, all that'll remain of you bits stuck on the wall. This is the Zone, okay?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_intro_4">
		<text>Hey, hobo. I'll give you some free advice - you'd better not go behind the factory - bandits have been seen there. Rumor has it they're coming here from the Cordon, through the gate.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_intro_5">
		<text>Why do you walk alone? This place is full of skinheads, they can catch you at any time! Lately they've become quite brazen, even attacking military roadblocks, I hear.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_intro_6">
		<text>If you don't know what's been happening here, then consider yourself warned! There's been a lot of gang activity around here lately. It's the second shooting with them in a week. Be careful, keep your eyes open, they've already sent six loners to the afterlife.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_intro_7">
		<text>You didn't happen to hear what the military suddenly needed in the research building, did you? What are they doing out there today?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_intro_8">
		<text>Keep your eyes open! There's a bunch of thugs in the main building. They have no conscience or pity. If I could, I'd strangle them all!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_intro_9">
		<text>You don't want to go into the Dark Valley alone. The killers are nesting in one of the buildings. We're still trying to smoke them out. Don't get hurt, man!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_intro_help_1">
		<text>Brother, help!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_intro_help_10">
		<text>Somebody, help me!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_intro_help_11">
		<text>Guards, I'm hit! Come here!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_intro_help_12">
		<text>Help! I'm dying!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_intro_help_2">
		<text>Guys, I need a first aid kit!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_intro_help_3">
		<text>Get a first aid kit over here!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_intro_help_4">
		<text>Guys, this man has gone into shock! Hurry up!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_intro_help_5">
		<text>First aid kit, men!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_intro_help_6">
		<text>Somebody! Give me an first aid kit!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_intro_help_7">
		<text>Buddy, I need an first aid kit... first aid kit!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_intro_help_8">
		<text>Help, man!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_intro_help_9">
		<text>Share your first aid kit, buddy, huh?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_intro_help_13">
		<text>Hey, man, can I borrow your first aid kit?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_intro_help_14">
		<text>Man, you got a first aid kit?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_intro_help_15">
		<text>Bro, you got a first aid kit?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dm_intro_help_16">
		<text>Man, help me out!</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="list_trader_repair_0">
		<text>The cost of repairing the weapon in the first slot:</text>
	</string>
	<string id="list_trader_repair_1">
		<text>The cost of repairing the weapon in the second slot:</text>
	</string>
	<string id="list_trader_repair_2">
		<text>Cost to repair armor:</text>
	</string>


<!--****************************-->
<!-- Repair at the Barman's -->
<!--****************************-->
	<string id="bar_trader_repair_0">
		<text>Barkeep, you wouldn't happen to be a gunsmith, would you? (start here for your first session on 10/6/25 and don't forget to remove this reminder when you start)</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_trader_repair_1">
		<text>Truth be told... me, no. But I have a great gunsmith in my kitchen! So not only does he repair weapons, he repairs suits. So what are we gonna fix?\n\nA list of possible repairs:</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_trader_repair_2">
		<text>Repair the weapon in the first slot.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_trader_repair_3">
		<text>Repair the weapon in the second slot.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_trader_repair_4">
		<text>Repair the vest.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_trader_repair_5">
		<text>Shit, money's always tight. Let me come back later!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_trader_repair_6">
		<text>Here you go! Everything is fixed as far as it can be!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_trader_repair_7">
		<text>Here you go! Everything possible is done!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_trader_repair_8">
		<text>Your gunsmith really is a master! Give him my regards.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_trader_repair_9">
		<text>Great job indeed!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_trader_repair_10">
		<text>Is there anything else he can fix?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_trader_repair_11">
		<text>Of course, he doesn't have much work to do now anyway!\n\nA list of possible repairs:</text>
	</string>

</string_table>
