<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1251" ?>
<string_table>


 <string id="jresy_kill_desc"> 
 <text>There's a group of bandits at the Rostok factory. They call themselves the Dark Priests. We need to find them and destroy them.</text> 
 </string>

 <string id="descr_deadcity_paras_start"> 
 <text>The city of Shining Path, the abode of Freedom. Duty wants this place to be safer... what's that about?</text> 
 </string>




 <string id="zagony_text"> 
 <text>According to Snitch, there's a prison in the general vicinity near the Bar, located on a site behind the Rostok factory. The entrance to this prison must be found. That's where one of his men disappeared with the information Snitch needs.</text> 
 </string> 


<string id="mil2_freedom_commander_common2_0">
		<text>Hi. I'm back.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mil2_freedom_commander_common2_1">
		<text>Hey, stalker. What's the situation there?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mil2_freedom_commander_common2_2">
		<text>There's a couple zombies and some rats. Seems pretty calm.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mil2_freedom_commander_common2_3">
		<text>You sure? In that case, it might be a good idea to bring something heavier, just in case. Me and a buddy of mine have something stashed here that'll knock out a helicopter. Alright, what else you see out there?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mil2_freedom_commander_common2_4">
		<text>Well... as I was approaching the Rostok exit, a bloodsucker showed up. I think it was following me.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mil2_freedom_commander_common2_5">
		<text>Okay. Well, if that's the case, I think we can make it to the factory if we prepare.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mil2_freedom_commander_common2_6">
		<text>What's the plan of action?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mil2_freedom_commander_common2_7">
		<text>Like I said, we should prepare. Okay... right now we're waiting for the necessary equipment. When we're ready, I'll let you know. After that, we'll move to the site.</text>
	</string>


      <string id="carbar_0"> 
 <text>I'd like to purchase an automobile.</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="carbar_1"> 
 <text>Alright. There are several options to choose from.\nZaporozhets - 1000 rubles. It's old, but it seems to work. There's one, in a garage near the Bar.\nMoskvich - 2000 rubles. Stalkers from Pripyat brought it over here. Almost new... It's at Yantar in the automobile hangar near the scientist bunker.\nRAF - 6000 rubles. Here, near the Bar, you can find it in the field, near the entrance to the administrative building of the Rostok plant.\nKamaz - 8000 rubles. For serious transportation, this truck is the real deal, with good cross-country ability. There's one here, near the Bar.\nLada - 5000 rubles. It's good on the road in terms of how efficient it is with fuel, having about 130 liters worth of it, but it's not nearly as good offroad. The Lada here for sale is also near the Bar, in one of the garages.\nAnd the BTR - 15000 rubles. Don't ask I got one of these, I'm just selling it. It's here near the Bar. What do you want done with it? Although, you should show that you have enough money for this. Otherwise, we won't talk. And keep in mind one thing - you shouldn't leave cars unattended in the Zone, someone will steal it before you know it. It's here, near Bar, you can arrange with the guard at the entrance here to keep an eye on your car.</text> 
 </string> 


 <string id="carbar_2"> 
 <text>I'll take the Zaporozhets.</text> 
 </string> 

 <string id="carbar_moskvi"> 
 <text>I'll take the Moskvich.</text> 
 </string>

  <string id="carbar_lada"> 
 <text>I'll take the Lada.</text> 
 </string>

  <string id="carbar_rafik"> 
 <text>I'll take the RAF. (start here for your first session on 6/25/26 and don't forget to remove this when you start)</text> 
 </string>

  <string id="carbar_kamaz"> 
 <text>I think the Kamaz will be fine for me.</text> 
 </string>


  <string id="carbar_btr"> 
 <text>I'll take the APC.</text> 
 </string>


 <string id="carbar_3"> 
 <text>I changed my mind. Next time.</text> 
 </string> 





	<string id="bar_smazka_koolstory">
		<text>I see you're a responsible guy. I respect that. I can offer you a favor. in terms of weapons. You ever heard of nerds in the Swamps? No? They were there at one time. but they popped up. Once the rigs started working there, they got out, but I've been there a couple times. They're into some kind of weapons stuff, some kind of research. Anyway, They had this thing called gun lubricant. Well, it had a special effect - the barrel doesn't break from the shots! That's the thing. I used to visit them, so I managed to get some of this stuff. And I've got exactly one barrel left of this miracle solidol... As a token of my gratitude, for a symbolic sum of one thousand I can treat your machine gun, for example. Take it, it's useful, your gun will last you a long time.</text>
	</string>



	<string id="descr_bar_x16_documents">
		<text>Barkeep: We need to get into the laboratory in the Dark Valley and get the necessary documents from there. The entrance to the lab can tell one of the stalker groups there.</text>
	</string>


	<string id="mil_freedom_commander_common2_0">
		<text>Hi. From what group are you?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mil_freedom_commander_common2_1">
		<text>Hey, stalker. Listen, lone stalkers disappear without a trace inside the Rostok plant. The plant's been abandoned for years, veterans avoid Rostok, and the place is getting a bad reputation. A week ago, a group of three veteran stalkers disappeared inside. After that, several stalkers noticed a strange creature near one of the entrances to the factory.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mil_freedom_commander_common2_2">
		<text>Continue...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mil_freedom_commander_common2_3">
		<text>We're a group that's been wanting to sneak inside for a while now and find out what's going on.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mil_freedom_commander_common2_4">
		<text>Why would you do that?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mil_freedom_commander_common2_5">
		<text>The Barkeep's interested. Rumor has it there's a lot of interesting stuff inside the plant.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mil_freedom_commander_common2_6">
		<text>Can I help you?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mil_freedom_commander_common2_7">
		<text>Well, basically, yes. You need to sneak into Rostok and see what's going on there. But not to the factory site itself, but to the site behind it, here in Bar.</text>
	</string>




 <string id="bar_bar_osvedomitel_start_11">
        <text>Oh, hello... what do you want?</text>
    </string>

 <string id="bar_dolg_petrenko_start_11">
        <text>Hello... what do you want?</text>
    </string>


    <string id="doc_bar_11">
        <text>There was once a stalker named Gunslinger. He was a legend from the beginning, that he came from the outside world. Though he didn't like to talk about it himself.
Well, the Zone. it has a peculiar way of dealing with memory. Maybe it just encourages people to forget the past that doesn't suit them.
I, on the other hand, had already merged so much with the Zone that it treated me special now. The Zone not only accepted me, but also allowed, as a favorite child, all sorts of small liberties. In particular, I remember much more than most of the other inhabitants of the Zone. For example, where zombies come from. Strange as it may seem, the main mass was supplied not by the Controllers, or even by the RD units... The zombies were coming from somewhere in the north, there must be another city there, behind the force barrier of the RD units. Maybe that was the outside world where Gunslinger was originally from. But more likely it was another city. I vaguely remember that once the Professor and I, and the one who later became known as the Great Kree, also came from the City! But where is it and what is it, and why did they actually come to the Zone? And what is the Zone...? That remains to be seen...</text>
    </string>



    <string id="doc_bar_12">
        <text>Gunslinger was obsessed with the idea of finding out how the Zone works. And he managed to visit the city where the zombies come from. And somewhere nearby, according to the legends, was supposed to be the Black Monolith. But something there did not work out, somehow he crossed paths with the Angels of the Zone, the "uncles" of the "Sin" clan, for whom their "nephews" were worthless to them. And one day at dawn the zombies brought what was left of Gunslinger to my doorstep. And I actually put him back together virtually piece by piece. And Gunslinger stubbornly went north again...first time I've ever seen such stubborn people try to step on the same rake several times. Gunslinger already knew the legend of the Black Monolith, and even the version that it was a space tunnel. Or a time tunnel. After all, no one who had gone there had ever returned. Unless you count zombies, of course. I mean, they can't all be dead. But there's nothing in the Zone that can't happen. Anything can happen in the Zone.
And then there was a rumor that Gunslinger had returned in the Death Trucks and now he knew the truth about the Monolith. Not everyone believed that he was completely oblivious to it. I examined what the Trucks had delivered several times. The stalkers' bodies had been subjected to something monstrous. Surely something similar had been done to the consciousness, it could even be determined by the altered structure of the brain, but in practice it could not be confirmed, the Death Trucks were so named because so far they had only found dead people in them.
But the Journalist, he was strange, he was looking for something special. In particular, he, one of the few, believed in the legend of the children of the Zone. He'd actually met Gunslinger before both of them got into trouble. Each in their own, of course, but the Journalist seemed to be less fortunate. What's more, the Journalist had managed to dig up some papers somewhere that supposedly dealt with memory. Some kind of special experiments. And it was the Journalist who scattered certain information tags across the Zone. He believed that these tags would at some point help Gunslinger get to the Monolith. Despite the rather detailed information, Gunslinger did not feel satisfied. So far, all he had learned in crumbs was what he had done before, what he was looking for, what he wanted. And it was not at all clear why he had done it and why he had done it. And the deeper past was still there... or rather, as if it never existed!</text>
    </string>



    <string id="bar_ryaboy_medik_art">
        <text>Need a first aid kit for a zombified...</text>
    </string>

 <string id="osved_brainzomb_sha_colstoty">
        <text>Uh... I don't think so. But wait, I think there was one who came in about seven days ago and showed me something that looked like documents. I didn't take it, I didn't want to mess with it... It looked like what you wanted. I don't know where the guy is now, but, uh, I can help. I can give you two options. Okay, first one. I'll conduct a little search, try to find him using my channels. Once I do, I'll get a lead on his location. It won't cost you that much, just five grand. Or the second option, I'll use my powers to the max and get you those documents. I mean, you'll buy them from me, so to speak. It'll cost you fifteen grand. What's up?</text>
    </string>

 <string id="wolfbar1t">
        <text>Yeah, here's our bar. There's the buffalo. They say he's the one that has been the furthest north. He even saw the outline of the power plant. the heart of the Zone. And there's Hmyr, he's a bit of an "a-hole", but he managed to survive being exposed to the radiation from the RD unit. Usually the effects are similar to those of the Controller, and what's left after that can't be considered human at all. But the Dick's okay. He's alive, but he's weird.</text>
    </string>

    <string id="wolfbar2t">
        <text>With a relatively empty head, new information is much easier to digest. Even if some of the words look like mysterious abbreviations, and some of them are perceived as meaningless symbols. By the way, maybe you can tell me what's outside the Zone?</text>
    </string>

    <string id="wolfbar3t">
        <text>You shouldn't treat him like that. He's Rat 5, but unlike the previous ones, he's been in this place for more than half a year. And as you can see, there are plenty of people who want his place. But what's more, he's organized an uninterrupted supply of food and ammunition--</text>
    </string>

    <string id="wolfbar4t">
        <text>There's no way I had nothing to do with Gunslinger. A lot of people knew him, even Rat was afraid of him. But I, strangely enough, no one remembers me. But this can't be possible - the death trucks come from the very depths of the Zone - so I was there, and to go there unnoticed... Something's wrong! I couldn't have come from the north. Maybe I did, maybe I didn't. Tell me, Wolf, do you like living in the Zone?</text>
    </string>

    <string id="wolfbar5t">
        <text>A lot of stalkers have tried to get past RD installations. Some say they did. But no one's seen them since. You're the first, not counting zombies, to ride in the trucks of death with almost no visible damage. Speaking of zombies, there are a few in the neighborhood, looking for you.</text>
    </string>

    <string id="wolfbar6t">
        <text>Many will try to fall on your tail as you move towards the power plant, Rat in particular. The black monolith is something akin to oil and diamonds: where it is, there is greed, betrayal and death. People are not even frightened by what they say: as if it fulfills only the underlying, most cherished dreams. And can't we, living in such conditions, be suspected, for example, of an underlying desire... self-destruction?</text>
    </string>

 	<string id="bar_pdarstalker_story"> 
 	<text>Oh, that's respect for the old man. Now, listen to me. I told you I've been a lot of places, and believe it or not, I've been to the power plant too. It's dead quiet. not a soul. Only occasionally in the distance I heard the howling of the zombies. I approached the power plant itself, and I saw the Dark One - he was standing on the roof of the sarcophagus, looking into the distant bloody glow... And then a flash. And that was it. I woke up at Freedom's base, I don't even know how I got there. But I was there, all the regulars will tell you! In general, Hmyr in the bar can still tell you something about the northern territories, ask him...</text> 
 	</string> 

 <string id="magnet_five_final_done_0">
        <text>I think I've fired a few hundred rounds.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="magnet_five_final_done_1">
        <text>Well, uh-- Yeah. Hmm, and there's hardly any fouling. Interesting. Well, I guess that pretty much sums up our mission here in the zone. Mostly thanks to you, of course, stalker. </text>
    </string>
    <string id="magnet_five_final_done_2">
        <text>You're leaving the zone?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="magnet_five_final_done_3">
        <text>Yeah, we've already got a transport helicopter from the Big Land following us. I hear there's something strange going on in the cities. Rumor has it that zombies have been seen near the big cities. It's weird. Still, I'm glad we're finally getting out of this barracks.  </text>
    </string>
    <string id="magnet_five_final_done_4">
        <text>What about my reward?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="magnet_five_final_done_5">
        <text>I have something for you. An extremely rare item. Our research institute has been allocated one for the entire group. It's a professional anomaly detector. Luckily we didn't have to use it, so I'm giving it to you in good conscience. You're unlikely to find one like it anywhere else.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="magnet_five_final_done_6">
        <text>Thank you.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="magnet_five_final_done_7">
        <text>Well. This concludes our cooperation with you. All the best to you, stalker. Don't take any unnecessary risks. </text>
    </string>


 <string id="bar_pre_doks_talkerd_article_tx"> 
 <text>Stalker's Bar</text> 
 </string> 

 <string id="bar_pre_doks_talkerd_article_text"> 
 <text>Made it to Bar. It seems to be a former settlement. And there were people living here before the disaster. Still, their houses haven't been empty for long. The Barkeep needs a few days to decipher the documents from the roadblock... In the meantime, he asked me to visit Toad at the cordon. I wonder what he's gonna do this time.</text> 
 </string> 





    <string id="magnet_start_q_five_0">
        <text>I brought the rifle. </text>
    </string>
    <string id="magnet_start_q_five_1">
        <text>Great news! Perhaps I should bring you up to speed. As I was saying, our research is almost at an end, but we've received another important order from the military.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="magnet_start_q_five_10">
        <text>Good.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="magnet_start_q_five_2">
        <text>Is it related to this weapon?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="magnet_start_q_five_3">
        <text>Get to the bottom of it! Now, why we need a rifle from you is for collateral. I'm sure you know it's a rare item. A fellow stalker of yours has already brought one, and we've made a prototype for you to test. </text>
    </string>
    <string id="magnet_start_q_five_4">
        <text>What's the specialty of your design?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="magnet_start_q_five_5">
        <text>Well, I will not reveal all the cards... I will say, it is some modification of the barrel with the properties of the Magnet. First of all, in theory, it should increase the killing power. Second, the bullet should have more momentum. However, there are concerns about the velocity of the bullet, which may be slightly reduced...</text>
    </string>
    <string id="magnet_start_q_five_6">
        <text>So what's required of me?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="magnet_start_q_five_7">
        <text>Well, let's just say to perform some tests on this weapon. Stress test it, and most importantly, fire a few hundred rounds with it. That's the main task. </text>
    </string>
    <string id="magnet_start_q_five_8">
        <text>Okay, I'll do it.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="magnet_start_q_five_9">
        <text>Alright, great. Now, give me your rifle, it'll be collateral for us if anything happens to you, or whatever. Yeah. Anyway, when you're done with the test, come back.</text>
    </string>





    <string id="magnet_start_q_four_done_0">
        <text>Hello. Here, I think this is what you asked for.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="magnet_start_q_four_done_1">
        <text>Wait a second. Yes, this is indeed the battery. Where did you manage to get it? Would you care to share that information? </text>
    </string>
    <string id="magnet_start_q_four_done_2">
        <text>I don't think you need to worry about that. My mission was to find this ammunition, mission accomplished.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="magnet_start_q_four_done_3">
        <text>Alright, well, what about the artifact? Did you get it?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="magnet_start_q_four_done_4">
        <text>Yes, I got it. </text>
    </string>
    <string id="magnet_start_q_four_done_5">
        <text>Alright, then. Come on, this way. You are a very, very capable young man. People like you are worth their weight in gold around here. I predict a great future for you.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="magnet_start_q_four_done_6">
        <text>Thank you. What about payment?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="magnet_start_q_four_done_7">
        <text>Uh, yes. Payment! Our friends in the military presented us with something. We don't need that pipe at all. But for you. who knows, it might come in handy. Or at the very least, I'm sure a dutyer will offer you good money for it.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="magnet_start_q_four_done_8">
        <text>Thank you. What about your next assignment?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="magnet_start_q_four_done_9">
        <text>Oh, it's a beauty. Your efficiency is to be envied. So. I'd say our task is almost complete, and quite successfully. Much to your credit, of course. However, there is one last favor to ask of you. I won't go into details, I'll just inform you that you'd be kind enough to bring a VSS rifle, aka Vintorez, to our next meeting. I think our last collaboration will leave you with good memories of our work together.  </text>
    </string>







    <string id="magnet_start_q_tri_done_0">
        <text>So what about my special award?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="magnet_start_q_tri_done_1">
        <text>Yeah, yeah, hi. All in all, it's going pretty well. Thanks to you, we've almost managed to bring our main experiment to its final stage.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="magnet_start_q_tri_done_2">
        <text>Go on.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="magnet_start_q_tri_done_3">
        <text>Well, as I said, it's going pretty well. Our calculations show that 75% of our task here in the zone has been accomplished. However, there's still work to be done, and it's not to say there's not a lot of work to be done.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="magnet_start_q_tri_done_4">
        <text>I understand, let's get down to business.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="magnet_start_q_tri_done_5">
        <text>I like your approach. To the point. Our institute received an order from an overseas company to develop high-capacity rechargeable batteries. Perhaps you've heard of Zombified stalker fanatics? Or maybe you've come face-to-face with them? It doesn't matter. The point is that they are rumored to have some kind of weapon that uses high-capacity batteries as a combat charge. Sort of like a Gauss weapon.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="magnet_start_q_tri_done_6">
        <text>Is that the kind of weapon you want to get your hands on?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="magnet_start_q_tri_done_7">
        <text>No. Not exactly a weapon. It's the charges that we're interested in. Using our research in magnetic properties, we could create something more effective. In theory, of course. We need one sample of the Magnet artifact, as usual, plus one sample of this Gauss weapon battery. It doesn't have to be fully charged, just get us that battery. </text>
    </string>
    <string id="magnet_start_q_tri_done_8">
        <text>Alright, I'll try.</text>
    </string>




 <string id="dok_mag_1"> 
 <text>Good afternoon, stalker. Yes, you make a good point. We're a small scientific group that's formed here on Duty's territory. It's a safe place, and we get a lot of support from the group. You see, some of the security services are interested in our work.</text> 
 </string> 




 <string id="dok_mag_2"> 
 <text>Our group is studying a type of so-called anomalous formations. Locals call it the Magnet artifact. Here's the data for your PDA. It describes its basic properties. The thing is, this anomalous formation has very interesting properties in terms of anti-gravity waves, which we're studying. I would like to inform you that at the moment we have a shortage of material for research, so if you have these anomalous formations, we will be able to conduct the experiments we need. If the experiment is successful, we can reward you in a special way.</text> 
 </string> 



 <string id="dok_mag_3"> 
 <text>One of the overseas corporations that specializes in the study and production of holograms is interested in the illusory properties of this anomalous specimen. They promised us in case of success of the research to allocate additional equipment, which is extremely necessary for further research...</text> 
 </string> 




 <string id="deathcomesrippingbarzom_0"> 
 <text>Hello, General. I thought you wanted to see me.</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="deathcomesrippingbarzom_1"> 
 <text>So you came after all. Good. We need serious fighters like you. Between you and me, our fighters are in a bad mood right now, and having a new comrade like you would be great for us.</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="deathcomesrippingbarzom_2"> 
 <text>Shit, there's a wave of zombies coming out of Rostok. Where the fuck are they coming from? Where? You, this is a good time for me to tell you. We've got a machine gun nest set up, I'll get it loaded with ammo and you can go.</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="deathcomesrippingbarzom_3"> 
 <text>Okay, machine gun. Got it.</text> 
 </string> 


 <string id="aafde423"> 
 <text>Actually, you know, it's not all that fatal out there. Stalkers are out there, some of them are not exactly alive, and they're not exactly friendly. Still, I don't remember anyone coming back from there alive lately.</text> 
 </string> 



 <string id="gravartsmnb2_0"> 
 <text>I need a strong gravitational artifact.</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="gravartsmnb2_1"> 
 <text>Alright, give me the artifact crossbreeder device and the money. five grand. So, uh. you got everything?</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="gravartsmnb2_2"> 
 <text>Yeah, I got it all, here you go.</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="gravartsmnb2_3"> 
 <text>Here you go, the process was a success. If you need more, I'm here for you.</text> 
 </string> 




 <string id="gravartsmnb_0"> 
 <text>What kind of artifacts do you have here?</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="gravartsmnb_1"> 
 <text>Uh, yeah, I had a device. Artifact crossbreeder. Now all I have in my PDA is the recipe for the Strong gravitational artifact from it. If you have the device, I can do the transmutation. The ingredients for the transmutation will be mine, all you need is the device and 5,000 rubles.</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="gravartsmnb_2"> 
 <text>Okay, I'll keep that in mind.</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="gravartsmnb_3"> 
 <text>Yeah. It's a good thing, this artifact. Helps you carry a few pounds of more stuff, as I recall.</text> 
 </string> 








 <string id="stgraugdhs_0"> 
 <text>I need something.</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="stgraugdhs_1"> 
 <text>You? What's that?</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="stgraugdhs_2"> 
 <text>A gravity shotgun. I think you're the only one who can make one.</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="stgraugdhs_3"> 
 <text>Yeah, okay. But I need artifacts. A strong gravitational artifact. Two of them. You get it, we'll talk.</text> 
 </string> 




 <string id="ribkaprstugdhs_0"> 
 <text>Got artifacts.</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="ribkaprstugdhs_1"> 
 <text>For a shotgun? Alright, give it to me.</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="ribkaprstugdhs_2"> 
 <text>...</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="ribkaprstugdhs_3"> 
 <text>Take your shotgun and get out of here.</text> 
 </string> 



 <string id="grartgraugdhs_0"> 
 <text>I need something. A gravity glove.</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="grartgraugdhs_1"> 
 <text>We have it, we can give it to you. But not for nothing. We found a lot of things like that in this place...</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="grartgraugdhs_2"> 
 <text>What do you want?</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="grartgraugdhs_3"> 
 <text>We need artifacts. A strong gravitational artifact. Two. You bring it, we'll talk.</text> 
 </string>


 <string id="ribk22prstugdhs_0"> 
 <text>About the Gravity Glove.</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="ribk22prstugdhs_1"> 
 <text>You got it? Okay, give it to me.</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="ribk22prstugdhs_2"> 
 <text>...</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="ribk22prstugdhs_3"> 
 <text>Take it.</text> 
 </string> 





 <string id="zzgmetalkisghtikz_0"> 
 <text>Thank you, stalker!</text> 
 </string> 

 <string id="zzzzsngtfrghtikz_0"> 
 <text>Oh, shit. What happened to him?</text> 
 </string> 


 <string id="zzzzsnikz_0"> 
 <text>Hello.</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="zzzzsnikz_1"> 
 <text>Hello. Have you been able to find out anything about the missing group?</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="zzzzsnikz_2"> 
 <text>The group was captured by Sin, as you suspected. I managed to rescue them.</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="zzzzsnikz_01"> 
 <text>Yes, I'm picking up their signal! I think they're already here. Thank you, stalker! You did a great job! As a thank you, as promised, there will be a car outside the bunker. You can have it. Thanks again!</text> 
 </string> 




 <string id="prstugdhs_0"> 
 <text>I found what you asked for.</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="prstugdhs_1"> 
 <text>Really? They're lucky you walked by.</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="prstugdhs_2"> 
 <text>Can they be free now?</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="prstugdhs_3"> 
 <text>Yes, we'll let them go after a while... There's something we need to do with them before we let them go. Go, we'll keep our word.</text> 
 </string> 




 <string id="stugdhs_0"> 
 <text>Who's in the next room?</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="stugdhs_1"> 
 <text>Do you care? A group of scientists. Went to the wrong place at the wrong time. Just in time for our ritual to begin. Their heads will come in handy.</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="stugdhs_2"> 
 <text>Wait, you want their heads? No, that's no good. I want to buy them back from you.</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="stugdhs_3"> 
 <text>Buy them back?! You can't help us with money. Although, if you need it that badly. Bring three dead heads and they'll be free.</text> 
 </string> 




 <string id="hhhnikz_0"> 
 <text>Are there any tasks for payment?</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="hhhnikz_1"> 
 <text>Uh... Yeah. Within a month, we sent four teams to different parts of the Zone to investigate. The first one died on Cordon, near the tower. The second was the one you found in the City. One disappeared here, at the lake, but the fourth, we don't know its fate yet...</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="hhhnikz_2"> 
 <text>Go on.</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="hhhnikz_01"> 
 <text>All I know is that they disappeared in the Silent Hills. You know who's running the place, don't you? Those lunatics, the Sinners? I suppose it's possible they're at their base and may still be alive. If you're there, try to help our group. They're the only personnel we have left. Help us, and you'll get a special reward.</text> 
 </string> 






 <string id="silgrav_0"> 
 <text>I guess now we can talk about why I'm here.</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="silgrav_1"> 
 <text>Messer, you are certainly a very valuable specimen. You've certainly done a very good job for us, but listen. In order for us to make business contact with you regarding your case, get me two strong gravitational artifacts. After that, we can talk.</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="silgrav_2"> 
 <text>I'll try. But where do I find them?</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="silgrav_01"> 
 <text>At the gravitational anomalies. You're not new to the Zone! Or you could generate one yourself. You know, there are these things that synthesize artifacts from several others. Keep in mind that the artifacts need to be identified by an expert, or else I won't accept them from you. Alright, you find the artifacts, then we'll talk about the rest.</text> 
 </string> 



 <string id="psilgrav_0"> 
 <text>Here's your artifacts. I hope I can talk to you now.</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="psilgrav_1"> 
 <text>Well done, stalker. I think we're gonna get along just fine. I understand you and the Barkeep are having a conversation about those papers you found in the lab under the Dark Valley. I don't mind discussing those findings, but my time is valuable. So you're gonna have to do a little more work for us. You're all for it, aren't you?</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="psilgrav_2"> 
 <text>What do you mean?</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="psilgrav_01"> 
 <text>The usual stalker routine. You're a good fighter, a natural. I think I've even seen you before. but where-- But that's not important. Let's get to work.</text> 
 </string> 



 <string id="yaabneayb_0"> 
 <text>Got another job?	</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="yaabneayb_1"> 
 <text>You ever heard of the Sinners? Totally badass dudes. Rumor has it they're holed up in the Hills somewhere near Radar. The leader's not even human. He was one of the first stalkers in the Zone. In short, it's one of the oldest groups in the Zone, they've been here since before all this happened. So, I know that at their base, there on the Hills, there is a building with various documents. Anyway, there's something I need. One folder of documents. Maybe you can get it?</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="yaabneayb_2"> 
 <text>I'll try, but no promises.</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="yaabneayb_01"> 
 <text>Thank you! If you can get it, be careful with it.</text> 
 </string> 



 <string id="mnb_0"> 
 <text>Here, take a look at this folder.</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="mnb_1"> 
 <text>So... You were able to steal it from the base? Well done, stalker. This is going to help us a lot with our, uh, exploration of the Zone. I heard there was a bit of a commotion at their base. You don't know about it?</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="mnb_2"> 
 <text>I had one not so pleasant experience with these people. What about payment?</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="mnb_01"> 
 <text>Uh, yeah, sure. Thanks again for your help.</text> 
 </string> 





 <string id="ggzxroz_0"> 
 <text>Look, there's something. Are you interested in a false eye?</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="ggzxroz_1"> 
 <text>Hmm. It's rare! In the Zone, if anyone needs it... Anyway, come on, 500 rubles.</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="ggzxroz_2"> 
 <text>Here.</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="ggzxroz_01"> 
 <text>Interesting thing. You'll need it. Come over sometime, we'll play pool with you. You're running around the Zone like a madman.</text> 
 </string> 




 <string id="zxrpozsskayb_0"> 
 <text>I got some bad news for you.</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="zxrpozsskayb_1"> 
 <text>What? What do you mean?</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="zxrpozsskayb_2"> 
 <text>I found your brother. He's dead. He's in a lab under the Dark Valley.</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="zxrpozsskayb_01"> 
 <text>Stalker. Thank you. Я... I don't know how. Just leave me now.</text> 
 </string> 




 <string id="nzombar_koshak_start_0"> 
 <text>I think I found it.</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="nzombar_koshak_start_1"> 
 <text>Sta-a-alke-el, you-you-you. Thank you.</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="nzombar_koshak_start_2"> 
 <text>No problem, buddy.</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="nzombar_koshak_start_01"> 
 <text>     T-t-t-t-t-t-t-t-too do-mi-k-a.</text> 
 </string> 



 <string id="zombar_koshak_start_0"> 
 <text>Zombie? Human? Can you hear me?</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="zombar_koshak_start_1"> 
 <text>Sta-alke-er, help me! Please!</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="zombar_koshak_start_2"> 
 <text>What do you want?</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="zombar_koshak_start_01"> 
 <text>I had a cat, a big cat. She was always helpful. But she got lost! Find her!</text> 
 </string> 






 <string id="svdodddkz_0"> 
 <text>The Professor sent you, didn't he?</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="svdodddkz_1"> 
 <text>Yes. And I'm interested in something.</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="svdodddkz_2"> 
 <text>Interested in something... I'm interested in something too. These scientists have placed the radiation from their fucking Psi machine right in front of our base. Which is not good. Our people say the radiation is growing, it'll reach the base soon! Anyway, they're doing something in the hut on the left side of the road to the Hills... I don't want to send my men there. There's so much radiation there, the grass is vaporized. Why don't you go down there and see if you can turn that shit off? We'll talk after. I'm sorry, I have a shipment coming in.</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="svdodddkz_01"> 
 <text>Alright.</text> 
 </string> 





 <string id="dodddkz_0"> 
 <text>Doctor?</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="dodddkz_1"> 
 <text>Yeah. I knew you'd come.</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="dodddkz_2"> 
 <text>I have a few questions.</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="dodddkz_01"> 
 <text>Not all at once. I need your help. Afterwards, I'll help you with your questions. Listen up! A stalker wandered into the swamps here. He's been lying by the fisherman's cabin to the east for half a day. Bring him here. But don't take him inside, let him sit on the porch.</text> 
 </string> 



 <string id="mzdodddkz_0"> 
 <text>Hey, you okay?</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="mzdodddkz_1"> 
 <text>Ah? Who's there? Stalker! Shit, help! I came from Radar. There, there's, uh, radiation!</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="mzdodddkz_2"> 
 <text>I've got it. There's a doctor nearby, I think he can help you!</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="mzdodddkz_01"> 
 <text>Doctor?! Yes, hurry up.</text> 
 </string> 



 <string id="pdodddkz_0"> 
 <text>Doctor, I brought him. He says he's come from Radar.</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="pdodddkz_1"> 
 <text>I'll keep him outside for a while. Go and find out where he's from and who he is, and check his things.</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="pdodddkz_2"> 
 <text>Okay, got it.</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="pdodddkz_01"> 
 <text>Wait, there's more! After you talk to that stalker, go to the trader. His name is Toad. Maybe you already know him. He's a rookie to the Hills. You need to pick up a strange-looking container and bring it to me. If you do, you'll get a free treatment from me.</text> 
 </string> 


 <string id="dopdodddkz_0"> 
 <text>First things first. Who are you and where are you from?</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="dopdodddkz_1"> 
 <text>Ah? I'm Bullfrog. Me and a group from Shining Path went out toward Radar through the warehouses. But there, it's literally mind-blowing. I don't know how I got out in the dark and came here. I crossed a broken bridge, had to swim across the river.</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="dopdodddkz_2"> 
 <text>So, I see you don't have anything special. Machine gun, walkie-talkie. Right. The Doctor needs something to take you in. I'll bring him this stuff after the Doctor sees you.</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="dopdodddkz_01"> 
 <text>Yeah, okay. Thank you.</text> 
 </string> 



 <string id="jopdodddkz_0"> 
 <text>Toad, hello. Doctor sent me.</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="jopdodddkz_1"> 
 <text>Come from the swamps, have you? You're a real piece of work, lad. I thought you wouldn't last a couple of days in the Zone, and here you are! Alright, take it, the Doctor's reported you.</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="jopdodddkz_2"> 
 <text>Shit. How much does it weigh?</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="jopdodddkz_01"> 
 <text>You'd think. If it doesn't fit, put your stuff in the bedside table, you can take it back later. It's not going anywhere. I guess.</text> 
 </string> 




 <string id="hjopdodddkz_0"> 
 <text>Doctor, I've got what you asked for.</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="hjopdodddkz_1"> 
 <text>Good. Well, one more errand, then I'll answer your questions.</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="hjopdodddkz_2"> 
 <text>Good.</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="hjopdodddkz_01"> 
 <text>That stalker seems to be getting better. He said he was traveling with a group from the city. Maybe he's a member of some kind of group. Go down to the city and ask around about him.</text> 
 </string> 



 <string id="zzhjopdodddkz_0"> 
 <text>Hey, you know Bullfrog?</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="zzhjopdodddkz_1"> 
 <text>What? I know him, yeah. He disappeared on Radar a while back with a group. We used to send units up north at one time, one of them was rumored to have even gotten into the power plant. They found some documents, but they were lost there.</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="zzhjopdodddkz_2"> 
 <text>The Doctor's got him in the swamp. Alive.</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="zzhjopdodddkz_01"> 
 <text>Oh, dear. We'd already said goodbye to him, and then... Oh, such great news! Well, give the Doctor our thanks. I think what he learned there will be useful to us. We'll have to get in touch with him, have him send him back to us when he's back on his feet.</text> 
 </string> 






 <string id="nnnnnikz_0"> 
 <text>I think it's this knife.</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="nnnnnikz_1"> 
 <text>Yeah, that's the one. Good job. You've been a great help to me on this case. Why don't you have a drink? It's on me. It's a good occasion. I've been wanting this thing for a long time. I've got a collection of knives.</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="nnnnnikz_2"> 
 <text>You wanted to share information, didn't you?</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="nnnnnikz_01"> 
 <text>Don't you respect me? Well, well, well, look. You're looking for Gunslinger, right? Long story short, I heard in a bar from a stalker, in a robe or cloak, badly beaten up, that Gunslinger had hideouts in several places. Like at the Research Institute and here in the Rostok catacombs. Our guys are digging there now, so maybe the closed tunnels are accessible now. Alright, walk on, teetotaler. before the first anomaly.</text> 
 </string> 


 <string id="nnnnnikz_0133"> 
 <text>Uh, huh. let me see. Is that the right knife? You didn't mix it up? Okay, I'll believe it. but I'll check.  You're looking for Gunslinger, right? To make a long story short, I heard in a bar from a stalker, in a robe or cloak, that Gunslinger had hideouts in several places. Like at the Research Institute and here in the Rostok catacombs. Our guys are digging there now, so maybe the closed tunnels are accessible now. Alright, walk on, teetotaler. before the first anomaly.</text> 
 </string> 


 <string id="nloudmoth_0"> 
 <text>Is there any other work?</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="nloudmoth_1"> 
 <text>For you, I'll always find an adventure. Yeah. You need to find a knife in the basement of the Rostok factory, which was lost by a stalker, one of my so-called regulars... Now there are stalkers cleaning out those cellars after you killed that bloodsucker, and this guy I know is with them. I think he lost it in one of the catacomb rooms. He was drinking himself into a stupor last night when he noticed he'd lost it.</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="nloudmoth_2"> 
 <text>I'll look for it. What about payment?</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="nloudmoth_01"> 
 <text>I hear you're looking for someone. I think you'll find this information useful. Bring the knife and we'll talk.</text> 
 </string> 



 <string id="loudmoth_0"> 
 <text>You okay, stalker? Did you send the SOS?</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="loudmoth_1"> 
 <text>Yes... Help me, damn it. I ran away from that military base, I don't think it was the military at all! I don't think they were even human!</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="loudmoth_2"> 
 <text>What are you talking about?</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="loudmoth_01"> 
 <text>We were coming from Bar. They were following us. They took us to their base. They put Sergei on a pole. One of them was doing some kind of ritual. Shit, after that, I think my brains went to shit! Ahh.</text> 
 </string> 



 <string id="device_pda_uchenyh_deadcity_desc"> 
 <text>Last entry: Shit, I think there's a military raid on this house. The memory also contains information about psi installations in Lake Yantar, the swamp area, and the Pripyat area. There is mention of the Black Monolith project, but the information is encrypted.</text> 
 </string>


 <string id="duudpomosnikz_0"> 
 <text>About the missing group of scientists in the city.</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="duudpomosnikz_1"> 
 <text>What about them? Just tell me what you found.</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="duudpomosnikz_2"> 
 <text>Yeah, I think they hid in the attic of one of the houses when the military stalkers cleared the city. Here, they had this PDA on them. I have no idea why the military attacked your group.</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="duudpomosnikz_01"> 
 <text>Probably for this information. Well, alright. Thank you. Goddamn, it's a real mess with these groups.</text> 
 </string> 



 <string id="zuudpomosnikz_0"> 
 <text>Do you have a job?</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="zuudpomosnikz_1"> 
 <text>A week ago, a group of scientists went into town to make observations and disappeared. It's hard to say what could have happened to them. The city's crawling with zombies and whatnot. Besides, our people aren't very good fighters. We don't have anyone to search for them. We need to find the scientists or their corpses and find the results of the observations, if there are any.</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="zuudpomosnikz_2"> 
 <text>Alright, I'll try to find them.</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="zuudpomosnikz_01"> 
 <text>Anything you find, bring it back here to the bunker.</text> 
 </string> 
 



 <string id="dpomosnikz_0"> 
 <text>Look, is this it or not?</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="dpomosnikz_1"> 
 <text>What? You-- Did you find it?! Where?</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="dpomosnikz_2"> 
 <text>Someone gave it to me. Anyway, it doesn't matter, just take it. I realize it's important to you.</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="dpomosnikz_01"> 
 <text>Stalker. I don't know what to say to you! Thank you. I'll tell the Professor to let you into the bunker. Here. take this, I'm really grateful for what you did...</text> 
 </string> 




 <string id="pomosnikz_0"> 
 <text>Hello.</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="pomosnikz_1"> 
 <text>Ah? What do you want? The professor's not in today. You can turn around and get out of here!</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="pomosnikz_2"> 
 <text>Take it easy. I have an assignment from the Barkeep. Why are you so nervous?</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="pomosnikz_3"> 
 <text>What?! No reason. She's gone, you know? She's gone. She's missing, in that damn lab under the Dark Valley! I wish I could find the pendant I gave her. The silver one.</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="pomosnikz_4"> 
 <text>...</text> 
 </string> 




 <string id="prpozsskayb_0"> 
 <text>Well, I think we're here.</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="prpozsskayb_1"> 
 <text>Yeah. Thanks for your help, Messer. Here's your spacesuit, you earned it.</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="prpozsskayb_2"> 
 <text>Appreciate it.</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="prpozsskayb_01"> 
 <text>Here's the Professor's assistant, by the way. He's a little out of it. He had a wife, but she died. She had a special pendant, but it wasn't found near her body. She died in some lab under the Dark Valley. So now he's dreaming about that pendant. Alright, well, thank you.</text> 
 </string> 





 <string id="pozsskayb_0"> 
 <text>Zyablikov? What's up?</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="pozsskayb_1"> 
 <text>Hello again. Hey, Messer, can you walk me back to camp? I know the way. The road here is not very quiet, I'm afraid I can't make it alone... We'll go together, and you can find out where our habitat is.</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="pozsskayb_2"> 
 <text>Okay, let's go.</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="pozsskayb_01"> 
 <text>Great! When we get there, I'll give you one of our spacesuits, as promised.</text> 
 </string> 




 <string id="zsskayb_0"> 
 <text>Here's the paperwork.</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="zsskayb_1"> 
 <text>Well, well, well. I don't get it! What's the lab? Is he alive? Why haven't we been informed? What's going on?</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="zsskayb_2"> 
 <text>Calm down. What about the outfit?</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="zsskayb_01"> 
 <text>I'm sorry, I got a little overexcited. I've got to get back to Yantar. If you get a chance, stop by the science camp to pick up the suit.</text> 
 </string> 




      <string id="zcddaqiyorbar_0"> 
 <text>Hi. What kind of suit are you wearing? Science suit?</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="zcddaqiyorbar_1"> 
 <text>Yeah, it's special. Airtight. It'll protect you from all kinds of chemicals! You want one? For one favor.</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="zcddaqiyorbar_2"> 
 <text>What kind?</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="zcddaqiyorbar_3"> 
 <text>I used to have a brother who worked at the factory, Vanya, or rather Ivan Ivanovich. I had a big fight with him once, over nothing, I went away for a long time. When I came back, I found out that everyone had been evacuated from the plant, but Vanya had not returned. The administration somehow tried to talk themselves out of it, saying that he had either run away or died in the factory. The family burned out all their nerves. Later I received a letter from the Research Institute, an invitation to participate in an expedition in the Zone, or rather, in its protection. I thought to refuse, but I remembered that the plant is also in the Zone, and I had nothing to lose. In short, for the fact that you go to Rostok and find documents that may say something about my brother, or my brother himself, or his personal belongings, I give you a suit. Alright?</text> 
 </string>
 <string id="zcddaqiyorbar_4"> 
 <text>Alright. I'll see what I can find out.</text> 
 </string>





 <string id="cddaqiyorbar_0"> 
 <text>No work?</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="cddaqiyorbar_1"> 
 <text>There's a site on Bar, behind the factory, near the dam. There's a curious Kamaz there. We should bring it here, but nobody wants to do it. Two have already tried, but disappeared... Still, Rostok's not far away, and it's not a pleasant place.</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="cddaqiyorbar_2"> 
 <text>I can try it.</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="cddaqiyorbar_3"> 
 <text>You're a dashing fellow, I see. Go on, then. It's parked over there by the court, bring it over here to the bar. Don't worry about paying for it.</text> 
 </string>
 <string id="cddaqiyorbar_4"> 
 <text>Alright.</text> 
 </string>



 <string id="casskayb_0"> 
 <text>The Kamaz is here at the bar.</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="casskayb_1"> 
 <text>Good boy, keep your-- Anything suspicious? Maybe some cargo? Or anything else?</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="casskayb_2"> 
 <text>Not that I saw. Just a bloodsucker. Maybe from Rostok.</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="casskayb_01"> 
 <text>Alright, then. It's not news. We'll take the car to the parking lot. You're free to go.</text> 
 </string> 




 <string id="ddaqiyorbar_0"> 
 <text>Good day to you. I think I've accomplished your mission.</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="ddaqiyorbar_1"> 
 <text>Shit, you're alive. I can't believe it, and I don't know how you did it. No matter what anyone says, I'm sure you're-- you're the chosen one. And now you're a full-fledged comrade of the group.</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="ddaqiyorbar_2"> 
 <text>...</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="ddaqiyorbar_3"> 
 <text>Well, like I said, we're happy to have you. You are now officially a member of our faction. Here, take a special set of gear... Now, the current rumor is that there's a partially open path to the north. I think you know what that is. Then again, like I said, maybe that's where you'll find your Gunslinger. Anyway, The Barkeep and I have an agreement for an expedition into the radar territory. He's put you in charge of the expedition, which I'm all for. Talk to him about it.</text> 
 </string>
 <string id="ddaqiyorbar_4"> 
 <text>Serving Duty.</text> 
 </string>




 <string id="sskayb_0"> 
 <text>Listen, I need some of your irradiated bolts. Can you spare some?</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="sskayb_1"> 
 <text>You know. I could, why not? You owe me one thousand rubles for eight pieces.</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="sskayb_2"> 
 <text>Come on, it's a deal.</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="sskayb_01"> 
 <text>Come on, for that kind of money!</text> 
 </string> 



 <string id="skayb_0"> 
 <text>Listen, what are those boxes you have? And artifacts?</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="skayb_1"> 
 <text>Just think, the freedom fighters found ten crates of bolts on Rostok. Not just any bolts, but some kind of irradiated bolts. Anyway, they're supposed to take them back to the Big Land, so I'm keeping an eye on them. As for artifacts, I synthesized them once. I had a portable transmuter, I even have the recipes in my PDA. By the way, our leader has all the recipes from the known ones, if you're interested.</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="skayb_2"> 
 <text>Okay, I'll know.</text> 
 </string> 




<string id="arpr122_0"> 
 <text>Well, Barkeep. I think I did it. I talked to the leader of Duty.</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="arpr122_1"> 
 <text>Wait a minute. The guys from Radar brought in a stalker. I think he's, uh-- Not exactly sane. I think we could use some information about what he's learned about Radar and what's going on there. See if you can talk to him.</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="arpr122_2"> 
 <text>Radar? Good.</text> 
 </string> 




 <string id="aqiyorbar_0"> 
 <text>Your guest is in a bad way.</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="aqiyorbar_1"> 
 <text>Shit. So what's he saying anyway?</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="aqiyorbar_2"> 
 <text>I think the radiation's giving him brain damage. Do you at least have a first aid kit for him?</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="aqiyorbar_3"> 
 <text>Here you go. See if you can get him to talk.</text> 
 </string>
 <string id="aqiyorbar_4"> 
 <text>I will.</text> 
 </string>



	<string id="bar_ryaboy_job">
		<text>Meeting with Psycho</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_ryaboy_job_0">
		<text>Get information about Radar from the zombie.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_ryaboy_medik_job">
		<text>Get the first aid kit.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_ryaboy_medik_job_0">
		<text>Get the first aid kit from the Barkeep</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_ryaboy_medik_job_1">
		<text>Give the first aid kit to the zombie.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_ryaboy_lisiy_talk">
		<text>Talk to the stalker with the rifle</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_ryaboy_lisiy_talk_0">
		<text>Ask the stalker about the zombie</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_ryaboy_lisiy_talk_1">
		<text>Talk to the zombie.</text>
	</string>



 <string id="bopb_0"> 
 <text>Hey, Barkeep. Here, look.</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="bopb_1"> 
 <text>What are you doing? Hide it! You can't do this in front of everyone!</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="bopb_2"> 
 <text>Listen, there's someone here to see me.</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="bopb_3"> 
 <text>Let's go to my office and we'll talk.</text> 
 </string>
 <string id="bopb_4"> 
 <text>Alright.</text> 
 </string>




      <string id="qiyorbar_0"> 
 <text>Your man is dead.</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="qiyorbar_1"> 
 <text>Shit. Was there something else out there?</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="qiyorbar_2"> 
 <text>Several Freedom stalkers, also dead. There was a controller on the roof. He must have killed them, and I think he was following me.</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="qiyorbar_3"> 
 <text>Okay, well, then we'll just have to do this on our own. So the Freedom people gave us some information on the suspected location of the warehouse. It's right here in the bar. There's two places we need to check. We're moving right now.</text> 
 </string>
 <string id="qiyorbar_4"> 
 <text>Alright. [Cell phone rings]</text> 
 </string>




      <string id="iyorbar_0"> 
 <text>Hey. What'd you call me for?</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="iyorbar_1"> 
 <text>Stalker! Alive! I don't know how, but you did it. How are your brains still in place?</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="iyorbar_2"> 
 <text>As you can see, I'm alive.</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="iyorbar_3"> 
 <text>That's great! Let's get right down to business. Anyway, Duty has a piece of equipment that's of interest to another faction. It's rare, it's the only one in the Zone. MANPADS. Have you heard of such a toy? Anyway, Go to Rostok, there's a warehouse on top of a roof. You can get there by climbing a wooden ladder on the alley filled with chemical anomalies. Our man from Duty should meet you there. You meet him, we'll decide on the spot. It's simple. The reward will be more than worth it, believe me.</text> 
 </string>
 <string id="iyorbar_4"> 
 <text>You're not such an easy stalker, Witcher. Hmm. Alright, then.</text> 
 </string>






      <string id="vibebar_0"> 
 <text>Are you ready to move to the site?</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="vibebar_1"> 
 <text>Yeah, I notified the Barkeep that we're going to the site behind Rostok. He said it's kind of quiet out there by the site. Still, it's all set. I think we can handle it. We're gonna be on the highway, so bring some anti-rads. It's pretty smoky out there.</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="vibebar_2"> 
 <text>Alright, let's go.</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="vibebar_3"> 
 <text>Let's go.</text> 
 </string>

        <string id="olr_barman_bar_monsters_tree">
            <text>Destroy the bloodsucker camp</text>
        </string>
        <string id="text_olr_barman_bar_monsters_tree">
            <text>Hey, we got some bloodsuckers out behind the Rostok plant. I don't think they're coming in here with humans, but I don't know. You want to take a shot?</text>
        </string>
        <string id="desc_olr_barman_bar_monsters_tree">
            <text>Destroy the bloodsucker camp</text>
        </string>


        <string id="olr_barman_bar_monsters_tvo">
            <text>Destroy the dog pack</text>
        </string>
        <string id="text_olr_barman_bar_monsters_tvo">
            <text>Listen, there's a bunch of dogs in the parking lot. I don't think they come in here with people, but I don't know. You want to shoot it?</text>
        </string>
        <string id="desc_olr_barman_bar_monsters_tvo">
            <text>Destroy the dog pack</text>
        </string>


        <string id="olr_barman_bar_monsters_one">
            <text>Destroy the boar camp.</text>
        </string>
        <string id="text_olr_barman_bar_monsters_one">
            <text>Listen, we got a herd of boars up on the hill. They don't seem to come up here with people, but I don't know. You want to shoot them?</text>
        </string>
        <string id="desc_olr_barman_bar_monsters_one">
            <text>Destroy the boar camp</text>
        </string>



 <string id="vibbar_0"> 
 <text>Can you tell me where I can make some money around here?</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="vibbar_1"> 
 <text>Where? Well. that's a good question. Stalkers usually post jobs on the bulletin board out front. You can see the work there.</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="vibbar_2"> 
 <text>Okay, I'll see.</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="vibbar_3"> 
 <text>I think the science guys have a board, too. and I think Toad had one.</text> 
 </string>


        <string id="olr_find_art_drunk_gun">
            <text>Find an LR-300 for Duty Guy.</text>
        </string>
        <string id="text_olr_find_art_drunk_gun">
            <text>Hey, can you get me a barrel? Some NATO barrel, like an LR-300. We've got a shipment of underbarrels and sights in stock.</text>
        </string>
        <string id="desc_olr_find_art_drunk_gun">
            <text>Find an LR-300 for Dutyowitz.</text>
        </string>


        <string id="olr_find_art_osved_rour">
            <text>Find the artifact Disintegrator.</text>
        </string>
        <string id="text_olr_find_art_osved_rour">
            <text>There was an order from one of the scientific groups for an artifact Disintegrator. Its properties are strange, that's why the price is small at traders, but scientists are hunting for them. I pay well.</text>
        </string>
        <string id="desc_olr_find_art_osved_rour">
            <text>Find a Disintegrator artifact for the Snitch.</text>
        </string>


        <string id="olr_find_art_drunk_dvaa">
            <text>Find the artifact Mercury Ball.</text>
        </string>
        <string id="text_olr_find_art_drunk_dvaa">
            <text>I'm thinking of raiding the Garbage. It's not far. And as you probably know, there's a lot of phonies there, but not too much. I don't want to waste anti-radiation drugs on it, but an artifact against radiation is just fine! Bring me a mercury ball, for example. I won't hurt you!</text>
        </string>
        <string id="desc_olr_find_art_drunk_dvaa">
            <text>Find the Mercury Ball artifact for Dutyowitz.</text>
        </string>


        <string id="olr_find_art_drunk_ine">
            <text>Find the Mercury artifact</text>
        </string>
        <string id="text_olr_find_art_drunk_ine">
            <text>Recently I was sitting in the camp, on the Garbage, with our guys who came back from a raid. So one showed me an interesting thing, he said, on Radar found. It's called a Mercury artifact. They say it's common, but I've never seen it myself. Can you find it? I'll pay you well!</text>
        </string>
        <string id="desc_olr_find_art_drunk_ine">
            <text>Find the Mercury artifact for Dutyowitz.</text>
        </string>


        <string id="olr_petr_tree_vert">
            <text>Find a Colt 1911 pistol.</text>
        </string>
        <string id="text_olr_petr_tree_vert">
            <text>Listen, I got an order from one of our veterans for a Colt 1911 .45 caliber. Can you get it?</text>
        </string>
        <string id="desc_olr_petr_tree_vert">
            <text>Find a Colt 1911 for a Duty dealer.</text>
        </string>


        <string id="olr_petr_two_vert">
            <text>Find a Desert Eagle pistol.</text>
        </string>
        <string id="text_olr_petr_two_vert">
            <text>Listen, I got an order from one of our veterans for a Desert Eagle, the .45 caliber. Can you get it?</text>
        </string>
        <string id="desc_olr_petr_two_vert">
            <text>Find a Desert Eagle pistol for a Duty dealer.</text>
        </string>


        <string id="olr_petr_one_vert">
            <text>Find a USP pistol.</text>
        </string>
        <string id="text_olr_petr_one_vert">
            <text>Listen, I got an order from one of our veterans for a USP .45 caliber. Can you get it? Go for it, no offense!</text>
        </string>
        <string id="desc_olr_petr_one_vert">
            <text>Find a USP pistol for Duty's dealer.</text>
        </string>


        <string id="olr_kill_krovo_quest_vtor">
            <text>Kill the bloodsuckers</text>
        </string>
        <string id="text_olr_kill_krovo_quest_vtor">
            <text>In the Garbage, in the forest east of Duty's outpost, there are bloodsuckers. Apparently they are migrating from the Dark Valley. Destroy them!</text>
        </string>
        <string id="desc_olr_kill_krovo_quest_vtor">
            <text>Kill the bloodsuckers</text>
        </string>


        <string id="olr_tri_find_wpns">
            <text>Find the prototype AK-74.</text>
        </string>
        <string id="text_olr_tri_find_wpns">
            <text>Have you seen the military's strange assault rifles? They say they're prototypes of the new AK-74. It's pretty killer. I got an order for one of these guns. You can get one anywhere you want, but I know only the military has them. If you bring it, I'll give you a new AK-74, but it's serialized.</text>
        </string>
        <string id="desc_olr_tri_find_wpns">
            <text>Find a prototype AK-74 for the Snitch.</text>
        </string>


        <string id="olr_left_quest_dva">
            <text>Kill Digger.</text>
        </string>
        <string id="text_olr_left_quest_dva">
            <text>Listen, there's a man on Cordon. A group of them were coming from the Garbage, the group was killed by our men, and he was in charge. In general, I have information that somehow he is the only survivor and is now kind of hanging around the farm. We need to take him out. The sooner the better.</text>
        </string>
        <string id="desc_olr_left_quest_dva">
            <text>The snitch ordered Digger's murder.</text>
        </string>

        <string id="olr_quest_stor_osved">
            <text>To find the artifact Magnet.</text>
        </string>
        <string id="text_olr_quest_stor_osved">
            <text>Listen, a guy I know asked me to get him the Magnet artifact. Anyway, I need to find it.</text>
        </string>
        <string id="desc_olr_quest_stor_osved">
            <text>Find the artifact Magnet for the Snitch.</text>
        </string>




      <string id="arbar_0"> 
 <text>Tell me about yourself.</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="arbar_1"> 
 <text>What can I tell you about myself? I'm just a regular stalker, I go on raids. You see how lucky I was, man! Sometimes I help the Freedomers with supplies or provisions, stuff like that.</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="arbar_2"> 
 <text>Freedomers?</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="arbar_3"> 
 <text>Yeah, just some dudes, a Duty-type group. They've got a base in an abandoned town. They got snipers on the rooftops, holding down defenses. Especially after the zombies from Yantar come in. They're alright, to be honest.</text> 
 </string>

      <string id="iorbar_0"> 
 <text>Is that your buddy?</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="iorbar_1"> 
 <text>Yes... Oh, for fuck's sake! Looks like the raid's been postponed indefinitely. I think that bastard must have gotten out of Rostok! They've got a whole lair there, and no one's going in there, and they're already coming in here!</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="iorbar_2"> 
 <text>So what do you think we should do next?</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="iorbar_3"> 
 <text>I don't know, stalker. I'll see if I can find someone who's willing to go on a raid. Although, uh. I'll probably be here or in the bar. You know, why don't you go about your business, and then come see me sometime, see if there's anything for you.</text> 
 </string>
 <string id="iorbar_4"> 
 <text>Alright, I will.</text> 
 </string>

      <string id="serbar_0"> 
 <text>Hey, buddy! Haven't seen you around here before. You must be from the Garbage. Yeah, of course you're from the Garbage. What kind of question is that? You want to make some money?</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="serbar_1"> 
 <text>Money's always needed.</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="serbar_2"> 
 <text>Anyway, I'm going on a raid on Agroprom. Not alone, but with a partner. One of the rookies agreed. Just to carry my backpack for me and swing my bag, you know what I mean. So I sent him to that house over there to rest for the night. I just woke up and he didn't answer. That's weird. Let's go check it out. I don't know what's wrong. I'll give you some blood money, don't worry!</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="serbar_3"> 
 <text>Let's go check it out.</text> 
 </string>
 <string id="serbar_4"> 
 <text>I can't right now.</text> 
 </string>

      <string id="karbar_0"> 
 <text>Don't you get it? Get out of here, quick!</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="karbar_1"> 
 <text>Take it easy, what's going on here?</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="karbar_2"> 
 <text>Last warning to you, stalker.</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="karbar_3"> 
 <text>Fuck you.</text> 
 </string>



      <string id="narbar_0"> 
 <text>What do you want?</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="narbar_1"> 
 <text>Just passing by. Who's that stalker standing there? He looks like shit.</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="narbar_2"> 
 <text>Oh, they're rookies from the Garbage. They're new to the Zone, not used to the local liquor. But good for them for coming here.</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="narbar_3"> 
 <text>I see.</text> 
 </string>








 <!--Texts of dialogues with the Barkeep-->
	<string id="bar_about_killers_0">
	    <text>We need to talk.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_about_killers_1">
	    <text>What else you got?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_about_killers_2">
	    <text>I was attacked on my way out of a lab in Dark Valley by men in blue outfits. I know they're a clan of killers. What do you know about it?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_about_killers_3">
	    <text>Blue outfits, you say? Hmm. Looks like they placed a hit on you. I can't tell you who or why. I don't know. Maybe you had beef with someone.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_about_killers_4">
	    <text>Well, if I find out anything, I'll let you know.</text>
	</string>

    <string id="bar_before_repair_0">
	    <text>Hey, uh. can anyone help me out with some gear repairs around here?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_before_repair_1">
	    <text>You ask me. You do realize this zone didn't just start yesterday, right? It's a place like this, you know, not a resort. Weapons do not go here a lot, and therefore, as a rule, every first gun could be in the anomaly and in general not one dozen times broken. It's about physical fatigue of metal, you know?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_before_repair_2">
	    <text>Can you just tell me who's doing repairs?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_before_repair_3">
	    <text>There's a guy up here on the roof of this building. He's a jack of all trades. He's good with technology and science. Anyway, why don't you go see him and talk to him about it?</text>
	</string>

    <string id="bar_before_repair_4">
	    <text>Not bad, thanks.</text>
	</string>

 <string id="bar_about_inmormer_0">
    <text>Is it even realistic to order a normal barrel here?</text>
 </string>
 <string id="bar_about_inmormer_1">
    <text>Information, even that, costs money. Okay, I'll give you a hint... In general, you can, nerds from the science camp on Yantar periodically flies a chopper, you can negotiate about the gun will be.</text>
 </string>
 <string id="bar_about_inmormer_2">
    <text>How much do they charge? Do you know?</text>
 </string>
 <string id="bar_about_inmormer_3">
    <text>I'm sure it's not a lot. You won't be able to afford it. But if you scrape together the money, the gun will usually come new, and it won't jam every once in a while.</text>
 </string>
 <string id="bar_about_inmormer_4">
    <text>Thanks for the advice.</text>
 </string>



 <string id="reward_for_dyatel_off_0">
    <text>Well, the deed is done. The incinerator's off.</text>
 </string>
 <string id="reward_for_dyatel_off_1">
    <text>Alright, Messer. I can't believe the path to the center of the zone is now open. I can't believe it. It's kind of scary, you know, what's gonna happen to all of us. So what was it like out there? What did you see?</text>
 </string>
 <string id="reward_for_dyatel_off_2">
    <text>It's a long story. I'll tell it when I have time. You asked me to come over, didn't you?</text>
 </string>
 <string id="reward_for_dyatel_off_3">
    <text>Yes, I did. Our stalker collective got together and put together a reward for you for what you've done. Here you go. By the way, a guy came by here. asked me very nicely for you to meet him at the Cordon. I'll tell you right off the bat, he paid good money for me to give you this information. Why the hell go up there now when the north is open? He said to tell you he'll be in the village area.</text>
 </string>
 <string id="reward_for_dyatel_off_4">
    <text>Stalker? Hmm. Alright.</text>
 </string>


 <!--Texts of dialogues with the Informer-->
 <string id="questions_to_informer_0">
    <text>I'm interested in some information.</text>
 </string>
 <string id="questions_to_informer_1">
    <text>Ask away! I'll answer, but not for free, of course... One answer for 100 rubles.</text>
 </string>
 <string id="questions_to_informer_11">
    <text>Where is the Freedom base?</text>
 </string>
 <string id="questions_to_informer_12">
    <text>What is the radiation at Lake Yantar?</text>
 </string>
 <string id="questions_to_informer_13">
    <text>Who are the Sin Clan?</text>
 </string>
 <string id="questions_to_informer_14">
    <text>Where is the base of the Sin Clan?</text>
 </string>
 <string id="questions_to_informer_15">
    <text>Do you know where the Journalist was last seen?</text>
 </string>
 <string id="questions_to_informer_16">
    <text>I'd like to find some decent armor, what can you offer?</text>
 </string>
 <string id="questions_to_informer_17">
    <text>Who's Journalist?</text>
 </string>
 <string id="questions_to_informer_999">
    <text>Give me a hundred and you'll find out.</text>
 </string>
 <string id="questions_to_informer_9991">
    <text>Here you go.</text>
 </string>
 <string id="questions_to_informer_9992">
    <text>I'll come back later.</text>
 </string>
 <string id="questions_to_informer_11111">
    <text>Freedom Base is located in the Shining Path in the center of the settlement. You can access the Shining Path from Yantar or Silent Hills.</text>
 </string>
 <string id="questions_to_informer_12111">
    <text>It is a psi radiation generated by a facility in the central complex. It can only be turned off from the lab under the lake. Yantar's territory is very dangerous, one step away and you're brain-dead. You'll walk right away when you're called.</text>
 </string>
 <string id="questions_to_informer_13111">
    <text>Dark guys. No one knows where they're from, but it's believed they're people who were inside the perimeter during the second big bang. Very rarely make contact, otherwise just killed and fed to mutants.</text>
 </string>
 <string id="questions_to_informer_14111">
    <text>In the Silent Hills, a former army base.</text>
 </string>
 <string id="questions_to_informer_15111">
    <text>Last seen on the roof of a house near the Duty base.</text>
 </string>
 <string id="questions_to_informer_16111">
    <text>Look for it in the ruins of the Garbage, unless someone has already found it, hehehe... But I'm not getting my money back! I shared information with you in exchange for money, just like you wanted.</text>
 </string>
 <string id="questions_to_informer_17111">
    <text>An experienced research stalker. Came to the Zone to investigate an incident. A lot of people used to see him, but no one knows where he is now. Collaborated with a stalker called Gunslinger, or rather hired him to escort him.</text>
 </string>
 <!---->
 <!--Texts of dialogues with the Doctor-->
 <string id="doctor_help_actor_0">
    <text>I'm feeling a little sick. Can you fix me up?</text>
 </string>
 <string id="doctor_help_actor_1">
    <text>You give me food, I'll give you help!</text>
 </string>
 <string id="doctor_help_actor_11">
    <text>I've got bread, here.</text>
 </string>
 <string id="doctor_help_actor_12">
    <text>I can share some sausage.</text>
 </string>
 <string id="doctor_help_actor_13">
    <text>Here's canned food.</text>
 </string>
 <string id="doctor_help_actor_92">
    <text>I have nothing.</text>
 </string>
 <string id="doctor_help_actor_666">
    <text>Okay. Patch here. here, put some ointment on it. That's it. Alright.</text>
 </string>
 <string id="doctor_help_actor_667">
    <text>Okay, first time I'll just help you out. Okay. Patch here. here, here, here, here, here, here. That's it. Alright.</text>
 </string>
 <string id="about_doctor_0">
    <text>What do you do, Doctor?</text>
 </string>
 <string id="about_doctor_1">
    <text>I help anyone who needs help, if they deserve it.</text>
 </string>
 <string id="about_doctor_2">
    <text>You mean the patients in the next room are your patients?</text>
 </string>
 <string id="about_doctor_3">
    <text>For you stalkers, yes. Because you kill all living things, and each other. I suggest you think about killing a creature that doesn't want to hurt you.</text>
 </string>
 <string id="about_doctor_4">
    <text>I'll try.</text>
 </string>
 <string id="how_went_to_zone_0">
    <text>Why did you come to the Zone?</text>
 </string>
 <string id="how_went_to_zone_1">
    <text>I'm not here like the others. I'm here for knowledge, not money.</text>
 </string>
 <string id="how_went_to_zone_2">
    <text>Then what do you live on?</text>
 </string>
 <string id="how_went_to_zone_3">
    <text>In gratitude for my help, people provide me with what I need.</text>
 </string>
 <string id="how_went_to_zone_4">
    <text>I see.</text>
 </string>
 <string id="where_take_gift_0">
    <text>Why don't the mutants touch you?</text>
 </string>
 <string id="where_take_gift_1">
    <text>The Black Monolith can do more than that.</text>
 </string>
 <string id="where_take_gift_2">
    <text>The Black Monolith?!</text>
 </string>
 <string id="where_take_gift_3">
    <text>Yes. It does exist, but it doesn't grant wishes the way we'd like it to. I won't say anything more on the subject, but you'll find out for yourself in time.</text>
 </string>
 <string id="where_take_gift_4">
    <text>Perhaps.</text>
 </string>
 <!---->
 
 <!--OLR-->
 <string id="doll_0"> 
 <text>You wanted to see me?</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="doll_1"> 
 <text>Yes, I have a mission for you. I heard you killed that bloodsucker on Rostok. Good for you. Our guy reported you. I need you to bring me the diary from the factory. Actually, that was supposed to be the stalker you found in the catacomb, but as you know, he didn't make it.</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="doll_2"> 
 <text>Alright, then. I'm on my way.</text> 
 </string> 

 <string id="do_0"> 
 <text>Hello, stalker, are you new here?</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="do_1"> 
 <text>Yeah, I'm new here from Cordon.</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="do_2"> 
 <text>Look, I don't have time to talk right now. Come back later, or I'll call you myself.</text> 
 </string> 


 <string id="dokg_0"> 
 <text>Ahh... damn... bloodsucker... Help, stalker!</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="dokg_1"> 
 <text>Hold on.</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="dokg_2"> 
 <text>Shit! That hurts.</text> 
 </string> 

 <string id="serega_0"> 
 <text>Who are you?</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="serega_1"> 
 <text>What? Who the hell are you? Listen, I'm tired. I can't talk right now, I'm back from the raid. Come back later, we'll talk.</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="serega_2"> 
 <text>Alright. So be it.</text> 
 </string> 

 <string id="skay_0"> 
 <text>Hey, Messer. I'm a stalker with the Clear Sky group. There aren't that many of us, and we work with regular single stalkers. If you're interested in helping us, you can go to the central complex of the Agroprom Research Institute. Our group is there right now, they're probably looking for people like you.</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="skay_1"> 
 <text>Clear Sky? This is the first I've heard of your group. Well, if I get a chance, I'll meet your guys.</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="skay_2"> 
 <text>Thanks, Messer.</text> 
 </string> 



   <string id="g_bar_0">
     <text>Did you send me that text?</text>
  </string>
   <string id="g_bar_1">
     <text>Yeah. Actually, we usually just use guys like you right off the bat. Monsters love fresh stalker flesh. But I know you're here for a reason.</text>
  </string>
   <string id="g_bar_2">
     <text>I have a mission here.</text>
  </string>
   <string id="g_bar_3">
     <text>Hmm. What are you talking about?</text>
  </string>
   <string id="g_bar_4">
    <text>I'm looking for some documents. I got a tip that they're right here in this place.</text>
  </string>
   <string id="g_bar_5">
    <text>Yeah, we have them. I can give them to you, but not for nothing. You do a couple dirty deeds for me, you'll get your papers. There's some stalkers behind the base near the bar crossing. They're definitely sniffing around. We need to get close to them, overhear what they're saying, and then finish them off!</text>
  </string>
   <string id="g_bar_6">
    <text>Shit. Alright. I hope you keep your word.</text>
   </string>
  <string id="g_bar_7">
    <text>Go, stalker.</text>
  </string> 


   <string id="st_dialog_0">
     <text>Barkeep.</text>
  </string>
   <string id="st_dialog_1">
     <text>Poor bastard, but that's fate. He's not the first, he's not the last. So, how are you? You're alive, no brain damage? No, you have the same look in your eyes as when we first met.</text>
  </string>
   <string id="st_dialog_2">
     <text>I'm fine. The machine is shut down, there's no more psi radiation on the lake, the Phantasm seems to be gone too...</text>
  </string>
   <string id="st_dialog_3">
     <text>Good. So, judging from the documents you brought me from the lab under the Dark Valley, it's clear that the installation under Yantar and the Phantasm were generating a psi-field protecting another area. Another more powerful antenna, Woodpecker 1. which covers all the way north.</text>
  </string>
   <string id="st_dialog_4">
    <text>Go on.</text>
  </string>
   <string id="st_dialog_5">
    <text>There's an entrance to an underground complex in the Radar territory. It's most likely the control center for this Woodpecker. But it's not that simple. It's suicide to go to the radar alone, so, as you probably already know, Duty and I are going to organize a joint expedition, in which you'll play one of the central roles. Right now, we've got Duty scouts on a raid to find out what's going on. Besides, we need some time to properly equip the squad, because the raid is going to be very serious. That goes for you, too. So I suggest you start preparing for this sortie thoroughly, and then when everything is ready, I'll tell you what to do next. Yeah, there's a new group of scientists in the swamps, I hear they're bringing in weapons from the Big Land. I think it makes sense for you to pay them a visit.</text>
  </string>
   <string id="st_dialog_6">
    <text>Alright.</text>
   </string>
  <string id="st_dialog_7">
    <text>Alright. Come back in a day or so when everything's ready, but be prepared. This is going to be a very serious mission. I'll let you know via PDA. And yes, I advise you to go to the marshes. There's someone there who's interested in you.</text>
  </string>  


   <string id="doc_bar_0">
     <text>Hello, stalker.</text>
  </string>
   <string id="doc_bar_1">
     <text>Doctor. well... Perhaps you're familiar with the name Journalist?</text>
  </string>
   <string id="doc_bar_2">
     <text>Well, you see, I'll answer that question for you as well, but... a little later.</text>
  </string>
   <string id="doc_bar_3">
     <text>And you're probably familiar with the Great Kree, too?</text>
  </string>
   <string id="doc_bar_4">
    <text>... It seems you've visited Sin. How are the gray brothers doing?</text>
  </string>
   <string id="doc_bar_5">
    <text>Not so good...</text>
  </string>
   <string id="doc_bar_6">
    <text>They weren't doing too well before.</text>
   </string>
  <string id="doc_bar_7">
    <text>You don't regret putting me back together, out of pieces?</text>
  </string>  




   <string id="stader_barh_0">
     <text>That's an interesting security detail you got there.</text>
  </string>
   <string id="stader_barh_1">
     <text>They think, I don't know, that they've been assigned to me by the military... You're probably wondering why he's opening up. Uh, I don't read minds. Not really. Alright, files. Alright. Okay, it talks about some kind of psychotropic installations that are located in the zone in the north... Apparently, they're an obstacle. It also says that the scientist base on Yantar was supplying equipment for these antennas.</text>
  </string>
   <string id="stader_barh_2">
     <text>You know the legend of the Black Monolith?</text>
  </string>
   <string id="stader_barh_3">
     <text>Well, you could say I know almost nothing. I don't believe it.</text>
  </string>
   <string id="stader_barh_4">
    <text>No one needs you to believe. I don't. Almost. Then what do you need?</text>
  </string>
   <string id="stader_barh_5">
    <text>Well done, clever boy. I do need you.</text>
  </string>
   <string id="stader_barh_6">
    <text>I don't need you.</text>
  </string>
   <string id="stader_barh_7">
    <text>Don't be rude.</text>
  </string>
   <string id="stader_barh_8">
    <text>Alright. (chuckles) I'll consider myself a good listener... for now.</text>
  </string>
   <string id="stader_barh_9">
    <text>That's better. So, uh, about the Black Monolith. There are a number of once-secret laboratories in the Zone. When they were built and for what purpose, of course, no one is interested. Some of them, while they were functioning, were engaged in mutations, the soil was fertile. Once at the energy heart of the Zone, a nuclear power plant, there was an accident, an explosion of radioactive substances contaminated a fairly large area. A sarcophagus was erected, and the bulk of radioactive substances were buried under a multi-meter thick concrete. And within a radius of 30 kilometers around the territory became the Zone. But there were other laboratories on the territory of the Zone, which apparently appeared long before the catastrophe. Moreover, someone somewhere found separate documents that could suggest that the accident was the result of some mysterious experiments. Where and who saw such documents was not known. But the rumors were persistent. Rumors could not be gagged like poor Hoplite, rumors could not be taken out of circulation by a successful military operation or by groups like Duty, who carefully collected and destroyed paper information... Lately, it's been simply out of inertia. And one such rumor was the legend of the Black Monolith.
In one of the halls of the abandoned Sarcophagus, there was supposedly a device that fulfilled wishes. Materialized the most underlying desires. This tale even had an almost scientific basis. They say that an obscure device, originally associated with some esoteric-extrasensory things, under the influence of unknown processes occurring in the sarcophagus, acquired completely new properties associated with the transformation of time into space... or maybe vice versa.</text>
  </string>
   <string id="stader_barh_10">
    <text>The device itself may have existed and even functioned somehow, but what does it have to do with wishes? This is nonsense! What do you want me to do? You want me to go and make a wish for you?</text>
  </string>
   <string id="stader_barh_11">
    <text>I could play hide-and-seek with you, but I don't have a wish. I mean play hide-and-seek, and I have plenty of wishes for the monolith. What I've heard about you forces me to play with open cards. There are three devices on the path to the monolith, some kind of RDs. Stalkers say they make your brain boil.</text>
  </string>
   <string id="stader_barh_12">
    <text>You think my brain is more fireproof?</text>
  </string>
   <string id="stader_barh_13">
    <text>Don't be sarcastic. If it's true that you're thrice-born, then you've been on the other side of the barrier that the RDs form.</text>
  </string>
   <string id="stader_barh_14">
    <text>Even if I was there, I don't remember anything about it. But am I the only one who's been there? There's Gobber.</text>
  </string>
   <string id="stader_barh_15">
    <text>Maybe there were others. They say Gunslinger was there, but nobody's seen him for a long time.</text>
  </string>
   <string id="stader_barh_16">
    <text>Did you send him to the power plant?</text>
  </string>
   <string id="stader_barh_17">
    <text>I just told him how to try to do it.</text>
  </string>
   <string id="stader_barh_18">
    <text>How?</text>
  </string>
   <string id="stader_barh_19">
    <text>Well, I'd start by going to one of the scientists' camps. You know, at least in the lakes area. They're-- Hold on, I got a visitor. Shit, you better go. It's in your best interest not to meet this man. Keep in mind, there's a lot of psi activity at the lake. If you don't want your brains fried, stay away from the central complex. Oh, by the way, since you're going to Yantar. Here you go -- artifact crossbreeder. You can think of it as a reward for the lab documents. Just be warned, there are no recipes in the device's memory. You can ask the scientists if you're going there. The road to Yantar is right here on the bar grounds. It's a former freeway. As you leave the bar, go straight southwest on the road, that's how you'll get to the lake. Oh, wait. I need time to arrange a meeting between you and the Professor, and there's still a lot of psi activity on the lake. So go to Silent Hills and scout out the military base area there. I'm interested in what's going on there in general. After that, you can move on to Yantar. That's it, go.</text>
  </string>
 




   <string id="stader_bar_0">
     <text>Here are the documents Toad wanted to give to you.</text>
  </string>
   <string id="stader_bar_1">
     <text>So Messer himself. In the flesh. There's a rumor in the Zone that you, a stalker from the death truck, you've been nesting military nests... Well, here you are, right here. Well, this is the Stalker bar, so to speak, a staging area. Let's see what you brought back. Oh, not much. You're not gonna get a clear picture of what's going on here. You come back in a couple days, we'll figure out what we're gonna do. Have a drink at the bar with the guys, listen to some local stories. Toad asked me, after you give me the case, that you come see him, he's got some business for you.</text>
  </string>


   <string id="stader_bar_2">
     <text>Well, what about the paperwork?</text>
  </string>
   <string id="stader_bar_3">
     <text>What are you talking about? Ah... yeah, I got a result. So, uh. Some calculations, maps, installations. It says there's some kind of lab underneath the Dark Valley. There's some kind of research going on there. Listen to me. I think we need to find this place, and we need to find more documents. What you've got isn't enough. About the valley itself, it's not an easy place to find, there's something there that drives people crazy... like psi noise, you don't know where it comes from, but the fact is, regular stalkers don't usually come back from there. Or they do, but they come back as vegetables with their eyes closed. This psi noise can of course be bypassed by using a psi stabilizer. Almost all military personnel in the zone use them, they have them built into their defenses. I had a few of them, but I sold them. The scientists from the lake have them, but now it seems that all the passageways to them are blocked by the same radiation. Uh, talk to the snitch here, I think he might have one for sure.</text>
  </string>
   <string id="stader_bar_4">
    <text>Okay, so you're suggesting we go down to the lab?</text>
  </string>
   <string id="stader_bar_5">
    <text>What do you think? Yeah, there's no other option. The paperwork explicitly lists a lab under Dark Valley. If you don't have the stomach for it, I'll find someone else.</text>
  </string>
   <string id="stader_bar_6">
    <text>I'm going there.</text>
   </string>
  <string id="stader_bar_7">
    <text>Hmm. Yeah, Messer, that valley's a hell of a place. Stalkers don't go there much. You might want to stock up on some ammo from me, daredevil. I don't know what's waiting for you out there. The way to the Valley is on the east side of the Garbage. There are two paths to it. Well. take care. Oh, by the way. There's a group of Vets gathered around the yard on the left, see if they have anything for you.</text>
  </string>  









 <string id="sokolov_kvest_dialog_0"> 
 <text>Is there a special job for me? I heard about the bloodsuckers around here.</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="sokolov_kvest_dialog_1"> 
 <text>You heard right. Yeah, there's a job for you. But I doubt a man like you could handle it. You've been to Rostok before, haven't you? It may look like a quiet place, but it's not. Before the explosion, that factory was a special place because of what was produced there. And I'll tell you this, there's also rooms underneath the factory... That's where it's rumored to be the lair of a bloodsucker, an unusual one. Few people have seen such a thing, and those who have seen it may be lying. He's very different from the others in his bloodthirstiness. There was a bloodsucker researcher in the bar who was writing his dissertation on bloodsucker behavior. disappeared when I went to see him. He even dragged stalkers from the bar to his lair at night. And you, stalker, you're not exactly ordinary. I think you two deserve each other. What do you say. you think you can take the bastard down?</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="sokolov_kvest_dialog_2"> 
 <text>I'll do it.</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="sokolov_kvest_dialog_3"> 
 <text>Another time.</text> 
 </string> 

 <string id="sokolov_kvest_dialog_completed_0"> 
 <text>The bloodsucker's dead.</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="sokolov_kvest_dialog_completed_1"> 
 <text>Messer, goddamn it, you're alive. I can't believe you killed that bastard. Yes... I got something for you. You know where the Duty Force has set up shop?      Right across from their base, there's this place. The stalker who kept it disappeared a long time ago, I haven't seen him in over a year... Here's the key, you can settle in there. I haven't been there myself since the owner disappeared, and I don't need it, but you've done a great job. Oh, yeah, I almost forgot to tell you. Duty's leader asked to see you.</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="sokolov_kvest_dialog_completed_2"> 
 <text>The house? Interesting. OK, thanks.</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="text_gavrilenko_kvest"> 
 <text>You need to find and kill a bloodsucker at the Rostok factory.</text>  
 </string>



 <string id="barman_spam_dom">
 <text>Barkeep: How's the shack? You're not afraid of ghosts? I'm just kidding. I forgot to tell you, there's a safe in the house. It's good for storing stuff, so you can use it. And check the nightstands, see what you can find. Yeah, I think there was a generator on the roof. If you need light in the house, you can figure out how to run it, I guess.</text>  
 </string>


       <string id="rat_story_info_0">
		<text>Listen, I'm looking for someone. Gunslinger. You know that name?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="rat_story_info_1">
		<text>Gunslinger. Yeah, I've heard of him. Saw him on Agroprom with a group. He's missing. Rumor has it he's somewhere around the power plant. Others say it's in the area behind the power plant. I don't know, man, this Gunslinger thing's a mess.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="rat_story_info_100">
		<text>Thank you.</text>
	</string>	

        <string id="ros_sos">
		<text>Mayday! Somebody help! Hurry up!</text>
	</string>

        <string id="ros_sos2">
		<text>Hurry up! I'm under the compound!</text>
	</string>

        <string id="mg_leader_hello">
		<text>This is Freedom Leader. Talk to the merchant on the third floor, there's a job for you. We can talk later.</text>
	</string>


        <string id="escape_trader_oops_0">
		<text>Hey, who are you?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="escape_trader_oops_1">
		<text>Who are you? I don't really care. We're a small group of like-minded people. Kind of like a clan. We go out on raids for each other's mutual benefit. And this is our base.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="escape_trader_oops_2">
		<text>Right. So, what are the missions, mostly?</text>
	</string>

	<string id="escape_trader_oops_3">
		<text>Artifacts! You can't get anywhere here without them. And documents. You see, there are so many different laboratories in the Zone, so there are a lot of documents in them. There's a demand, and a very good one, I'll tell you.</text>
        </string>

        <string id="escape_trader_oops_4">
		<text>I see. Bye.</text>
	</string>


        <string id="escape_trader_job_0">
		<text>You got a job?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="escape_trader_job_1">
		<text>I got it. I need to bring in a TOZ-34.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="escape_trader_job_2">
		<text>Alright. Where do you think I can find it?</text>
	</string>

	<string id="escape_trader_job_3">
		<text>Across the street.</text>
        </string>

        <string id="escape_trader_job_4">
		<text>You got a deal.</text>
	</string>



    <string id="bar_arena_manager_game_202">
        <text>Yeah. Oh, you! Hey, you wouldn't happen to have any extra hot cotton candy lying around, would you? I promised a local scientist I'd get some. I'm on a deadline and I can't leave my post. Can you help me out? Here's the artifact info. I'll give you a nice gun when I pay them back.</text>
    </string>


    
	<string id="bar_bar_barmen_start_15131">
		<text>I need a first aid kit for a zombie.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_barmen_start_151311">
		<text>Here, I got one.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_barmen_start_1513111">
		<text>Oh, great.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_barmen_start_161">
		<text>What do you want?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_barmen_start_1721">
		<text>Hold on, hold on. Let's go to the room, there's too many people in here...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_barmen_start_17211">
		<text>Alright, let's go.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_barmen_start_171211111">
		<text>Alright, let's go.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_barmen_start_181">
		<text>What do you want?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_barmen_start_3">
		<text>What do you want?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_barmen_start_2012">
		<text>No, I'm not interested right now.</text>
	</string>
    <string id="bar_bar_barmen_jobs_room_0">
        <text>What's the job?</text>
    </string>
	<string id="bar_bar_barmen_talk_info_0">
		<text>I'd like to know something.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_barmen_talk_info_1">
		<text>What are you interested in?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_barmen_talk_info_10">
		<text>Uh, thank you.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_barmen_talk_info_3">
		<text>What do you know about Gunslinger?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_barmen_talk_info_31">
		<text>As far as I know, experienced stalker, leader of one of the groups. Worked the northern exits of the Zone. Not many people have seen him around here, but rumor has it that he and his group went to the very center of the Zone.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_barmen_talk_info_4">
		<text>What is this place?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_barmen_talk_info_41">
		<text>It's a former labor camp. It used to be home to workers who operated some kind of facility on the lake that's rumored to still be in operation.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_barmen_talk_info_5">
        <text>What do you know about the Doctor?</text>
    </string>
	<string id="bar_bar_barmen_talk_info_51">
		<text>An old stalker who's retired. Lives in the swamps, but nobody knows how to get there. He was once associated with Gunslinger's group.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_barmen_talk_info_6">
		<text>What do you know about a stalker named Journalist?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_barmen_talk_info_61">
		<text>There was a guy like that. But I haven't seen him in the bar in a while. A month for sure. He was interested in some documents. That's all I know.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_barmen_talk_info_7">
		<text>Tell me about the mobile science labs.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_barmen_talk_info_71">
		<text>As you may have heard, several government scientific organizations are studying the manifestations of our Zone. Rumor has it they're the ones who brought it to life with their experiments. Gunslinger and his group tried to find out if this is true, but as a result, Gunslinger's entire group was destroyed and he himself disappeared somewhere. The truth is unknown to me, only speculation. Scientific organizations leave in the Zone mobile scientific laboratories, metal bunkers isolated from the outside environment, inside everything that is necessary for life and study of the Zone. We're in contact with one such lab on Yantar. The scientists are good guys, they reveal us a lot of interesting information, and we also help them when we can... Heh-heh. Mutually beneficial barter, you know.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_barmen_talk_info_8">
		<text>What is a Wish Granter?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_barmen_talk_info_81">
		<text>Ooh! That's a very interesting question, and I wish I had the right answer. I can only tell you the legend of the Wish Granter, but how much of it is true is up to you. Will you listen to it?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_barmen_talk_info_811">
		<text>Yes, it's very interesting.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_barmen_talk_info_8111">
		<text>It's the legend of the Monolith, quite possibly the cause of the Zone. In 2006, the Zone exploded, the population around it was evacuated and the Zone was cordoned off by the army. No one knew what was going on, there was panic, the Zone was growing, field labs were powerless. A lot of people died inside. Everyone is afraid of radiation, which can cover half of Europe. A few years go by, the first desperate guys like you show up. They called themselves stalkers. They penetrated through army cordons, believing that there was something in the Zone, something that would bring them riches. Slowly, they started bringing in strange things, artifacts, which were instantly chased. Scientists were going crazy, hysterical. They used to pay a lot of money for one of these specimens! Not like this.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_barmen_talk_info_81111">
		<text>Go on.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_barmen_talk_info_811111">
		<text>So, the first stories and legends about what is inside the Zone, near the half-destroyed nuclear power plant appeared. Then one of the veterans retold a story heard from one of the local stalkers - old-timers, about the Monolith, supposedly fulfilling wishes. What hysteria began here, stalkers gathered in groups and rushed to the center of the Zone, everyone wanted something from the Monolith. There were grim details about the first stalker who got to the Monolith...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_barmen_talk_info_8111111">
		<text>Then... What happened next?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_barmen_talk_info_81111111">
		<text>When the Zone first appeared, many people were under its hood, cut off from the outside world. Most of them died immediately, but there were rare lucky ones who not only survived, but also tried to do something about it. One of the survivors was near the power plant, inside he saw a strange glow, he had no choice, the way back was cut off, and he got closer. He saw a picture of the Sarcophagus roof pierced through, with a glow coming out from underneath. He climbed up the wall and the inner view was revealed to him, a huge black shard of geometric shape rested amongst a pile of metal debris and charred concrete pancakes. This was the Monolith! Stalker finally awoke from his strange obsession and realized that he had literally climbed into the terribly phoned Sarcophagus. He was struck with a wild fear, through which the monotonous call of the Monolith pierced. The Monolith was calling him, and the stalker's hair stood on end, his head exploding with strange incredible pictures of the Monolith...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_barmen_talk_info_811111111">
		<text>Wow...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_barmen_talk_info_811111112">
		<text>I don't know what's true or false in that story. The point is that he made a wish and it came true, and the Zone increased dramatically by five kilometers. It seems that for every wish granted, the Zone eats our Earth. But that doesn't stop brave guys like you. They keep on rushing in, carrying in their hearts their innermost desires...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_barmen_talk_info_812">
		<text>I'm more interested in other information right now.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_barmen_talk_info_8121">
		<text>Well, suit yourself. What exactly are you interested in?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_osvedomitel_trade_info_0">
		<text>I want to buy information.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_osvedomitel_trade_info_21">
		<text>Right now, I'm willing to sell information on the location where Gunslinger is rumored to have set up one of his hideouts. For the completely symbolic price of 400 rubles.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_osvedomitel_trade_info_211">
		<text>Alright, I'll buy it. Here's 400.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_osvedomitel_trade_info_2111">
		<text>It's rumored to be at the Agroprom Research Institute, somewhere near one of the complexes. I have no idea what might be in there, but it could be something important.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_osvedomitel_trade_info_212">
		<text>No, I changed my mind.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_osvedomitel_trade_info_2121">
		<text>It's up to you. When you make up your mind, come by. I'm always at the bar.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_osvedomitel_trade_info_31">
		<text>At the moment I'm ready to sell information about the group that reached the center of the Zone. For the completely symbolic price of 200 rubles.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_osvedomitel_trade_info_311">
		<text>Okay, I'll buy it. Here's 200.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_osvedomitel_trade_info_3111">
		<text>A group of unknowns, led by Gunslinger went to the center of the Zone. What they discovered next is unknown. All we know is that Gunslinger is missing. The last known information is that the Journalist most likely knows what happened to the group. Besides, I heard there was another group... In fact, a year ago, two veteran stalkers accidentally discovered some documents. They contained data that explained what was behind the Chernobyl NPP... They went there and got lost. The leader of the Freedom group received messages from them for a while, but soon the signal was cut off.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_osvedomitel_trade_info_312">
		<text>No, I've changed my mind.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_osvedomitel_trade_info_3121">
		<text>It's up to you. When you make up your mind, come back. I'm always at the bar.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_osvedomitel_trade_info_41">
		<text>At this moment, I'm willing to sell information about the mystery of Lake Yantar. For the absolutely symbolic price of 350 rubles.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_osvedomitel_trade_info_411">
		<text>Alright, I'll buy it. Here's 350.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_osvedomitel_trade_info_4111">
		<text>The mystery of Yantar is similar to the mystery of the installation that is on the radar and does not let you go north. Their effects are similar in many ways. Unknown radiation zombifies all who fall under its influence. As a result, zombified stalkers move around the center of a certain emitter, attacking anyone who is not irradiated. There are reports that the lower levels of the Dark Lab contain the clue to Yantar. Here are the coordinates of the emitters on Lake Yantar and the installation on Radar. In addition, I'll give you the coordinates of the Dark Lab. In addition, when the blowout begins, the radiation of the installation begins to work in high mode... I suggest you seek shelter immediately. You could go crazy. Oh, and, uh, one last thing. Part of the Monolith group was zombified while exploring the lake. They disappeared somewhere in the central complex. So be doubly careful out there.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_osvedomitel_trade_info_412">
		<text>No, I've changed my mind.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_osvedomitel_trade_info_4121">
		<text>It's up to you. When you make up your mind, come by. I'm always at the bar.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_osvedomitel_trade_info_999">
		<text>There's no new information at the moment.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_osvedomitel_trade_info_outfit_0">
		<text>I'd like to buy the information on the stash of the suit.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_osvedomitel_trade_info_outfit_1">
		<text>I'm willing to sell it to you for the completely symbolic price of 2,000 rubles.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_osvedomitel_trade_info_outfit_11">
		<text>Alright, I'll buy it. Here's the money.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_osvedomitel_trade_info_outfit_111">
		<text>The stash with the suit is located on the Garbage in a small forest, where there are packs of wild dogs. The coordinates of the forest are attached.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="bar_bar_osvedomitel_trade_bio_1521">
		<text>Barkeep? Ah. Yeah, actually. What do you want to buy? I'll tell you right off the bat, I don't sell full cans, only empty ones. You'll have to make your own if you want it. How do you ask? You get close to the anomaly and you fill it, no magic. The thing is useful very useful... against swarms of mutants, especially. 250 rubles a can.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="bar_bar_osvedomitel_trade_bio_177">
		<text>It's possible that's what it is. Anyway, talk to the professor at Lake Yantar. I think he'll be able to bring you up to speed. Now go.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="bar_bar_osvedomitel_trade_bio_1771">
		<text>Wait a second. The scientists didn't say anything about this device being mutant-proof.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="bar_bar_osvedomitel_trade_bio_178">
		<text>Good call, Messer. However, in order to join our clan, you must be baptized in combat. Now that the road to the swamps is clear, we have an opportunity to destroy one of the rarest and most dangerous creatures in the world. Scientists call it the Phantasm, and it lives in the swamp. All we know is that it uses telekinesis. Since you have the brainwave emulator the scientists developed for you, theoretically, it shouldn't be much of a threat to you. </text>
	</string>

	<string id="bar_bar_osvedomitel_trade_bio_1781">
		<text>I think I'll agree to join you.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="bar_bar_osvedomitel_trade_bio_179">
		<text>That's right. You see, with our powers, together, we can really find him. And then everyone gets what they want.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="bar_bar_osvedomitel_trade_bio_1791">
		<text>So you're suggesting I join you?</text>
	</string>

	<string id="bar_bar_osvedomitel_trade_bio_180">
		<text>I mean, we don't have enough people like you, you know? I know you got your own agenda, you're looking for someone like Gunslinger. I'll tell you what, we're looking for him too, and we have been for a while. The information Gunslinger has is more important than his life. It could save the lives of thousands of people. According to our intel, Gunslinger's been zombified and is near a PSI antenna on Radar. </text>
	</string>

	<string id="bar_bar_osvedomitel_trade_bio_1801">
		<text>There's a room upstairs in the store building where they keep stuff now. You can leave it there, but you'll be charged a hundred for access to the vault. Yeah, it might be a little pricey, but it'll keep your stuff safe and sound. What do you say?</text>
	</string>

	<string id="bar_bar_osvedomitel_trade_killer_doc_12">
		<text>No, I changed my mind.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_visitors_1_start_71">
		<text>What do you want? Can't you see I'm trying to relax?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_visitors_1_start_711">
		<text>What's new?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_visitors_1_start_7111">
		<text>I heard Gunslinger's back. Along with everything he needs to break through to the Executor. Only he's hiding because a lot of people are after him. Some overtly, some covertly. Even Duty and Freedom are rumored to be on the hunt. each with their own agenda.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_visitors_1_start_71111">
		<text>Looks like Gunslinger's not hiding for nothing!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_visitors_10_start_71">
		<text>What do you want?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_visitors_10_start_711">
		<text>Can you tell me something interesting?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_visitors_10_start_7111">
		<text>Interesting? Well, listen. Up north, not far from the Brain Scorcher, in an old military base, there's a group called Freedom. It's in zombie town. Freedom fighters, for fuck's sake! Fucking guerrillas! All they do is shoot up army units. I can only give you one piece of advice, never get involved with them, they only take the totally fucked up. Unless there's a bounty on your head, they won't take you... Ha-ha-ha-ha. Can you imagine that?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_visitors_10_start_71111">
		<text>Thanks for the advice.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_visitors_12_start_71">
		<text>What do you want?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_visitors_12_start_711">
		<text>You're new here? Haven't seen you before.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_visitors_12_start_7111">
		<text>Yeah, there was a group. They were legendary throughout the Zone. Good and bad things were said about them, but few people knew the truth. And the truth is that they wanted to cope with the Zone, they wanted to dig out the reasons for its appearance. Military stalkers were hunting them, but they didn't know where to look. Government organizations knew something that ordinary stalkers shouldn't know. At one point they found some very important information and part of the group, along with Gunslinger, rushed to the center of the Zone. Half of the group died on the way, but they made it. Nobody knows what happened to them afterwards. They seem to have vanished. Meanwhile, the rest of the group was captured and slaughtered. and nobody survived. That's the story.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_visitors_12_start_71111">
		<text>Apparently, someone's very interested in keeping the Zone unrecognized.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_visitors_13_start_71">
		<text>What do you want?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_visitors_13_start_711">
		<text>Been here recently?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_visitors_13_start_7111">
		<text>The Kill Team is kind of like Freedom, only worse. Freedom at least has an idea, but these jackals are willing to do anything as long as you pay them. Shoot them all and be done with it, before they bring something dangerous from the Zone to the civilized world. They're in the Dark Valley.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_visitors_13_start_71111">
		<text>Looks like we need to be careful.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_visitors_14_start_71">
		<text>What do you want?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_visitors_14_start_711">
		<text>Seen you before?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_visitors_14_start_7111">
		<text>Probably not. Why don't you get the hell away from me? I heard about you, how they found you at the cordon. I'm not talking to you.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_visitors_14_start_81">
		<text>What do you want?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_visitors_14_start_82">
		<text>Are you the one who was on Radar? I need to talk to you.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_visitors_14_start_83">
		<text>So what's it to me?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_visitors_14_start_84">
		<text>One of your group got pulled off Radar, and the other one died. Does that mean anything to you?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_visitors_14_start_85">
		<text>Shit. Shit!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_visitors_14_start_86">
		<text>He's in very bad shape, he's not thinking straight. Can't you try to get him to talk? We need to find out anything about the rig that's in there.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_visitors_14_start_87">
		<text>No, no, no! I'm the one who got him killed, and I'm the one who got him. I betrayed them at the worst possible moment and ran away. I can't look him in the eye now.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_visitors_14_start_88">
		<text>Tell me more about what happened.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_visitors_14_start_89">
		<text>We've been preparing to break through to the North for a long time. The only thing we were missing was the time period where the radiation cooled down, and the guy in the room got that information. From whom, I have absolutely no idea. We got halfway down the radar when the rig suddenly kicked on. One of them blew a roof off, lost consciousness and fell down the slope. I panicked, decided to drop everything and head back. Toth insisted on pulling the guy out, but it would have been pure suicide to go down and drag him all the way back up. I agreed, and he started down the slope just as another burst of radiation hit us. I came to my senses near the military base, until then I thought they were dead! But it looks like he pulled him out at the cost of his life.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_visitors_14_start_90">
		<text>...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_visitors_14_start_91">
		<text>I'm sorry, brother. I don't want to talk anymore, I'd rather have another drink.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_visitors_2_start_71">
		<text>What do you want?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_visitors_2_start_711">
		<text>What's new?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_visitors_2_start_7111">
		<text>He was a hunchbacked guy with a lisp. He wasn't himself, talking to himself and animals... Other than that, he seemed okay. He disappeared downtown with Gunslinger, even though they say Gunslinger's back.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_visitors_2_start_71111">
		<text>I wonder where he is now.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_visitors_3_start_71">
		<text>What do you want?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_visitors_3_start_711">
		<text>What you got to tell me?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_visitors_3_start_7111">
		<text>The Monolith believers are nuts, they scream about it, but no one knows what's at the center of the Zone. An invisible crystal that fell from the sky. Ha, ha. I think it blew up one of the secret labs. Somebody even said they used to work there. But, of course, you can't bomb the Zone, not only will the radiation spread all over the world, but the reaction of the Zone could blow up half of Europe.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_visitors_3_start_71111">
		<text>Thanks for the information.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_visitors_4_start_71">
		<text>What do you want?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_visitors_4_start_711">
		<text>What do you hear?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_visitors_4_start_7111">
		<text>If you go around Lake Yantar, you'll find a scientific camp, they're studying something there... The helicopter brought them in, it's also a regular supply, so they're well entrenched there. You can talk to them, they buy artifacts, they might even ask you to do something.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_visitors_4_start_71111">
		<text>Thanks for the information.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_visitors_5_start_71">
		<text>What do you want?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_visitors_5_start_711">
		<text>What do you hear?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_visitors_5_start_7111">
		<text>I heard that the Silent Hills area is or was under partial psi radiation... Rumor has it that someone or something shut down the passage to the north on purpose, so the smart ones wouldn't steal anything from there... Although, a freedom peddler in Shining Path once told me that they have swamps up there..., so... he's probably lying. So there's a creature living there. and it's living in the swamp, and it's already dragged a few of them down to the bottom. That's the news.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_visitors_5_start_71111">
		<text>Interesting.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_visitors_6_start_71">
		<text>What do you want?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_visitors_6_start_711">
		<text>What do you hear?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_visitors_6_start_7111">
		<text>Every now and then, missing stalkers come back. It's a terrible sight, mooing and reaching for missing weapons. Once one of them dragged himself to Duty's outpost, a lot of people gathered to watch. I think they even recognized him. Scary, eyes red, all in bruises, can't say anything, only mooing and walking in circles. Duty took him in, but he died a couple of days later. Something is happening in the Zone with people. What is it?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_visitors_6_start_71111">
		<text>I wish I knew.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_visitors_7_start_71">
		<text>What do you want?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_visitors_7_start_711">
		<text>What do you hear?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_visitors_7_start_7111">
		<text>Zombies are wandering in circles around Lake Yantar, if they see you, they'll start hunting you too! You have to get off your feet, because a lot of them, former stalkers, died on this lake! And now there's nothing but idle ones wandering around.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_visitors_7_start_71111">
		<text>Yeah, I wouldn't want to join their ranks.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_visitors_8_start_71">
		<text>What do you want?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_visitors_8_start_711">
		<text>What do you hear?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_visitors_8_start_7111">
		<text>Merchants say there's a Klondike of artifacts in the center of the Zone. Whoever gets in there is gonna be rich beyond belief. I have a different opinion about it, and it's understandable for traders to think about their profit, but there are some rumors. There's something better than a scattering of artifacts, something that doesn't belong to our world, something alien or from some other dimension. It's called a Wish Granter. I even heard a legend about a stalker who got to it. Only, they say the Zone grows after every wish fulfilled, and those who got there don't seem to wish for the Zone to disappear. Apparently, when you get to the executor already do not care about others, only their own skin cares!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_visitors_8_start_71111">
		<text>It's sad.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_visitors_9_start_71">
		<text>What do you want?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_visitors_9_start_711">
		<text>What do you hear?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_visitors_9_start_7111">
		<text>Those who believe in the Monolith are nuts. They shout about it, but no one knows what's at the center of the Zone. An invisible crystal that fell from the sky. Ha ha. I think it blew up one of the secret labs. Somebody even said they used to work there. But, of course, you can't bomb the Zone, not only will the radiation spread all over the world, but the Zone's reaction could blow up half of Europe... Lately they've gone completely crazy... I heard they're killing ordinary stalkers for nothing. How about that? They're out of their minds, those fanatics.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_visitors_9_start_71111">
		<text>I think it's worth looking into.</text>
	</string>
	


    <string id="bar_dolg_base_guard_acces_121">
        <text>Alright, alright. You guys did good to get out. I'll talk to the group leader about what happened out there. And I'll have to talk to the general about how the Slugs got into the plant. Here, relax for now. We'll figure out what to do about it later.</text>
    </string>

	<string id="kill_barter_govno1">
        <text>Hey, do you have any more vodka? I'm having a hard time here. At least it makes me feel less crazy. Listen, you're traveling around the zone, you'll need ammo. Come by the base tonight when I'm on shift. Bring some bubbles. I'll arrange a little barter for you, okay? Just between you and me, cause we don't really encourage that.</text>
    </string>

	<string id="kill_barter_govno2">
        <text>Okay, alright. Here's what I can offer you right now: 9x18 pistol ammo a pack for a bottle, 9x19 ammo two bottles for a pack. Shotgun ammo - a pack for two bottles. Kalash ammunition - two bottles per pack. Gasoline canisters - three vials per canister. I can't tell you which ammo is armor-piercing or regular - it's a matter of luck. What are you gonna get?</text>
    </string>

	<string id="bar_dolg_base_guard_rules_0">
		<text>The Barkeep told me your bosses had some assignment for me.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_base_guard_rules_1">
		<text>Yeah, he told us about you. But before we let you in, I need to familiarize you with our rules. Now, listen, our rules are simple. First rule, no shooting on our property. For two offenses, our patrol will fire on you. Even if you make a run for it, you won't be on our property again, the guards will take care of you. If you behave calmly, you won't have any problems!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_base_guard_rules_2">
		<text>I see. Is that all?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_base_guard_rules_3">
		<text>Yes, that's enough. You can go now.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_base_guard_rules_4">
		<text>Okay. Is that all?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_base_guard_rules_5">
		<text>Yes, that's enough. If you ever want to try and join the Duty Group, you're welcome to join. We need good fighters. But I must warn you, before you're accepted, you'll have to do some dangerous tasks. We don't want any weaklings, so everyone will be tested.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_base_guard_start_11">
		<text>Stop! No one goes into Duty's base! Strangers have no business there!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_base_guard_start_21">
		<text>What are you standing there for? Hurry up and go through!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_base_guard_start_31">
		<text>Come on, brother. And remember, Duty's mission is purification!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_guard_bunker_start_11">
		<text>Halt! You're in Duty's territory. You shoot here if you want to live... if you disobey, you'll get a bullet.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_guard_bunker_start_111">
		<text>Why don't you let me into the bunker?</text>
	</string>

	<string id="bar_dolg_guard_bunker_start_1111">
		<text>What do you want? Come on in.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="bar_dolg_guard_bunker_start_21">
		<text>What are you standing there for? Hurry up and get in!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_guard_bunker_start_31">
		<text>Come on in, brother. And remember, Duty's mission is to purify!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_ivancov_start_11">
		<text>What do you want?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_ivancov_start_21">
		<text>Yes, sir.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_ivancov_start_31">
		<text>Hello, Brother.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_leader_prisyaga_0">
		<text>I'm ready to take the oath!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_leader_prisyaga_1">
		<text>Well done! Then repeat after me: I, swear to defend the aims and ideals of Duty.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_leader_prisyaga_2">
		<text>I swear to defend the aims and ideals of Duty!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_leader_prisyaga_3">
		<text>To preserve the Earth from the dangers of the Zone. To pursue and destroy any manifestation of the Zone both within and beyond its borders!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_leader_prisyaga_4">
		<text>Protect the Earth from the dangers of the Zone. Pursue and destroy any manifestations of the Zone both within and beyond its borders!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_leader_prisyaga_5">
		<text>To fight against any dissent in the person of both individual stalkers and groups!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_leader_prisyaga_6">
		<text>To fight any dissent in the person of both individual stalkers and factions!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_leader_prisyaga_7">
		<text>And give your life in the name of justice and order on Earth!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_leader_prisyaga_8">
		<text>And to give their lives in the name of justice and order on Earth!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_leader_prisyaga_9">
		<text>Congratulations! You are now a full member of the Duty faction.</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="bar_dolg_leader_start_11">
		<text>Go ahead.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_leader_start_21">
		<text>What brings you to me, brother?</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="bar_dolg_leader_deadcity_map_12111">
		<text>Well, if you find it, come back!</text>
	</string>

	<string id="blastyouass">
		<text>What? The one in the bar, you said? I thought he's not himself lately, and he's drunk all the time. No, we're not going to put up with this. He'll get what's coming to him. Good for you for telling me. Later, if this information checks out, you can expect a reward from the merchant.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="bar_dolg_leader_deadcity_map_21">
		<text>Duty story.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_newbie_start_11">
		<text>Hello, stalker. Join Duty, we need good fighters. I just joined up myself. Look at the nice uniform they gave me!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_newbie_start_21">
		<text>Hi. It's good to have you with us. Duty's gonna need good fighters soon.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_novice_start_2">
		<text>Hello, brother stalker.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_novice_start_3">
		<text>Tell me about Duty.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_novice_start_31">
		<text>We've been here since the beginning. The group was founded by survivors of one of the special forces sent to the Zone to deal with the cause of its emergence. We got into some serious trouble. After half the squad was killed in horrible circumstances, the survivors swore that they would not leave until they dealt with what happened in the Zone. Until they'd dealt with it!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_novice_start_4">
		<text>Tell me about Freedom.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_novice_start_41">
		<text>They're scumbags who don't realize the Zone is a pestilence on the Earth. They want to spread it around the world, a piece of it in every home. And they'll do anything to get it. I can't wait to get rid of them!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_novice_start_5">
		<text>You want to deal with the Zone?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_novice_start_51">
		<text>Yes, and we're working very hard to do just that! Our cleansing missions are burning out entire nests of mutated contagion on the approaches to the center of the Zone.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_novice_start_6">
		<text>Thank you.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_petrenko_start_31">
		<text>Hello, brother. What brings you to me?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_veteran_start_2">
		<text>What do you want?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_zastava_11">
		<text>Come in, don't be long. What are you staring at?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_zastava_21">
		<text>Oh, hello, old man! Glad the mutants haven't eaten you yet!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_zastava_about_zastava_0">
		<text>Guarding me?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_zastava_about_zastava_1">
		<text>Yeah, we are. guarding. So any assholes who get past the first barrier at the dump don't go any further. You wanted something?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_zastava_talk_0">
		<text>I wanted to know something.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_zastava_talk_1">
		<text>What's that?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_zastava_talk_2">
		<text>Can you tell me about this place?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_zastava_talk_21">
		<text>Before the accident in 1986, it was a workers' camp from the Rostok plant. Now, as you can see, all that's left are empty houses. Near the store in the basement you'll find a bar, stalkers from all over the Zone gather there, a local merchant works as a Barkeep, maintains the premises, so to speak. Go there if you want to trade, socialize or get an interesting assignment, you'll also get the latest news. On the corner to the north is the base of the Duty faction. If you want to try to join Duty, you can go there, they will tell you who to contact. This whole area is under Duty's protection, so be careful, don't wave your gun around, and if you shoot, our patrol will calm you down in no time.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_zastava_talk_211">
		<text>You said there was a bar. Can you tell me where it is?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_zastava_talk_2111">
		<text>In the basement of a former department store.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_zastava_talk_21111">
		<text>Thanks for the info.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_zastava_talk_212">
		<text>You said there's a Duty group base here. Can you tell me how to get there?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_zastava_talk_2121">
		<text>Go north, you'll see the former store building...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_zastava_talk_21211">
		<text>Thank you for the information.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_zastava_talk_213">
		<text>Our goal, our mission, is to keep them out of here... it's just not natural for the dead to walk among the living... the law of nature... you know? Now, we're gonna collect all this dead scum and take them to the nearest gravity feeder, a good disposal facility.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_zastava_talk_2131">
		<text>Next to the bar, I think. I don't remember exactly, sorry.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_zastava_talk_21311">
		<text>Thanks for the info.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_zastava_talk_214">
		<text>Thanks for the information.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_psih_start_pain_11">
		<text>That's crazy. What is it? in my head. I don't get it at all.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_psih_start_pain_21">
		<text>Yes... and to think, it's, uh.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_psih_start_pain_31">
		<text>The head. it's a load of bullshit. total bullshit!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_psih_start_pain_41">
		<text>No... I don't want this with me. this.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_psih_start_pain_51">
		<text>No, it's not gonna happen to me! It's not gonna happen to me!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_psih_start_pain_61">
		<text>I'm normal! I'm normal. I can take it, I can take it.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_psih_start_pain_71">
		<text>I can do it!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_psih_start_pain_81">
		<text>...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_psih_start_pain_91">
		<text>Good luck to you.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_psih_talk_pain_0">
		<text>Hey!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_psih_talk_pain_1">
		<text>I can do it. I don't want this with me. this.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_psih_talk_pain_11">
		<text>Do you hear me?!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_psih_talk_pain_111">
		<text>No, it's not gonna happen to me! It's not gonna happen to me!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_psih_talk_pain_1111">
		<text>Talk to me!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_psih_talk_pain_11111">
		<text>My head. this is bullshit. it's bullshit!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_psih_talk_pain_111111">
		<text>Shit! This is a waste of time. I need a first aid kit.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_psih_talk_pain_1111111">
		<text>This is bullshit, what's that... in my head. I don't understand it at all!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_psih_talk_pain_11111111">
		<text>Get the first aid kit! This should help a little.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_psih_talk_pain_11111112">
		<text>No first aid kit. I'll have to ask the Barkeep.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_psih_give_medkit_0">
		<text>Get the first aid kit! That should help a little.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="bar_bar_psih_talk_gorbun_0">
		<text>I'm seeing double.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_psih_talk_gorbun_1">
		<text>It must have helped. What do you know about the antenna on Radar? When does the radiation fade?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_psih_talk_gorbun_11">
		<text>The radiation. radiation.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_psih_talk_gorbun_111">
		<text>...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_psih_talk_gorbun_1111">
		<text>Stalker. We went to Radar together, as a group.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_psih_talk_gorbun_11111">
		<text>Well? Speak, don't be silent.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_psih_talk_gorbun_111111">
		<text>We were in a group. He's here in this bar. Talk to him. He's got a silenced rifle.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_psih_talk_gorbun_1111111">
		<text>Here in the bar? I'll be right there,	 wait a little while.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_psih_talk_gorbun_11111111">
		<text>...</text>
	</string>

	<string id="bar_bar_psih_talk_lisiy_0">
		<text>He said you were able to get information about the radiation.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_psih_talk_lisiy_1">
		<text>Yes... I did. It was worth a lot, and it wasn't entirely accurate.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_psih_talk_lisiy_11">
		<text>Tell me everything you know.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_psih_talk_lisiy_111">
		<text>I don't remember much. The radiation seems to weaken at night, sometimes by an hour, sometimes even longer... On Radar, we decided to take a shortcut, we went through an irradiated forest. As it turned out, it's no safer there... There is a hole in the fence, you can bypass some monolith patrols... No. don't-- don't--</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_psih_talk_lisiy_1111">
		<text>What?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_psih_talk_lisiy_11111">
		<text>I don't remember. There's a voice calling me. I have to go.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_psih_talk_lisiy_111111">
		<text>What are you babbling about?!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_psih_talk_lisiy_1111111">
		<text>I was there! I saw it! It got inside my brain and spoke to me. It spoke to me! There was a horrible voice in my head, burning my brain. The horror. The horror. The horror! Don't go in there! It will become you just like it became me. A terrible pain in my head. And a voice Whispering to me.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_psih_talk_lisiy_11111111">
		<text>Calm down, buddy. It's alright, you're safe now!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_psih_talk_lisiy_111111111">
		<text>Whispering. The whispering and creaking of a child's swing. My daughter. I want to see her so badly, but I can't appear in front of her. It's in my head and I'm a monster now. No, you can't. Buddy, give the Barkeep my artifact. It's all I found in there when it got inside my head. The Barkeep will give it to my wife, my daughter. It'll compensate them.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_psih_talk_lisiy_1111111111">
		<text>Compensate for what?</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="bar_svoboda_dialog_0">
		<text>Yeah. What's going on? So you helped him. Well, good for you. I'll tell you something in confidence. We're in business together. We're making orders for the Big Land - jars of jelly. I don't know if you've seen it, but you can create your own anomaly. Talk to him, you can tell him for me.</text>
	</string>

   	 <string id="bar_svoboda_volkodav_start_11">
        	<text>I don't know what its name is, so here you go. Yeah, about the next task. We also need two magnets, but in addition, we need an electric ball. Here's a description of it. I'll give you all the details when you get the samples.</text>
    	</string>

	<string id="ros_bandit_stranger_112">
        	<text>Uh, huh. Yeah. Let's just say there's no reward for you this time, unfortunately, but this experiment was a major step forward for us. Which means that with the next study, you'll have something special waiting for you. Now, come back in 12 hours, we need to do some calculations and analysis of your work.</text>
   	</string>

	<string id="ros_bandit_stranger_1121">
        	<text>To a certain extent. You see, to complete the experiment, we need a strong electromagnetic pulse. Something like a lightning strike. our generator is running out of power. We don't have time to wait for real lightning, so what we need from you is this. You need to find an Elektra-type anomaly and drop this into it. If everything goes right, the artifact will be charged.</text>
    	</string>

</string_table>
