<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1251" ?>
<string_table>
	<string id="Blind">
		<text>Blind dog</text>
	</string>
	<string id="Karlik">
		<text>Dwarf</text>
	</string>
	<string id="Bloodsucker">
		<text>Bloodsucker</text>
	</string>
	<string id="Boar">
		<text>Boar</text>
	</string>
	<string id="Crow">
		<text>Crow</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_mutant_blind_general">
		<text>Several generations of the dog species have lived and died since the catastrophe. Each was more affected by the Zone than the previous one. Rapid mutation lead to a vast improvement in previously peripheral abilities, frequently at the expense of primary ones. The most notable biological change was the loss of sight, paired with an uncanny development of smell. As it turned out, blind cubs survived in the Zone as well as normal ones, if not better. As a result, the common dog quickly became extinct in the Zone, giving way to a new breed - that of blind dogs. The animals instinctively identify and avoid anomalies, radiation, and other invisible dangers that plague the Zone. Like their wild ancestors - the wolves - blind dogs hunt in packs. An encounter with a large group of these animals can be dangerous even to an experiences and well-armed stalker.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_mutant_bloodsucker_general">
		<text>Experienced stalkers describe this semi-legendary beast as a tall, hunched humanoid with a mess of tentacles where its mouth should be. According to those who saw it and lived to tell the tale, the creature uses its tentacles to cling to the victim's throat, paralyze it, and suck it dry of blood. A dry, mummified shell is all that's left of what used to be a living human being. The most astounding feature of the bloodsucker, however, is its ability to become invisible. Countless dead or missing stalkers are said to have perished in the merciless grip of a bloodsucker. The lucky few who have survived an encounter tell spine-chilling tales of marshes and subterranean areas haunted by the Zone's version of Count Dracula.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_mutant_boar_general">
		<text>A massive, mutated animal, reaching 1.5 meters at the shoulder. The Zone boar's aggressiveness and ability to survive surpass by far those of its relatives outside the contaminated area. Radiation and anomalies left their mark on the physical appearance of the animal as well: its fur is entirely gone in some places, and long and bristly in others. The hooves have evolved into sturdy, sharp claws, the pupils became colorless, and the boar's bald head is marred by pigmentation disorders and deep wrinkles. Zone boars are quite resistant to radiation and can stay in heavily contaminated areas for longer periods of time. They usually charge at their victims, trying to knock them over and then rip them to shreds.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_mutant_crow_general">
		<text>The only bird species to have survived in the Zone, enduring increased radiation levels and effectively avoiding anomalies. While the army pilots need to rely on complex detectors to avoid gravitational disturbances, the crow seems to rely on its own senses for that - a mystery that drives ornithologists and biologists mad. Various theories attempting to explain the phenomenon exist, all of them pointing to a highly specialized development of the bird's brain.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_mutant_flesh_general">
		<text>Like most other living creatures in the Zone, the domestic pig also underwent serious biological changes since the day of the catastrophe. It seems the genes responsible for metabolism were especially affected in this case. Mutant pigs, known simply as Flesh among the stalkers, are one of the most vivid examples of the Zone's disastrous perversion of nature. Mutant pigs developed a protective layer of scales and exoskeletal plates. Their regeneration potential increased several times, as did the complexity of their nervous system. Just like a normal pig, a Flesh is an omnivore and may attack a stalker if hungry.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_mutant_poltergeist_general">
		<text>Supernatural in the eyes of some, invisible creatures haunting the deeper reaches of the Zone, usually haunting old, abandoned buildings. Nothing is known about their origin, although rumors in circulation claim they are spirits of stalkers hit by a massive wave of radiation. Their mysterious appearances and disappearances seem to correspond to the poltergeist legend, hence the name. Known encounters with poltergeists are quite diverse in fact: from mischievous laughter and blood-chilling howling, to deadly fireballs appearing out of nowhere. Unfortunately, all information about the poltergeist phenomenon originates from unclear and contradictory stories of questionable validity.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_mutant_pseudodog_general">
		<text>Despite the name, the pseudodogs evolved directly from wolves. The animals inhabiting the forests at the time of the catastrophe gave rise to one of the Zone's most dangerous mutant species. Pseudodogs are about as different from mutant dogs as wild wolves differ from poodles. The creatures mark and guard their territory carefully, attacking anyone stupid enough to venture onto their land on sight. Lightning-fast reflexes, uncanny dexterity and razor-sharp teeth make the pseudodog a formidable enemy for large mutants and well-armed stalkers.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_mutant_pseudogiant_general">
		<text>The pseudogiant resembles a massive, drop-shaped abdomen with a pair of disproportionately large limbs. The limbs are arms and legs at the same time. The creature uses them to move around and grab its victims. An adult pseudogiant can weigh up to two tons and stand 2 meters tall. Their clumsy appearance might be deceiving, since they can move very rapidly if needed. Their muscles are exceptionally powerful and their bones are as hard as steel. The creature's brain is protected by a sturdy (up to 10 centimeters thick) skull, while many complex functions are controlled by the spinal medulla. Another astonishing feature of the beast is its ability to create local shock waves, which damage all living things in the vicinity.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_mutant_snork_general">
		<text>These creatures appear to have once been human, though it is hard to imagine what conditions could drive a human to such a state. Dwarves mostly inhabit underground utilities. They have telekinesis. They may be a subspecies of the Boorers, but without the cloak.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_mutant_tushkano">
		<text>An unknown species of zombie. Appears near Lake Yantar. Apparently, the result of the work of one of the laboratories of the Zone. The distinctive feature is the absence of a head.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_mutant_zombie_general">
		<text>The Brain Scorcher strips its victim of mind and reason, leaving only an empty, mindless shell. The brainless bodies then turn into zombies, following only the most basic instincts, wandering aimlessly around the Zone without weapons or clothing. Zombies are little more than sluggish walking corpses, caring only about food and sleep. They eat and drink just about anything they can get their claws on, hence they are virtually soaked in radiation and toxic waste. Usually they roam the Zone without any apparent purpose or just lie corpse-like in abandoned buildings. However, as soon as they sense the presence of a human being, they attack immediately. Experienced stalkers have learned to avoid them if they can.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="Flesh">
		<text>Flesh</text>
	</string>
	<string id="General">
		<text>General information</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mutant_boar_leg">
		<text>Boar tissue sample</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mutant_boar_leg_description">
		<text>Boar tissue is used by scientists to make a number of drugs, the most common of which is an anti-radiation serum. It can be consumed.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mutant_dog_tail">
		<text>A tissue sample from a dog</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mutant_dog_tail_description">
		<text>The resistance of mutated dog tissues to chemical and electrical effects has long attracted the attention of scientists. It can be consumed.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mutant_flesh_eye">
		<text>A sample of flesh tissue</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mutant_flesh_eye_description">
		<text>After the mutation, the flesh tissue acquired a number of properties, the most useful of which is the ability to regenerate. The details of this mechanism are not exactly known, but this discovery promises to revolutionize medicine. It can be consumed.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mutant_krovosos_jaw">
		<text>A tissue sample from a bloodsucker</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mutant_krovosos_jaw_description">
		<text>Bloodsucker tissue samples contain a special gland: it secretes an enzyme that dissolves the victim's skin while preventing blood from clotting. If scientists are able to determine the structure of the enzyme, it could help bring about a breakthrough in medicine. It can be consumed.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mutant_psevdodog_tail">
		<text>A tissue sample from a pseudo-dog</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mutant_psevdodog_tail_description">
		<text>The resistance of mutated dogs to chemical and electrical exposure has long drawn the attention of scientists. It can be consumed.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mutant_snork_leg">
		<text>Snork foot</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mutant_snork_leg_description">
		<text>The snork's foot, unlike the human foot, contains a greater number of tendons, which have amazing elasticity. This explains the ability of snorks to make incredible jumps.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="Mutants">
		<text>Animals and mutants</text>
	</string>
	<string id="Poltergeist">
		<text>Poltergeist</text>
	</string>
	<string id="Pseudodog">
		<text>Pseudodog</text>
	</string>
	<string id="Pseudogiant">
		<text>Pseudogiant</text>
	</string>
	<string id="Snork">
		<text>Naked dwarf</text>
	</string>
	<string id="Tushkano">
		<text>Corpus</text>
	</string>
	<string id="Zombie">
		<text>Zombie</text>
	</string>
	<string id="Controller">
		<text>Controller</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_mutant_controller_general">
		<text>A rare mutant found near the center of the Zone. It looks like a humanoid with a disproportionately enlarged head. Possesses advanced perception as well as the ability to control the behavior of less evolved living beings. Mature individuals are capable of taking control of even humans. This is a dangerous enemy, meeting with which even the most experienced stalkers are afraid.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mutant_zombie_hand">
		<text>Zombie meat</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mutant_zombie_hand_description">
		<text>Scientists are trying to figure out how such a rotten body was able to retain the muscles that allow Zombie to strike so hard. It can be consumed.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mutant_burer_hand">
		<text>Burer's meat</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mutant_burer_hand_description">
		<text>Burer meat is of great interest to scientists. The burer can deal both physical and telepathic damage with his hand. It can be consumed.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="Burer">
		<text>Burer</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_mutant_burer_general">
		<text>A very rare mutant. There is an opinion that it is a result of genetic experiments conducted by special services over criminals on the program of development of telekinetic abilities in a person. A fat man with hypertrophied facial features, in the remnants of his clothes. In a worn out form. Lives mostly in gloomy, dark catacombs. It's hostile to humans. B?hrer attacks with powerful limbs, delivering an invisible telekinetic strike. Can create a gravity field that protects him from bullets and explosions. The harsh light blinds the burer for a while.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="Chimera">
		<text>Chimera</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_mutant_chimera_general">
		<text>A very rare mutant. Rumor has it that it is the result of genetic experimentation for the "universal guardian animal" program. A very smart, strong and fast creature. He's hiding, coming around the back. A duplicated internal organ system and an extra brain makes the process of killing her highly problematic. Strong strikes with clawed paws. In motion, it resembles a panther.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="Rat">
		<text>Rat</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_mutant_rat_general">
		<text>Rats aren't from underground lab complexes, they're the true masters of the zone. It's hard to imagine a more adaptable organism. The known resistance of rats to radiation is explained by the efficiency of their DNA repair systems. Rapid reproduction rates and large numbers of offspring allow them to quickly adapt to new environmental conditions.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="Fracture">
		<text>Fracture</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_mutant_fracture_general">
		<text>A little-studied mutant. Either the result of experiments, or the result of the Zone's effect on the remaining humans. There are hypertrophied limbs. The face is close to human. Slouching. From afar, it looks like a hunchbacked hobo. Attacking people. Eating corpses. A strong punch with a hypertrophied arm.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_mutant_karlik_general">
		<text>Artificially grown stunted creatures of the humanoid type. As well as B?hrers - dwellers of catacombs, but unlike them perceive bright light is not so painful. Possessing intelligence, communicating with each other. Telekinetic and telepathic abilities have not yet been established. They collect various mechanisms out of garbage and set traps.</text>
	</string>
</string_table>
